<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">ca01013</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Undergraduate Life records <num>CA.MS.01013</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-18 15:18:47 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Undergraduate Life records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="lcsh">Smith College -- Students</corpname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>CA.MS.01013</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">44 boxes plus oversized material</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1892/1892"
                   type="inclusive">approximately 1892-present</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_3c8681b51054a4d679c1f7a63dc25747">Undergraduate Life records contains papers related to student clothes and fashions, Distinct Groups (informational files on foreign students, minorities, Ada Comstock Scholars), Student Government (includes Council and House minutes, course critiques, SGA records), and Student Publications.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_70b45e853bafb63fceab3b9e7d50c816">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.  Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.  In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_779f2e51639e2e3ff009f2d283819c7f">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_0d9e216b795fb5fcf5e910fb6c727ca9">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Many parts of the collection have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_fe8f2abcf72a3adae944da304340978e">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Undergraduate Life records, College Archives, CA-MS-01013, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2dd3e01fb8d39eaa86b797d48b48d4ca">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Undergraduate Life records contains papers related to student clothes and fashions (news clippings, photographs); Distinct Groups (informational files on foreign students, minorities, Ada Comstock Scholars, including pamphlets, correspondence, photographs, newsletters, organization); Student Government (includes Council and House minutes, course critiques, SGA records); and Student Publications (complete runs of student newspapers, literary magazines, etc.).</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d8103aead8144db9d0afdf530bfe08be">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
