<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">ca01004</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Office of the President Ruth J. Simmons papers <num>CA.MS.01004</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-16 14:06:12 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Office of the President Ruth J. Simmons papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_3874" source="local_inmagic-people">Simmons, Ruth</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.01004</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 boxes and oversize materials</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1995/2001"
                   type="inclusive">1995-2001</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_f5d975e288915896c836dd5cf0eeead3">The collection contains records from the presidency of Ruth J. Simmons, including news clippings, inauguration records, and biographical information.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_85b68c0e78c03cfbe3ef5969b13775e5">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.  Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently.  In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d247c5a18391ddca2ee0d93ac59365e7">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Unknown source</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_f242516ddf3f40733dc3755d12ef58fd">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>
Ruth J. Simmons graduated from Dillard University, a private, liberal-arts black college in New Orleans, in 1967, before earning a doctorate at Harvard University in 1970.  She made stops at the University of Southern California and at Princeton University, where she is largely credited with raising the profile of the black-studies program. She then served as an administrator at Spelman College.  She was appointed president of Smith in 1995, the first black president of Smith College. In 2000, Brown University selected her as its 18th president, making her the first black president of an ivy league college.  She retired in 2012, but in 2017 the Texas A&amp;M System announced that Simmons would serve as interim president of Prairie View A&amp;M.   </p>
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_719a6d97400eb64d9069cb29ee04456b">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The collection has container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_1e4b2e3bb283b3b732480c986ad16eff">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Office of the President Ruth J. Simmons papers, College Archives, CA-MS-01004, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_3f01bc084206bf029cc8f730bc310888">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection contains records from the presidency of Ruth J. Simmons, including news clippings, inauguration records, and biographical information.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_90c4b23b89d86175d40c3f59bd0ebcfc">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_3874"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Simmons, Ruth</persname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
