<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">manosca81</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests Records <num>CA.MS.00081</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Eleanor M Lewis, Ellice Amanna</author>
            <sponsor>Encoding funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-20 11:48:09 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2005-09-23</date>
            <item>manosca81 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02-5c.xsl (sy2003-10-15).</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-11-20</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated with new box numbers, barcodes, locations</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="naf">Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests.</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.00081</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.625 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(2 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1922/1983"
                   type="inclusive">1922-1983</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_11c088ea10a064a916a557aaa64a6dd2">These records document a research institute to develop methods of combining efficient home management with serious intellectual endeavors. The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, proposals, and programs.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests was established at Smith College in 1925 with Ethel Puffer Howes as director. Mrs. Howes, an advocate of domestic reform, formulated a plan for a research institute to develop methods of combining efficient home management with serious intellectual endeavors. Mrs. Howes submitted her proposal to the president of Smith College, where she had studied and taught. The proposed institute received a three-year grant from the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Foundation and the approval of the Smith College Board of Trustees.</p>
         <p>  The Institute had two major goals: to find practical ways to make household chores easier for women and to educate women to pursue interests which could be integrated with the duties of marriage. In an effort to achieve the first objective, the Institute experimented with ways to help married women lighten their daily routines. Between 1926 and 1929, the Institute conducted research and practical demonstrations to provide home assistance through cooperative nursery schools, dinner kitchens, and cooked food delivery services. To attain the second objective, Mrs. Howes sought to guide women into professions and activities which could be combined with marriage. Toward this end, the Institute studied domestic and landscape architecture and free-lance writing to determine their possibilities for coordination with family life.</p>
         <p>  Associated by the faculty with vocational training and home economics, the Institute functioned as an isolated entity. In two recent papers about the Institute, the authors concluded that neither the goals of the Institute's programs nor its theoretical bases were clearly defined. In 1929 Mrs. Howes asked the Trustees for a two year extension for the Institute. She also proposed that the Institute be incorporated into the college curriculum, a plan which the faculty did not endorse. After the Rockefeller Foundation denied a request for continued support, the Trustees appropriated funding for Howes to conclude her work. Howes did not complete her research and by 1931 the Institute was at an end.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The records consist of .625 linear feet of correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, proposals, and programs. In addition, the Institute published a series of nine studies which present its various projects in greater detail.</p>
         <p>  Although numbering fewer than 150 pages, the correspondence and memoranda follow the affairs of the Institute from its conception in 1922, through its development, 1925 to 1928, to signs of its decline in 1929. The minutes of both the Smith College Board of Trustees and Trustees' Committee on the Institute reveal the attitudes and intentions of their members regarding support for the Institute. The material includes reports which outline the activities of the Institute and a 1926 questionnaire sent to 500 Smith alumnae in an effort to learn whether college graduates had integrated the interests of marriage and work.
Two student projects contribute to our understanding of the Institute. An important source is an honors thesis for a B.A. in American Studies, "In Search of the 'Good Life': Ethel Puffer Howes and the Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests," by Elizabeth A. Harwick. This paper traces the rise and fall of the Institute concentrating on its conceptualization and formation. A research paper, "A Matter of Compromise: The Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests at Smith College, 1925-31," by Amelie Russell, also examines the Institute's history.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests records, College Archives, CA-MS-00081, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_add-related">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Material relating to the Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests can be found in the records of the Laura Spellman Rockefeller Memorial and the Laura Spellman Rockefeller Papers (1918-49), both located at the Rockefeller Archive Center, Pocantico Hills, North Tarrytown, New York.</p>
         <p>Partial results of an unpublished 1926 Institute survey are located in the files of Eleanor L. Lord in the College Archives. Between 1922 and 1927, Ms. Lord was educational consultant and research associate for the Institute.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation.
Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.
In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
References</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>A few items in these records were donated by Benjamin T. Howes, son of Ethel Puffer Howes. The source is unknown for the remainder of the materials.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Eleanor M. Lewis.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Family life education--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Family life education--United States.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Home economics--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Home economics--United States.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Education--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Education--United States.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Employment--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Employment--United States.</subject>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="faculty-mem_133"
                   source="local_inmagic-faculty-mem">Howes, Ethel Puffer, Class of 1891</persname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests.</corpname>
    
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_9f8b9bf48cb5ecb0b259e0387dd75ecb" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Organization</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_d84a2767f2dde0c17bf19b97bd443917" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1925/1929"
                            type="inclusive">1925-29</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_181a40a3be674fc6624afe41c28d84ec"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ee0f362b9c7c691d77e581bb6418ab9e"
                             parent="aspace_181a40a3be674fc6624afe41c28d84ec"
                             type="folder">1-5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_856e9d5868cbf6344f902eb6c3ba9fd5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Memoranda and miscellaneous items</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1922/1928"
                            type="inclusive">1922-28</unitdate>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_b0b89fd37654570ba2ce30914d6b0fde"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_516e8db2c6ecb2db84496d4741f50d0f"
                             parent="aspace_b0b89fd37654570ba2ce30914d6b0fde"
                             type="folder">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ea4c90289448326ffe3cc8313e85367e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Board of Trustees of Smith College</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1925/1931"
                            type="inclusive">1925-31</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_f2dcb70a57c047e894884d35fe055a86"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fe335f4a1518fd3176d3abb1fbda8a39"
                             parent="aspace_f2dcb70a57c047e894884d35fe055a86"
                             type="folder">7</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_f31bf71affe49a7a58a56adffc75ce66" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Questionnaire to alumnae for program development</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_6261e7a790cb55cb5038aec8dbb4bafd"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_29fb0d9e6dec784f3cdff901fd7dedec"
                             parent="aspace_6261e7a790cb55cb5038aec8dbb4bafd"
                             type="folder">8</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7409cefe3253e9ef6c09feb1d1938c64" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reports to the Board of Trustees of Smith College (5)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1926/1927"
                            type="inclusive">1926-27</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_dd95fd0f775a58fbf7813330b20a8e1d"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_66c43a1deb712979b453409067afae2a"
                             parent="aspace_dd95fd0f775a58fbf7813330b20a8e1d"
                             type="folder">9</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ab4091bef810f62cc94b3d452e564e44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minutes of the Trustees' Committee on the Institute</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1926/1927"
                            type="inclusive">1926-27</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_21ad989ac4b9fa7dd5396f9c8880b67f"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ef0929b239cb6a7fa282cb030e2b8ce4"
                             parent="aspace_21ad989ac4b9fa7dd5396f9c8880b67f"
                             type="folder">10</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ba434da0f1bc390afb30b2f810cdb0ad" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Proposals for extension of the Institute</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1928/1930"
                            type="inclusive">1928-30</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_66bf9fce60b94958182b2fad54441b77"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fd208df6337720c01701cda99925dcf1"
                             parent="aspace_66bf9fce60b94958182b2fad54441b77"
                             type="folder">11</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_627ed7872789487ca2a9e0e5b94ed8b7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Articles and clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1926/1928"
                            type="inclusive">1926-28</unitdate>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_4a508671259e1c9e36b694fe16e4cbb6"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fbee9332836fd02f309231c8e3843015"
                             parent="aspace_4a508671259e1c9e36b694fe16e4cbb6"
                             type="folder">12</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_d8dcfae832d596bc8752e9d4c2a243f9" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Programs</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_00161eb7d691723cfe1992b3e9be4a77" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Conferences: press releases, programs, clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1926/1927"
                            type="inclusive">1926-27</unitdate>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_17a4cd6a82b16f59d86539c8f938e443"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cb3d9f470d6d37d36d8f8700e1290507"
                             parent="aspace_17a4cd6a82b16f59d86539c8f938e443"
                             type="folder">13</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6e2582db532276c793347a62287bb2d5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dinner Kitchen: Press releases, notices, menus, price lists</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1927/1929"
                            type="inclusive">1927-29</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_4205883eee9691956012484d3afa2437"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_779746f6fabc78d651e528610bf9b85c"
                             parent="aspace_4205883eee9691956012484d3afa2437"
                             type="folder">14</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c21bfe1abcda5ab2ccac2b237b22e3a5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Free Lance Writing: publicity statement, announcements</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927-10/1927-10">Oct. 1927</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_84190f9f051aa339f6ff6be39f344c46"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bfbab6078eef2be54766b5f1d85ecf51"
                             parent="aspace_84190f9f051aa339f6ff6be39f344c46"
                             type="folder">15</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ae89c6b4bd4eca8a5dd93f558fca9024" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Home Assistance Club: publicity statement, announcements</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_16966f091ffc1f24405e9cc29a7f8a64"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f7c8e71aa3e426cbc70dae38b13fae3c"
                             parent="aspace_16966f091ffc1f24405e9cc29a7f8a64"
                             type="folder">16</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_4cffdf5355eb69e1e9bb55ce5a1900cb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nursery School: articles, correspondence, notes, memos, reports, photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1927/1928"
                            type="inclusive">1927-28</unitdate>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_ac92cbc63c8a08ebb35b6b607560386f"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9ecb88a0b9ebc22f198b605350ee7ee8"
                             parent="aspace_ac92cbc63c8a08ebb35b6b607560386f"
                             type="folder">17</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_08417ad8b9e37469cec9c7125bfceb08" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Summer Institute: brochure, miscellaneous notes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_c7680aa9ad59213c597f39a6c0ef1453"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ad58ceabff715d635a58f7c2c5a23bab"
                             parent="aspace_c7680aa9ad59213c597f39a6c0ef1453"
                             type="folder">18</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_89217061034ceef4567bb07e12091448" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_72c59393d2a8fdf82c28a1db825f38f1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alma Louise Olsen, "Free Lance Writing as an Occupation for Women," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 1</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_691e4cd2a8ff7501050f8b90a1da6b51"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e4d21341f1a9cdd2b593c2933884a573"
                             parent="aspace_691e4cd2a8ff7501050f8b90a1da6b51"
                             type="folder">19</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_d5cf60fd21cafa59b269b954ae24f7e4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Alice Peloubet Norton, "Cooked Food Supply Experiments in America," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 2</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_eedd1d9757eb496dc5fca58c3b38a0b4"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4dab6947f3bc9204d95311209cb1f4cc"
                             parent="aspace_eedd1d9757eb496dc5fca58c3b38a0b4"
                             type="folder">20</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7b2458103596e42e67aee9c9f5a565fd" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ethel P. Howes and Dorothea Beach, "The Cooperative Nursury School: What it Can Do For the Parents," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 3</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_6f6b121343c537c1015f4af8d2eb7a2b"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_af8fb9459e29145b9cab364a11534552"
                             parent="aspace_6f6b121343c537c1015f4af8d2eb7a2b"
                             type="folder">21</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_42e9ff4c61f72b943c8612d0d3ab42b2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"The Nursery School as a Social Experiment," Conference, <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 4</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_728c78fb431d1447ce32efc01a00a440"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0aad3d6702d81266c04131412c687092"
                             parent="aspace_728c78fb431d1447ce32efc01a00a440"
                             type="folder">22</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_5391c002a8a22c253cca2a91d23073eb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Esther H. Stocks, "A Community Home Assistants Experiment," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 5</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_dcd91a9b4b978f0f567507febafee4c2"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b0c83794e3a61ad177a0b1052cea6d12"
                             parent="aspace_dcd91a9b4b978f0f567507febafee4c2"
                             type="folder">23</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_273df7ada5f9c76e346f437dc3d28f83" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ethel Puffer Howes and Dorothea Beach, "Cooked Food Supply Experiments in an Eastern College Community," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 6</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_9712331759eab2bf19b08552ec293317"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0edae25aaf65de27f2b0c583f4b35324"
                             parent="aspace_9712331759eab2bf19b08552ec293317"
                             type="folder">24</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_d4e5175523d9cde24b65efb1a4bfbcb5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry A. Frost and William R. Sears, "Women in Architecture and Landscape Architecture," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 7</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_c2dcf392bb11cd6de6b950f8742cc558"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9e592a945984f290e7e6c422f1ea8946"
                             parent="aspace_c2dcf392bb11cd6de6b950f8742cc558"
                             type="folder">25</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_bf84c3f59cef5e0401fc27b6fb514af5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ethel Puffer Howes, "The Progress of the Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 8</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_07210b059e1a4b53e6dc2277c625cf54"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247269]"
                             type="box">1303</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d6133be3199882e0e700b662b89fcc6f"
                             parent="aspace_07210b059e1a4b53e6dc2277c625cf54"
                             type="folder">26</container>
               </did>
               <odd id="aspace_2d4230bc8ce80eda786ebe46fd6be1e4">
                  <head>General</head>
                  <p>[See also Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests, Publications 1-9, 1927-30 (One Volume, Box 2)]</p>
               </odd>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_cf8e33e23b8f25be468ab91d9f2073cf" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ethel P. Howes and Doris M. Sanbourn, "The Dinner Kitchen Cookbook, including Report for 1928-29 Smith College Community Kitchen," <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, no. 9</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                             id="aspace_fca518db31ba799f852cf87f68a94f1f"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247327]"
                             type="box">1304</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6f9779a71ff5c1478123e34c8df661fb"
                             parent="aspace_fca518db31ba799f852cf87f68a94f1f"
                             type="folder">27</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_97fe2f8ec167a9f6c0e57663516c46c4" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Student Theses</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_c75b93cbf2961d6869b6cd01ad717e10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Amelie Russell, "A Matter of Compromise: Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests at Smith College, 1925-31," 39 pp.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                             id="aspace_82d82c49a933e824d2a61121476f2e7b"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247327]"
                             type="box">1304</container>
                  <container id="aspace_dca2a0e68a512c2a2ee2db64ddb6d24a"
                             parent="aspace_82d82c49a933e824d2a61121476f2e7b"
                             type="folder">28</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_e6926df8c26b9dd3973c191d0852dcd2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Elizabeth A. Harwick, "In Search of the 'Good Life': Ethel Puffer Howes and Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests," 88 pp.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                             id="aspace_ce1304b82c66905b11b14031854616b2"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630247327]"
                             type="box">1304</container>
                  <container id="aspace_84898ea23e95e8aa8ea6136e88c3d483"
                             parent="aspace_ce1304b82c66905b11b14031854616b2"
                             type="folder">28</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-1-9" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>
                  <title>Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests</title>, Publications 1-9 in one volume</unittitle>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="1927/1930"
                         type="inclusive">1927-30</unitdate>
               <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                          id="aspace_cf98b6f8f966172e63f57441ab0fd391"
                          label="Mixed Materials [310183630247327]"
                          type="box">1304</container>
            </did>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
