<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">manosca117</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Women's Studies Task Force records <num>CA.MS.00117</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Laurie Winslow</author>
            <sponsor>Encoding funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>© 2003</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-14 11:03:57 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2005-09-23</date>
            <item>manosca117 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02-5c.xsl (sy2003-10-15).</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-11-11</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS and added boxes</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Women's Studies Task Force records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="naf">Women's Studies Task Force</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.00117</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.833 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(2 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1972/1981"
                   type="inclusive">1972-1981</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_792028cbc573429f4a7fa9ef4edcfde7">Student Group. The Women's Studies Task Force was formed at a crucial time in the history of the development of women's studies at Smith College. The Task Force, like its parent organization, the Women's Resource Center, played an instrumental, if little recognized role in providing impetus towards a formal women's studies program at the College. The records include administrative records and research materials. The bulk of the collection is research material from the Interterm Project of the Women's Studies Task Force.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Women's Studies Task Force Collection is composed in part from records transferred from the Sophia Smith Collection in the spring of 2003 and in part from donations to the College Archives by alumnae Deborah Levison, Class of 1982.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_scope-org">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>This collection is organized into two series:</p>    
         <list type="ordered">
            <item>I. Administration</item>
            <item>II. Interterm Project</item>
         </list>
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Women's Studies Task Force, a student group, was formed as an operational group of the <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/smitharchives/manosca108_main.html">Women's Resource Center</extref> (WRC) in February, 1979. Faith Reidenbach, a member of the Center, served as the group's first chair, and other WRC members formed the bulk of the initial membership of the Task Force. In 1979, the <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/smitharchives/manosca108_main.html">Women's Resource Center</extref> (chartered by the College in 1973) supported three task forces, the other two being the ERA Task Force and the Health Task Force.</p>
         <p>  The Women's Studies Task Force was formed at a crucial time in the history of the development of women's studies at Smith College. The Task Force, like its parent organization, the WRC, played a vitally instrumental, if little recognized role in providing impetus towards a formal women's studies program at the College. The Task Force was formed under the 'pledge' of the WRC to "work with the CEP [Committee on Educational Policy] for as many years as it takes to persuade the administration to recognize a formal women's studies program" (WRC Newsletter, Feb. 16, 1979).</p>
         <p>  Prior to 1979, women's studies courses at Smith College, instituted formally by a CEP mandate in 1974, were integrated into the various traditional academic departments, for reasons both practical and philosophical (with the latter, much discussion in academia at the time centered around concerns that formal women's studies programs would 'ghetto-ize' women in the curriculum). With the arrival of Jill Ker Conway in 1975 as president, a focus on women's issues and needs in general, as well as within the College curriculum, gained attention and funding. In 1978, President Conway obtained the first of a series of significant grants from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation to form the Project on Women and Social Change, a multi-year research program. This project was funded in answer to a proposal for the creation of a women's studies research center as a part of the College, an idea that was resisted by the majority of the faculty and rejected by the faculty Committee on Research on the Study of Women.</p>
         <p>  Involved in this committee and in the Women and Social Change Project was Professor Marilyn Schuster of the French Department, also a member of the Committee to Review the Curriculum for the CEP. Professor Schuster was also a part of the initial meeting of the Women's Studies Task Force, as was Professor Susan Van Dyne of the English Department. Both professors acted as mentors to the group. In the spring of 1980, Professors Schuster and Van Dyne recommended, without success, the formation of an ad hoc or advisory committee on Women's Studies to the CEP and the Committee on Committees, with the support of the Women's Studies Task Force. No further records of Task Force activity beyond this time are apparent. </p>
         <p>  The matter of women's studies was taken up the next academic year by the Project on Women and Social Change Curriculum Group, for which Professor Schuster wrote proposals to coordinate the current women's courses through additional text in the handbook and in student advising. The Committee on Women's Studies was formed in 1982 following a renewed proposal by Professor Schuster and further action in November, 1982, by the WRC in the form of an 'open discussion' on options for women's studies in which both President Conway and Professor Schuster spoke, as well as other key faculty members. A minor in Women's Studies was instituted in 1984 and a major in 1987.</p>
         <p>  The Women's Studies Task Force's main accomplishment and contribution to the process of formalizing women's studies at Smith College was its research work, primarily accomplished during the Interterm Project it was awarded by the Student Government Association in January, 1980.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Women's Studies Task Force Collection, Box #, Smith College Archives, CA-MS-00117, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachussets.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Laurie Winslow.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_add-related">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Further information on the Women's Studies Task Force may be found in the records of the <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/smitharchives/manosca108_main.html">Women's Resource Center</extref> and in an article entitled, "Women's Resource Center seeks to aid all women," in the April 16, 1979 edition of the Sophian. Related information pertaining to the Committee on the Study of Women can be found in the Dean of Faculty Office records and information on both the Women's Studies Committee and Women's Studies Program can be found in the Departmental records of the College Archives under the Women's Studies Program.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Women's Studies Task Force records consist of 1 linear foot (2 boxes) and are the administrative records from 1979-80 and the records and research materials related to the Interterm Project of the Women's Studies Task Force conducted in January 1980. The bulk of the collection is research material from the Interterm Project. The research materials are divided into two sections (Smith College and Other) and date back to the early 1970's. There is no record of the disbandment of the group.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women's studies--Massachusetts--Northampton.</subject>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College--Students.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Women's Studies Task Force (Smith College)</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="naf">Women's Resource Center (Smith College)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-ser1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series I. Administration</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_201fb2e7d415a97995b48b9c14eee072" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Meeting minutes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_80b9bc2c67e9e3c63abcdc39e08521d1"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_da81412d74c88b9c4b3bf67909d5541d"
                             parent="aspace_80b9bc2c67e9e3c63abcdc39e08521d1"
                             type="folder">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_41191d874cd2c8a00cde8ca665a66540" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1979/1980"
                            type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_3757f75d5d8351c3b1ce982230967951"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d3d140ccad166330453e9dc69180d0ba"
                             parent="aspace_3757f75d5d8351c3b1ce982230967951"
                             type="folder">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c50a722ea7b9e42b52b8ccd5d87c845a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Women's Studies Questionnaire</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_0f8dee2b7d47c0bab908a1616423ef3a"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_baa8e0aa85ce04cae2d856f8a22e8a43"
                             parent="aspace_0f8dee2b7d47c0bab908a1616423ef3a"
                             type="folder">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_695e868088a2a18427473c49ee78653c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Meeting announcements ( <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/smitharchives/manosca108_main.html">Women's Resource Center</extref> newsletters)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">undated</unitdate>
                  <unitdate normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_a4dc50927189096c1d6a0bbc55b2b2cf"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f4b41432ac84ce79f738aa9b39027fd6"
                             parent="aspace_a4dc50927189096c1d6a0bbc55b2b2cf"
                             type="folder">4</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_64399358ab4893eafd13d7c06f620b2a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Flyer for Works in Progress program</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_8ba21bac88d2871e74ef6c6eca46a04c"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f238a9bf720f4f11a14b1750219209dc"
                             parent="aspace_8ba21bac88d2871e74ef6c6eca46a04c"
                             type="folder">5</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-ser2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series II. Interterm Project</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_46ded0776e08464b14fb11df76481421" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Description and readings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980-01/1980-01">Jan. 1980</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_966cf01e4fdeeb15b1db1cf06942f3de"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                             type="box">3021.1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9e4627c2b82f347bb09be4e9f56a5fd4"
                             parent="aspace_966cf01e4fdeeb15b1db1cf06942f3de"
                             type="folder">6</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_f6d9afb72e601a952e5bac7f97c18c75" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Research, Smith College</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_9164544e1984f36112976e59f1aa376b" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's courses syllabi</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1972/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1972-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_4d5d8fce607d325e1349db4d0f51bd9f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6662f1fe0872a9d3064343bb5d23ac95"
                                parent="aspace_4d5d8fce607d325e1349db4d0f51bd9f"
                                type="folder">7</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_263475dd0e6e80b7ecddbab757fd9230" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's courses evaluations</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_35306de49157017e4faa391fcadc1e1b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_cc0d37c99be4acc0195cb7e8cf8e8ab6"
                                parent="aspace_35306de49157017e4faa391fcadc1e1b"
                                type="folder">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b501570a7231325e9e6d0d5fa39ad50c" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's courses statistics</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1972/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1972-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_545d24c1ed0998496562065e96745d5f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_97e73ac745652b3fe4a7dd99f8679ce0"
                                parent="aspace_545d24c1ed0998496562065e96745d5f"
                                type="folder">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_191623f0426f1692f8ba01d9801703d0" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Faculty and student research papers</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1976/1979"
                               type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_e6b36a516379d9db8e70f60f380d13a5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_de868bdb230444dc8f2da626ca9dd71c"
                                parent="aspace_e6b36a516379d9db8e70f60f380d13a5"
                                type="folder">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c468bae03bbe11a4cb1d3565e92f0ee6" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Self-designed, interdisciplinary major by Jennifer Jackman, '82</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_3dc3c0868f3d66d6299bf7f6a31d6141"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3c06ee9a12a7b59282b98b0a6145a914"
                                parent="aspace_3dc3c0868f3d66d6299bf7f6a31d6141"
                                type="folder">11</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ee2546c420cbef67518cc54d1ed92ebc" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Jill Ker Conway articles</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1974/1979"
                               type="inclusive">1974-1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_122d468af0580c8472bb31c7b354e5c3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0761c904b9fc4dbc3f528ef7af9c39d5"
                                parent="aspace_122d468af0580c8472bb31c7b354e5c3"
                                type="folder">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d3b4f8811b21c176cbb31a796991f969" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/smitharchives/manosca108_main.html">Women's Resource Center</extref>: publications</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_08a3e22d5547aead6d8218f659bd36f1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_38aa22d408d08b51808cb0dfa36d813a"
                                parent="aspace_08a3e22d5547aead6d8218f659bd36f1"
                                type="folder">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_742f2ab822e09a595dc89ab4c3fe47ae" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Project on Women and Social Change</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_c7169571231cdc2d260a499b305a2634"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_635f52b50fcf89a1b0bdd45f8d750224"
                                parent="aspace_c7169571231cdc2d260a499b305a2634"
                                type="folder">14</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_9b249c0f8f90c7d975814039ea98552c" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Praxis (feminist publication)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_9f8038d065d78daf5d8adb7536c9695e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_5ca58f3d6926981b6b10154ad711eef7"
                                parent="aspace_9f8038d065d78daf5d8adb7536c9695e"
                                type="folder">15</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_07015ab98456a09bbe36b52c6425b20d" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Freshman Colloquia</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_77317569a958ae26865d21cf33868216"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_48926364b883ac232e405af341bb0d87"
                                parent="aspace_77317569a958ae26865d21cf33868216"
                                type="folder">16</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_2d247c3b0f60ad2c0f8eb1c22907f467" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>
                        <title>Alumnae Quarterly</title> (Kenneth McCartney article)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980-02/1980-02">Feb. 1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_9284e80b79fa5ba44eab0d4c06732f77"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238946]"
                                type="box">3021.1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_33bb04aa22f1d4f820f64aa43ffece47"
                                parent="aspace_9284e80b79fa5ba44eab0d4c06732f77"
                                type="folder">17</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_95ed73205c65a43d3611c1d2cfbf7dea" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Research, Other</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c03 id="aspace_28d663efccbf9c39419e7d57f72f317e" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>UMass Women's Studies program</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1977/1981"
                               type="inclusive">1977-1981</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_276f6257d5da5cb7e208591a63b154f3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_75c57c79acd2ebb76c65a9d118ad4637"
                                parent="aspace_276f6257d5da5cb7e208591a63b154f3"
                                type="folder">18</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_7e71a394ae9cb847ead9157d0b4e6eb1" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>National Women's Studies Association</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1979/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_4f4176ecf650960a937b435a19249de1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f863499056573a1adeefa78e7ed97dc8"
                                parent="aspace_4f4176ecf650960a937b435a19249de1"
                                type="folder">19</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8d023785074ef98aa494558a002389c4" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's Studies journals</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1973/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1973-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_8680191009dbeb895f046cb642373938"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1c66eb250b2d8da8595a37d50163dca4"
                                parent="aspace_8680191009dbeb895f046cb642373938"
                                type="folder">20</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b7063dba117e1a5104b22eab532ac7ff" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Five College Women's Studies program</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1976/1981"
                               type="inclusive">1976-1981</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_1564e1dd6417a31bb9dbfeb1e196508b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_555eacd74f49744c070fbb28181151cd"
                                parent="aspace_1564e1dd6417a31bb9dbfeb1e196508b"
                                type="folder">21</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_278d4af17787223e2366be83887327fd" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Bibliographies</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_4e794bc47c26fe6a4daf3098361dd279"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0cba492cd3b970198bbf7938ff88485b"
                                parent="aspace_4e794bc47c26fe6a4daf3098361dd279"
                                type="folder">22</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_e980a1f2aee4ece3fdcff0d6c376ea7b" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Research on women's studies and gender in the curriculum</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1979/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_7a01cf2d816f51bcdb8b1282475179b2"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_27b85e2e2ef242cff2d51f557747caeb"
                                parent="aspace_7a01cf2d816f51bcdb8b1282475179b2"
                                type="folder">23</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_49878ff392264ce59ea4a280c827dcf5" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Project on the Status and Education of Women internship</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980/1980">1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_9346314c4c0bba99d5a6f58e62bfeda5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d01b428ba5cdc140c019cd6c3c3a0ba3"
                                parent="aspace_9346314c4c0bba99d5a6f58e62bfeda5"
                                type="folder">24</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_198a6b0b552d9808b1a5711f7413c421" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>General articles and publications on women</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_45b0676cec27badee955a90a83a08100"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_35554e09e8fe3008d82b945a3ce7f71c"
                                parent="aspace_45b0676cec27badee955a90a83a08100"
                                type="folder">25</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_aee2f0c7ee69d642cb75b290e7f97745" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Other women's studies programs descriptions and syllabi</unittitle>
                     <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                               era="ce"
                               normal="1972/1980"
                               type="inclusive">1972-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Letter document box"
                                id="aspace_76b5903b512b7b9fb97ee78dc1fb0297"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630238953]"
                                type="box">3021.2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_564fc05df5015d17101360f66995d2c1"
                                parent="aspace_76b5903b512b7b9fb97ee78dc1fb0297"
                                type="folder">26</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
