<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">manosca63</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the William A. Orton Papers <num>CA.MS.00063</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Katrina Cokeng</author>
            <sponsor>Encoding funded by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</sponsor>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>© 2003</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-12 11:01:13 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2005-09-23</date>
            <item>manosca63 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02-5c.xsl (sy2003-10-15).</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-11-12</date>
            <item>Containers added and finding aid updated as part of the College Archives Survey</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>William A. Orton Papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="naf">Orton, William Aylott, 1889-1952.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.00063</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.208 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(1 container)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1922/1952"
                   type="inclusive">1922-1952</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_9f3415c9b3af72ef6f18ce52d0c7eb59">Professor, economics, writer. Contains articles, speeches, publications, correspondence and photographs.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>William Aylott Orton was born on February 9, 1889 in Bromley, Kent, England. He graduated with honors from Christ's College, Cambridge University in 1919 and received his M.Sc. degree in Economics from the University of London for a thesis entitled "British Industrial History Since 1914," a work which was published that same year in London under the title of "Labour in Transition." He received his M.A. from Cambridge in 1922, the degree of Doctor of Science from the University of London in 1946, the honorary degree of Doctor of Laws from Boston University in 1947, and the degree of Doctor of Letters from Georgetown University in 1951. </p>
         <p> Orton also served as a lieutenant in the British army in Gallipoli, Egypt and France from 1914 to 1917, and was then connected with the intelligence staff of the War Office in London until 1919. A staff officer in the industrial relations department of the Ministry of Labor from 1919 to 1922, Orton also lectured to the London County Council and the University of London during these years. </p>
         <p> Orton joined the Smith College faculty in 1922, and during this time he also taught summer sessions at Bryn Mawr College and at the University of California, and served as a visiting professor at Amherst and Williams Colleges.
 
 Orton wrote on numerous topics, and was actively interested in moving pictures as a form of art. He is well-known for his books, Prelude to Economics (1932), America in Search of Culture (1933), The Last Romantic (1937), Twenty Years' Armistice (1938), and The Liberal Tradition (1945). A frequent contributor to the Atlantic Monthly, the American Mercury, the American Economic Review, Harper's, and the New Republic, Orton also wrote the entry on "Liberalism" for the Encyclopedia Britannica. He was well known as a speaker throughout the East. In 1948, Orton gave the Walgreen Foundation lecture at the University of Chicago, and in 1949, he was appointed a trustee of the University of Massachusetts. He was also a member of the American Economics Association and the American Academy of Political Science. </p>
         <p> Orton died on August 13, 1952 following a heart attack, ending a 30 year career on the Smith College faculty.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The William Aylott Orton Papers mostly cover Orton's long history at Smith. Most of the material is comprised of articles, speeches, and publications. There is an occasional letter or two and some photographs.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_scope-org">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>This collection is organized into three series:</p>    
         <list type="ordered">
            <item>I. Biographical Materials</item>
            <item>II. Articles/Publications</item>
            <item>III. Photographs</item>
         </list>
      </arrangement>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>William A. Orton Papers, Smith College Archives, CA-MS-00063, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>The William Aylott Orton Papers were processed by Katrina Cokeng, '02, CDO Archival Intern in 1999-2000</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_43f746ae768634012fe1fa7353768ba0">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_e0886c593ab1383c0b67c366da75d3af">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="naf">Orton, W. A. (William Aylott), 1889-1952.</persname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College--Faculty.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-ser1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS</unittitle>
               <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                          id="aspace_c789d0dcf54bbb3c819e2584fa2de3fc"
                          label="Mixed Materials [310183630223286]"
                          type="box">960.1</container>
               <container id="aspace_45878c6ea4759446d5be88b20a8e703c"
                          parent="aspace_c789d0dcf54bbb3c819e2584fa2de3fc"
                          type="folder">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d5347bbb475ed1b9cd1712aa6eae9991">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The majority of the biographical materials are composed of newspaper articles on Orton and his activities. He was very active in the Smith community and beyond, so quite a few articles summarize his speeches and opinions. A few articles, for example, reveal his interest in the way radio broadcasting and movies were changing and developing. Orton also contributed many opinions to newspapers, and these are included in this series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-ser2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>SERIES II. ARTICLES/PUBLICATIONS</unittitle>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="1924/1946"
                         type="inclusive">1924-46</unitdate>
               <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                          id="aspace_0b17cfea604af7f22400b60debdba02d"
                          label="Mixed Materials [310183630223286]"
                          type="box">960.1</container>
               <container id="aspace_4fd10bfca759d207cd01f23c81461767"
                          parent="aspace_0b17cfea604af7f22400b60debdba02d"
                          type="folder">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3260dd63cd8b06375b91a90cba7d4942">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Many of the articles he contributed to magazines and journals are contained in the second series, and the materials cover a period from 1924 to 1946. He wrote articles for The American Journal of Sociology, The International Journal of Ethics, the American Economic Review, and the Journal of Social Forces, to name a few. He wrote a particularly controversial article for the Atlantic Monthly, entitled "The Thirteen-Year-Old Level." In this article, he talks about how advertising in the radio broadcasting industry negatively affected the popularity of radio as well as hampered the demand for radio sets. In addition to these articles, this series contains copies of chapel talks given by Orton in 1938 and news releases about the publication of Orton's books.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-ser3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>SERIES III. PHOTOGRAPHS</unittitle>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="1930/1939"
                         type="inclusive">c1930s</unitdate>
               <container altrender="Half letter document box"
                          id="aspace_1c1ebfddd8fbd1fb8c1c0a6fa17509b4"
                          label="Mixed Materials [310183630223286]"
                          type="box">960.1</container>
               <container id="aspace_f75f5aff112e3c5c40005cc6820bc20c"
                          parent="aspace_1c1ebfddd8fbd1fb8c1c0a6fa17509b4"
                          type="folder">3</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_79075c33cc230cac2afd731d2fe0cc2f">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The photographs are primarily composed of formal portraits of Orton, and all seem to have been taken in the late 1930s. There is also one photograph of Orton's twin sons standing in front of John M. Greene hall.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_list-serBKS" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>BOOKS ON SHELF</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_0a6b8eaeaf14b0e08522106f9ed3e221" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>America in Search of Culture</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_2f5f4092169e9da0c894d37a088c1eeb" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>Prelude to Economics</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_edeb34c0d696973c2667f0e507ae0c29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>The Last Romantic</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_5972c8b368ee35b4d4d85a5d54d76b9f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>Twenty Years' Armistice</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_de15744a72d2e9f252234de2e217618e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>The Economic Role of the State</title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
