<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss430</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz papers <num>SSC.MS.00520</num>
            </titleproper>
            <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
            <author>Finding aid prepared by Burd Schlessinger; updated in 2018.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-02-08 13:06:32 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:18-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-12-04</date>
            <item>Container list and descriptions added for latest accession; updated collection-level notes to current standards</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_3936" source="local_inmagic-people">Berman, Ruth</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00520</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">21 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(13 unspecified boxes (likely record cartons), 2 letter document boxes, 1 flat oversize box)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="part">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 items</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(11 DVDs, 10 loose and 1 in original packaging)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1956/2018"
                   type="inclusive">1956-2018</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_b58fc055a30b9c33f90222011aa7cde1">Lesbian activists; Teacher, Health and Physical Education; Professor; Counselor. The Ruthie Berman and Connie Kurtz Papers include personal correspondence and emails, scrapbooks, photographs, and files related to gay and lesbian rights, same-sex marriage, and women's rights. The collection also includes audiovisual materials, production notes, and public relations materials pertaining to the documentary about the couple: Ruthie and Connie: Every Room in the House (2002). The most recent accession also includes material related to Connie's death and obituary.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The papers were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by Connie Kurtz and Ruth Berman in 2005, with additions in 2006 and 2018.</p>
         <p>Acc: #05S-32 was donated by Donald Goldmacher, producer of Ruthie and Connie: Every Room in the House; the film's original title was"Ruthie and Connie: More Than a Love Story." There is a separate COG for his accession.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <altformavail id="aspace_admin-altform">
         <head>Additional Formats</head>
         <p>Selected videotaped recordings have been copied for research use.</p>
         <p> Digital copies are available for select recordings. Please contact us for more information.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Ruth Berman was born in Brooklyn, NY on March 30, 1934 to Jeanette Zahner and Milton Green. She graduated from Thomas Jefferson High School in 1951 and went on to earn her B.S. (1955) and her M.S. (1958) in Health and Physical Education from Brooklyn College. From 1971 to 1974, she was employed as a teacher and administrator at various middle schools and high schools in the New York City area , and at Brooklyn College as adjunct professor.</p>
         <p>Constance Kurtz was born July 19, 1936 to Rose Levy and Elias Levy. After graduating from high school, she worked in Brooklyn, NY and in Jerusalem, Israel; her job descriptions have included bookkeeper and election campaign volunteer. Ruthie and Connie met in their Brooklyn neighborhood in the late 1950s and became fast friends; both were in traditional marriages and both had children. In 1970, Connie moved to Israel with her family. When Connie returned to the U.S. for a visit in 1974, she and Berman fell in love and began the challenging process of coming out, divorcing their husbands, and beginning a life together as a lesbian couple. The process propelled them into becoming politically active for gay and lesbian rights, and in 1988 they sued the New York City Board of Education for domestic partner benefits (Berman was a health and physical education teacher at a Brooklyn high school), winning the landmark case in 1994. Connie passed away in June of 2018 after a long battle with cancer.</p>
         <p> Both Berman and Kurtz are certified counselors and in that capacity founded The Answer is Loving Counseling Center, where they have served for over twenty years. They travel widely, offering workshops that focus on skill-building towards a more functional life, including workshops for gays and lesbians and their families. They have started branches of Parents, Friends and Family of Lesbians and Gays (PFLAG) in Florida and New York. They also run a T-shirt business: Not So Subtle Ts, and they host a web site (ruthieandconnie.com). In 2000, they began serving as co-chairs of the New York State NOW Lesbian Rights Task Force, and they are members of the GLBT synagogue of the Congregation Beth Simchot Torah. Ruthie and Connie have appeared on national radio and television, including The Donohue Show, Geraldo Rivera, Bill Boggs, and WBAI. In 2002, filmmaker Deborah Dickson made a documentary film about Berman and Kurtz, titled Connie and Ruth: Every Room in the House (produced by Donald Goldmacher).</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_aa86bf6d8655f57953fdd1447250c831">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>This collection has been received in six separate accessions between 2005 and 2018. Currently, only the most recent of these accessions has an online contents list in the form of this finding aid. The other accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <phystech id="aspace_3c649639d6fde8d5797b533a35199a9d">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, MS 502, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Processed by Burd Schlessinger, 2005.</p>
         <p>The 2018 addition has not been processed, in the sense that archival arrangement and description beyond creating minimal box lists has not been done. The arrangement and description of materials may change in the future as iterative processing occurs. Researchers are encouraged to document their citations with this in mind.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Ruthie Berman and Connie Kurtz Papers include personal correspondence and emails (1963-2005), scrapbooks (1980s-2005), photographs (circa 1950s-2000), and materials relating to gay and lesbian rights, same-sex marriage, women's rights, and Berman's and Kurtz's activism with regard to these issues. The collection also includes audiovisual materials, production notes, and public relations materials pertaining to the documentary film about the couple's relationship, Ruthie and Connie: Every Room in the House (2002). The collection documents their personal lives, first as wives and mothers in traditional marriages and, later, as a lesbian couple and as grandmothers. Also includes materials related to Connie's death and obituary.</p>
         <p> [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that they own copyright, Berman has assigned the copyright of Berman's works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Berman, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Domestic partner benefits--New York (State)--New York</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Gay rights--united States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Gay activists--New York (State)--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Jewish lesbians--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Jewish women--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian activists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbianism--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian feminism--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)--History--Sources</geogname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Ruthie and Connie: every room in the house--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dickson, Deborah</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Goldmacher, Donald</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Ruthie and Connie : every room in the house / a film by Deborah Dickson; produced by Donald Goldmacher--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photograph albums</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">scrapbooks</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publicity</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">DVD video discs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">CD-Roms</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_3936"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Berman, Ruth</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="naf">Kurtz, Connie</persname>
    
    
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_3cff51ec7e6c7018b26d8137060c5221" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz papers addition</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-S-0077</unitid>
               <origination label="source">
                  <persname authfilenumber="people_3936"
                            role="dnr"
                            source="local_inmagic-people">Berman, Ruth</persname>
               </origination>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(2 letter document boxes, one flat oversize box)</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4847cdf3d533b33a09372a1c2e5d9083">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Materials sent by Ruthie Berman after Connie Kurtz's death. Records document the creation of their film, the counseling center (The Answer Is Loving) that they co-directed, support for political work, their lawsuit against the state of New York for domestic partner benefits, awards, and Kurtz's obituary.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <controlaccess>
               <persname encodinganalog="600"
                         authfilenumber="people_3936"
                         role="dnr"
                         source="local_inmagic-people">Berman, Ruth</persname>
            </controlaccess>
            <c02 id="aspace_f3853f9cf823610a537b3284f23dd249" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographical information of Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">3 folder (1 in Box 1, 2 in Box 3)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1993/2018"
                            type="inclusive">1993-2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_2b215e35276e35b48ad848aa2489e3ea"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_e2077a961a801a6dead3e80428a6d3ab"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_65120e22d6677e6f2725e82d05506361" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Connie Kurtz obituaries, articles, and condolences sent to Ruth</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2002/2018"
                            type="inclusive">2002-2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_35e0722fad907266c9f3b7ac98b06d11"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_2310b50da0f4815525d89108ad6202db"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9b0af95934c0b9d765af4af7fb0bac7f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Awards given to Ruth Berman and Connie Kurtz</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_e63f1f625c7883fde4e7a713bdce38f6"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9c65893757069eda93d51a590a1785e3" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Proclamation from the US House of Representatives honoring Berman, Kurtz, and The Brooklyn AIDS Task Force</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2001-04-01/2001-04-01">2001 April 1</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_c463278eae936418f6991448bf8c4f1d"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9845cece2e8467daa38f47b2462adc9b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>The Answer is Loving Counseling Center newsletters, event fliers, notes, information, and correspondence</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(3 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1986/2005"
                            type="inclusive">1986-2005</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_1847f02de9310b54598ab855b9aebddf"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_458fceed514cd44e89d5d6a64e139d5f"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_57849b7e2026c07e3f1e6f8090ed986d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence to and from Berman and Kurtz, including cards, letters, counseling evaluations, and donation appreciation</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(4 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1983/2004"
                            type="inclusive">1983-2004</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_def3bb7c0534d36cf4fdab5bf9a4bee8"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_71c51484b796d7761e10db4c6a59141f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Not So Subtle Tees" mail order forms</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            certainty="approximate"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2000/2000">approximately 2000</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_b09fd265d7e8b59934eb9f210c788011"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074465]"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_182c5e1d2d9974163beb4ec93d6ca6e2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Domestic partnership lawsuit: Florida</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2004/2004">2004</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_3f34c90d63796715c388d71aab3b73ce"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074473]"
                             type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c28047f4a180da492c9a04cd52f9c835" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Domestic partnership lawsuit: New York</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(3 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1988/2017"
                            type="inclusive">1988-2017</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_a0416f2fd8f24b708699e37612f45591"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074473]"
                             type="box">2</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6e2e4b28a808f444d6d9115f89a0d113" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>News clippings related to marriage equality and domestic partnerships</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1993/2015"
                            type="inclusive">1993-2015</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_fdc45aafc2ed5569c7e786845d4b49aa"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_f8d015deec863e983f8839033c6e96c4" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Film, <title>Every Room in the House</title> events, news, background information (formerly <title>Ruth and Connie: More than a Love Story</title>)</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(4 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="1990/2011"
                            type="inclusive">1990-2011</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Letter document box"
                             id="aspace_a2e3267611aa53c4577dd3b7e472eca4"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074473]"
                             type="box">2</container>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_6ca522dd7ade47de9b3c8f5f9de61bf2"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_2c36f8c3313f77cc680e44b50a6fdb99" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Ruthie Berman and Connie Kurtz film and television appearances</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-S-0087</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 items</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(11 DVDs, 10 loose and 1 in original packaging)</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_79456f1ee354e5c1ca860686d78c6579">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Updated version of "Every Room in the House" and recordings of television appearances.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <controlaccess>
               <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">DVD video discs</genreform>
            </controlaccess>
            <c02 id="aspace_3b9583fad96f1a03fa47decb2f13aa53" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "CNBC News, Point of View: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1989-07/1989-07">1989 July</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_0fc71b0fb90eae7a2bdb8c8f6b3eaea2"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6f0d919074b3fc00bb276d1c70c7cf78" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "TV New's Clips and In the Life Program: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1990/1990">approximately 1990</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_b0b6071be5eeb082242c5f5594a8ce14"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9915a7dfdfab9c6b939aa1b76a95d17a" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Lawyers Live: Same Sex Marriages, Ruth Berman, Connie Kurtz, Paula Ettelbrick, Rev. Pat Bumgardner, Robert Peters, Skip Robokoff, Bob Peters and Bob Oeters"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1991-03-05/1991-03-05">1991 March 5</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_04a37832e3703a19fffc4e41a7ded232"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7958e60f0d21f2f5e6b6a1ab191c2236" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Night Talk: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1992-05-20/1992-05-20">1992 May 20</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_d6efad3084dda4515d6148607886ee1c"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9422b4f2b1bb87e3da3788e98da8b004" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Lavender Health: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1993-11/1993-11">1993 November</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_83f50aa8dc774d49253145817090838a"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c768cea9f06ba1b335f62bb5f249df3f" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, copy DVD, "CNBC News Point of View, TV News, Lawyers Live, Night Talk, Lavender Health"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1989/1993" type="inclusive">1989-1993</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_1ea6c98dea15bd05d1383ad1afa5f5da"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_799d811b2e3a0b7fd9e774a97102ca22" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Geraldo Rivera Show: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1991-01-28/1991-02-04" type="bulk">1991 January 28, February 4</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_3596fa081c1ca9733cdd3d467495c3bd"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_37497c0ddf421bf087c661e2cd6fd12a" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Phil Donahue Show: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1990/1990">approximately 1990</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_3dcd844971667df4229dd3c98c4445dc"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6b7a2cee57156e148a445e13cf404435" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "CLGR"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1991-03-19/1991-03-19">1991 March 19</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_2b14818530337217532c3fab9bb78141"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_fe7e4ce4e3e7af4a879d4250e8a3d5b0" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Nassau Now Meeting: Ruth and Connie"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">1 DVD (Master DVD, VHS tape to DVD recording)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="1992-06-17/1992-06-17">1992 June 17</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_1b4790df66058c3175921f1619e5df39"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_3b301d9d1a3abc5950a8ab7f07eac5a2" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Video recording, "Ruthie and Connie: Every Room in the House"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 DVD)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="2014/2014">2014</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Flat box (11d x 3h x 17w)"
                             id="aspace_cfbe3f9eea8c6c2d88a83454c6d03f87"
                             label="Moving Images [310183630074481]"
                             type="box">3</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
