<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss558</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Alan Guttmacher Institute records <num>SSC.MS.00720</num>
            </titleproper>
            <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2014</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-11-26 15:48:08 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:22-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018/08/10</date>
            <item>This record was revised to reflect the addition of new materials.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Alan Guttmacher Institute records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname authfilenumber="people_5096" source="local_inmagic-people">Alan Guttmacher Institute</corpname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00720</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20 boxes</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(20 linear feet)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(10 record cartons)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1960-2013 (ongoing)</unitdate>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_f092e34d4b293376aac572ec2e7069a3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>, <language langcode="spa">Spanish</language>, <language langcode="por">Portuguese</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <abstract id="aspace_790d16289c50600b6f7ee5ccc33091d6">Birth control advocacy organization; Birth control research organization. Records include reports, data, publications, administrative and financial records, some correspondence. They document especially well the efforts of a fact-finding organization determined to disseminate as widely as possible the data it collects so as to help shape policy to increase access to reproductive health services, and to "to ensure the highest standard of sexual and reproductive health for all people worldwide." They also include the papers of Jacqueline E. Darroch and Christopher Tietze. [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Founded in 1968 and first known as the Center for Family Planning Program Development, the organization was initially part of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA). The Center had as its champion Alan F. Guttmacher, the prestigious obstetrician/gynecologist/educator who served as PPFA president for more than ten years until his death in 1974. By 1977, the Center was renamed the Alan Guttmacher Institute (AGI) in Dr. Guttmacher's honor and incorporated as an independent non-profit organization with its own Board of Directors, distinct from PPFA. But its mission and goals remain the same since its founding. As stated on their Web site, "The Guttmacher Institute advances sexual and reproductive health and rights through an interrelated program of research, policy analysis and public education designed to generate new ideas, encourage enlightened public debate and promote sound policy and program development. The Institute's overarching goal is to ensure the highest standard of sexual and reproductive health for all people worldwide." To that end, AGI maintains an impressive Web site, making widely available the facts and figures they so carefully collect. [source: <extref href="http://www.guttmacher.org/about/mission.html">Guttmacher website</extref>]</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Records include reports, data, publications, projects, administrative and financial records, some correspondence. They document especially well the efforts of a fact-finding organization determined to disseminate as widely as possible the data it collects so as to help shape policy to increase access to reproductive health services, and to "ensure the highest standard of sexual and reproductive health for all people worldwide." They also include the papers of Jacqueline E. Darroch and Christopher Tietze, as well as Darroch's slides relevant to the organization.</p>
         <p> [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection with the following caveats:</p>    
         <list type="ordered">
            <item>Partially restricted access - contact the Sophia Smith Collectionfor more information.</item>
            <item>This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may bedifficult to use.</item>
         </list>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Sophia Smith Collection owns copyright to the unpublished works created by the Alan Guttmacher Institute in this collection. Copyright to materials authored by others may be owned by those individuals or their heirs or assigns. Permission must be obtained to publish reproductions or quotations beyond "fair use." It is the responsibility of the researcher to identify and satisfy the holders of all copyrights.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Alan Guttmacher Institute Records, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <accruals id="aspace_admin-accruals">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic additions to collection are expected and may not be reflected in this record.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Alan Guttmacher Institute began donating their records to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2013. Periodic additions to the collection are expected.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Accessioned by Kathleen Banks Nutter, 2014.</p>
         <p>2018-S-0046 and 2018-S-0052 processed July and August 2018 respectively. Original organizational structure and folders were preserved; background information and inventories for each project were donated and have been used in the descriptions for each file. Original inventory sheets have been photocopied and added to the beginning of each section.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_add-related">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Associated materials can be found in the Joy Dryfoos Papers and in the Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Abortion -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Birth control -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Birth control -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Birth control -- Research -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Reproductive rights -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dryfoos, Joy G.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Guttmacher, Alan Frank, 1898-1974</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Jaffee, Frederick S.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Planned Parenthood Federation of America -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Center for Family Planning Program Development -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Agendas</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Annual reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Brochures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Electronic records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Electronic mail</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Grant proposals</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Surveys</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Slides</genreform>
    
    
    
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" authfilenumber="n50075375" source="naf">Planned Parenthood Federation of America</corpname>
    
         <corpname encodinganalog="610"
                   authfilenumber="people_5096"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Alan Guttmacher Institute</corpname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_5129"
                   role="dnr"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Audam, Suzette</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_5129"
                   role="dnr"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Audam, Suzette</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_69a354817fd8c1cc9db7b5d3ceb7cbe1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Alan Guttmacher Institute website</unittitle>
               <unitid>2013-S-0076</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 website</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(1 website)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="2015/2015">First captured 2015</unitdate>
               <dao actuate="onrequest"
                    href="https://wayback.archive-it.org/6150/*/https://www.guttmacher.org/"
                    show="new"
                    title="Link to Alan Guttmacher Institute website"/>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_efeeff342db982177e9f843973209be0">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Institute publishes on its website a wide range of resources on topics pertaining to sexual and reproductive health, and articles from its two publishes two peer-reviewed journals, Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health and International Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health, and the public policy journal Guttmacher Policy Review. This archived website was first captured in October 2015. Subsequent captures are scheduled annually.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_721f6ae4d6ad9e14375d99a853ec6dc4" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Guttmacher Institute project records and Jacqueline E. Darroch slides</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-S-0046</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(3 record cartons)</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6b24f5e3bf3b792189fa7d6baedd1984">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Includes Jacqueline E. Darroch's slides and the project records of Men and Contraception; ACT for Safe Abortion; Managed Care and Opening Doors; and Birth Girls</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <acqinfo id="aspace_ff822cf9809470f54b76b62afcc78a70">
               <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
               <p>Records created and held by the Guttmacher Institute and prepared by Kyra Gilbreath.</p>
            </acqinfo>
            <processinfo id="aspace_61a3657bd7538dd0eb9afefb478a0a41">
               <head>Processing Information</head>
               <p>Organized before donation by Guttmacher Institute intern, Kyra Gilbreath; her inventory sheets are included with the donated materials.</p>
            </processinfo>
            <c02 id="aspace_5b5b97397df29ec3b5610ecce695d1ec" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Managed Care and Opening Doors files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(12 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_4cb635655109016ed21fc955dde8813e">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Managed Care: The Alan Guttmacher Institute's project Mainstreaming Family Planning in Managed Care aims to document and evaluate how well managed care serves the contraceptive needs of American women, especially those who are poor. The Survey of Women will involve a telephone survey of 1,000 women enrolled in managed care plans across five states.</p>
                  <p>Opening Doors: Low-income and minority women have greater difficulties than other women in avoiding unplanned pregnancy; in part, this reflect lower levels of contraceptive use and higher likelihood of contraceptive failure. However, it is not clear whether racial and ethnic
differences simply represent the greater socioeconomic disadvantage of black and Hispanic women or if they result from other characteristics of or barriers faced by these women. This study sought to learn directly from low-income women about their perceptions of and experiences with contraceptive methods and contraceptive service providers. Using that information, a further goal of this project was to inform policymakers and those providing contraceptive and other reproductive health information and services to women about how they might better meet the needs of low-income women and minority-group women. The key objective of this project was to document the attitudes and experiences of
low-income women and minority women with regard to obtaining contraceptive information and services and effectively using available contraceptives.</p>
                  <p>Background information was prepared by the Guttmacher Institute to be sent in with the materials.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_053a2e9feec9e8429b174c5d1af64f07">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Materials include publications, surveys, findings, proposals, meeting notes, field notes, and correspondence related to the Managed Care and Opening Doors projects.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_5e6bf2f91b0103bb7cc2edff1dc48d65" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care article drafts and 3 surveys</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4af98a6b844ca915bc223c0606f6e68c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_0d5909a2fef8437d1704dfe4839a5968" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care findings and drafts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b5659bc1bcb551133ec7010c8d709635"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8c290ad8c43eb4a0b91069e719cb4e1b" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care data: coding, keypunching</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_2a3cf637ac93117b8d8b1819dd033a00"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a7648ed8bd3a96f78c7df026f607f204" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care questionnaire development</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_03cb937538c76ebfcb7c251320302c6b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_52d0cfa6d7a202b2d715913074e23428" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care Kaiser proposal revision</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6bb690fba6fff96bac74be45fab03e81"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_f22901fc535dde690e3e6f13d9c40afb" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care survey methods group</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_eea51f8a086a36efa3805a388c01c755"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_91d4952103c8072b3da79424e411f7c5" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Managed Care advisory panel meeting</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997-12/1997-12">1997 December</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_75e6aea19a99891387701f122fa82afd"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_071a3bc35c4f032e89a08b07b8b4597f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors copies</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_aeae89f32eb53089f27f892fff6fe191"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3ecc11cda323cd0f3c31123f8fe9b625" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors focus group transcripts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1996" type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a117ad7c5e328a8ae78ed074335d23ff"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_722ff403a8818668bb7408ef1a161360" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors field reports and correspondence with MDI</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1995" type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4130af53096e26f0f49953065ccc70f3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_82f2e6b7cabea0c25a7ef32b7c80b409" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors original charts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1996" type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_add18c81394d689fb7e28e274b3bcfdb"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_16e6d836ae47decabd0462e8af701e91" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors preliminary figures</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 binder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-11/1995-11">1995 November</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_dfb9a12274a343d15c0899b9da0b944b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_82fdd4b2506edb8bae5d626a3e7a9721" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Opening Doors questionnaires and open-ended responses</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1996" type="inclusive">1995-1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_da08cdc130ff3528be8a380665141266"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_787b6bbcc551acff4892c342bf0c4ab1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Reassessing United States Family Planning and Reproductive Heath Needs research files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(15 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_6ffdfbd7fd4dbc570b00bed8fc017f45">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>The ultimate goal of this project is to reduce the level of unintended pregnancies in the United States. This project uses a variety of data collection and analysis activities designed to monitor family planning clinics and the clients they are serving.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_74f9306ca5b8bb2496eefd6feea562bd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Materials include research plans, surveys, correspondence, mailings, clinic records, CDC services and records, and client data.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_23947b03f122caf512cb037b9b82c2b4" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family planning needs and assessment papers</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1999" type="inclusive">1994-1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e49f93c60fe5f51de19ce744d00a3a04"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ebef6e6a843f9caef254523c71a8963e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters from reporting systems</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0fe1ea027d765bcec7148b2efe98e8d6"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_5df43dc84a4f2078dd9053d7dc4f5c5e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women at risk 1995 papers</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate>1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_096a5df357cc4f31d90ef5c70a7eed2f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4d5a5752acd22214559fef6b9efd4292" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>CP needs and services mailing</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1998" type="inclusive">1995-1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f426390770707d9b6945388823907a97"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_6a6e0a72add3e2f07fbff0ad75a571af" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clinic census directory sources and fieldwork records</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_1813e85b99e6779b970511ec720533dc"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_f3289b0e03af7f413a0cd341d7fc1b1e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Client clinic data revisions</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1996">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_bd6c460af968e5bc7ff852dbbfa28379"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_da79303723901d8f3f10883704e6f59c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family planning clinic information and articles</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6b41caf895e2457167b21fa833ebbf74"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4ef60aa7cabac57637cad83ba7cdb7b6" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family Planning Clinic Services in the US</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1994">1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_1aa4181388b86c8c9bfa67eb5b7c044f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c7e3cdeae4aa648ff465a60e1e68e76e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Indian Health Services directory</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ed4781c44bbcf0131a5df1c60ef49664"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_b1bd636e294197a760e2a98ac6bc75a6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>300 ACT Sharing Responsibilities, "ACT for Safe Abortion"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(5 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_325b86ad0a3acdebd67cc1bd7ffac2c2">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>"The ultimate goal of this project is to increase women's access to safe abortion services, by compelling decision-makers to act by generating the political will to make abortion safe, legal, and available. The project's specific objectives are:</p>
                  <p>Increase the quality and quantity of accurate high-priority information on abortion care available to policymakers and key stakeholders through research, the publication of a global chartbook, at least two journal articles and a range of communications products (fact sheets, policy briefs, PowerPoint presentations, etc.) in order to advance evidence-based discussions and policies; and through assessment of knowledge gaps and research needs in the Buffett Foundation's 11 priority countries leading to preparation and submission of proposals to address identified high priority questions and issues.
    Communicate/disseminate findings and materials to global, regional, and local audiences to reinvigorate policy discussions on clandestine abortion and advance evidence-based policies at all levels.
    
Project components: The monograph included a literature review of the past 10 years of evidence about the safety of abortions and included analysis of Guttmacher's AICM projects in select countries that had recent project activity including: Guatemala, Nigeria, Pakistan, Philippines, Uganda, Burkina Faso, Ethiopia, and Mexico."</p>
                  <p>Background information submitted with the materials by the Guttmacher Institute.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_94a19b33a372ab3070d688ef9a02c5b9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Materials include the article published in the Women's Heath Journal, proposal and earlier communication, PRB/Guttmacher meeting information, and reviewer comments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_91735d35e90fa727b08e6f255f8e281d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Women's Health Journal article and other final articles</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2007/2007">2007</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_64eae8a88bd16c72fd673c99a579fb9c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_028a67d3444e87785f0a900ff0fd4d92" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>300 ACT proposal and earlier communication</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2007/2007">2007</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_72febed4f3f8fa3495bd216e16092bba"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_118848056f427d8577f05f865cae4593" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>PRB and Guttmacher meeting in New York materials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2007-11-20/2007-11-20">2007 November 20</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e0494550ffbcf305e6b15c58a36813fe"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ee57cdd76c3305296f9f0c10a24efec1" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Unintended pregnancy article reviewer comments</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2010/2010">2010</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a1699941c8a428b899ea8cdd6fce083d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_038527173cea7d6b988fcc599d947057" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Journal submission invitations</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2010/2010">2010</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b7f4c0626fea6810d296b232863fed50"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_afc4231c217e18bf1de1415a52d09594" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Men and Contraception" article and research</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(11 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_1d5dda41cb48a869a0f8a6cdad6a12aa">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Final Article: Young Unmarried Men and Women Discuss Men's Role in Contraceptive Practice
Authors: David Landry and Theresa Camelo
Published in 1994 by Guttmacher Institute in Family Planning Perspectives (now Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health)
Description of the Study: "This research entails a series of focus groups designed to explore men's involvement in decisions regarding contraceptive use. It is one component of a project designed to begin to assess future directions for research regarding men and their attitudes and experiences regarding sexuality and contraceptive use. The project also includes a meeting of experts to discuss current and needed research regarding men and a special report summarizing research needs."</p>
                  <p>Background information included in the materials written by the Guttmacher Institute</p>
               </bioghist>
               <c03 id="aspace_4adcb413d1bc7d2c3f6e461bfcb8b662" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Men and Contraception MAC proofs/IRB</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f153c1b67b3afeb7ee350a396fcfcd3e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4494df265196599ac5860645f35bffc2" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Article submitted to Family Planning Perspectives, outside reviewers, exec staff, SRAs, and SA</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ea5c0f0411653b392037492c7888bac9"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3f637984c77d0017b46bae64c644a478" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Articles and focus group studies</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_956936fa64fe2fd4edb0aa5efbf31903"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_2ee606ed5c207702d9177f0eb826ba40" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Proposal and budgets</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_c97fb0fa9ff2fb7557614cf29dae6606"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c057532a8034a9e8ed49d33caa3d4660" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Focus group report and summary</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_49977de84e38bc2218f03d83c4c5341e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_0935fc57450d4d97c32db1ad2b2be50f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Bibliography information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_916b0bcb69887d2fe26b6e3da4b4e5e1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_19633f3f05a660131241ac365d3f38e4" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Men and Contraception meeting information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_59b253b94e115b2c4535f79a48b4e7aa"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c172fc23918e7bc75245d2e5cfbd324a" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Internal memos, meeting notes, and grant announcements</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_2651b68528b973b5198411010cec1ad5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013117]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ed7fb5c48c58a133bd81548305445c74" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Birth Girls files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(16 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_9cc4149dac0bc1523dfc4b31040b62a8">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Files for "A California Study of Why Young Women Carry a Pregnancy to Term"</p>
                  <p>Principal Investigator: Jennifer Frost, Dr. P.H.</p>
                  <p>Project Description: "As part of The California Wellness Foundation's (TCWF's) Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Initiative, the Alan Guttmacher Institute is undertaking an investigation into issues surrounding teenage childbearing in California. Key questions that underlie this project include: Why do so many adolescents become pregnant and why do those who do so accidentally (the great majority) carry their pregnancy to term rather than have an abortion? What can be done to emphasize preventive behavior, what services are available to assist teens facing a pregnancy; and what factors, life circumstances and parental, peer or partner pressures are involved when teens decide to carry a pregnancy to term?"</p>
                  <p>Background information included in materials sent by the Guttmacher Institute</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0d148addb2dcf93691bb7c01f2d65143">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Materials include notes and paper drafts, proposals, survey development, information on counties and prenatal care providers, correspondence, and final documents.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_17193c721d8ecdb43eed592d1e5977f9" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notes and paper drafts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_33b3d5410861f97d4bbabab53ca6555b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4f4ab55881872b0d1067cd4d73eabc6f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Survey development papers</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1999" type="inclusive">1994-1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f8d6a748c84ce5d38cf79d26afe96075"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_33779ab4cbb10bb8e76346b83ffa0fa5" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Santa Cruz County information and notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3fadb6decaf23e7eb328378fd3376c9e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_aaeb7b47bc988d5ef3b77b8f83c3d9d3" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Phone/fax survey of prenatal care providers</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1996">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_1dda08073dce48db76ac26d3fe542a67"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_39105e31d05c913cde112998c68c3ccd" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Early paper drafts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_cece719e99004fc4b1b31e0dd7b051c6"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_15c7e3f90f79aebc930b128de96eda6e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Planned Parenthood of Mar Monte correspondence and notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1996">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4416b7b6bc7f87a2b3dc0db5dda537b5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_691ac69b3c84456c0daaf45422046693" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Final documents for survey</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">approximately 1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4e2bc1372637fa4c5ecc87d660c7d40d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_7d29fddb3f8225e0e6012eefea508325" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Birth Girls final report</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder and 2 booklets)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_bc24fa3ad75a252cce28e021534da32f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_bcbee613c97c2866dfdcd1afcc7cb411" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>California Wellness Foundation: correspondence during grat</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1999" type="inclusive">1996-1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_caa0024b0f6dbac239c7c75ce03d9e7c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_534bdba90b23f49cc1cbec621a041107" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Early analysis files</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">approximately 1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_656612d87288acf621a57b60f1bf3459"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a5e0b62ef21fe85e24f0287fe5b92a41" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Memos related to articles and distribution</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/2000" type="inclusive">1998-2000</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6f7bb51744eae849179f2ac489113042"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8a7a3c3e7e7408cf9cbbb9174981a3e1" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Questionnaire development, pretest questionnaires and comments</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1996">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3287007b40075a870d09eafbc1fe5057"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_aa102784365d358f8d176070f0ca9a31" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>California Birth Girls proposal</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_c6ab6b9d7dc10d97174da54128298762"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d4d48add122dcd14c54b7fcee83b5495" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Birth Girls revised files</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ae970c751ac4089b1f4a1a121d2689d3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013174]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7c8b02cfede489e396b76026d9351bb9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jacqueline E. Darroch slides</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(6 binders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_e1613d17ea8fef20a315b6882ad882c7">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Darroch's bio from Guttmacher's website, Guttmacher.org:
"Jacqueline E. Darroch is a Senior Fellow at the Guttmacher Institute. She has been involved with the Guttmacher Institute since 1978. As Interim President in 2003 and Senior Vice President from 1996 to 2004, she provided leadership for the organization's policy-focused research and public education on sexual and reproductive health. She oversaw developments and opportunities in the areas of research, theory and methodology, health care delivery and financing, public opinion and behavior, and local, state, federal and international policies and programs. In addition, she worked to obtain funding from private foundations, the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services' Office of Population Affairs. Dr. Darroch also held the positions of Director of Research (19781988), Vice President for Research (19882002) and Vice President for Science (20022004). Dr. Darroch served as Associate Director for Reproductive Health at the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation from 2004 to 2006. She is the author or coauthor of more than 100 articles and publications on sexual behavior, fertility, family planning, maternal and child health, teenage pregnancy and abortion."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_065f8ab3482b57a17750750d66d728b4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>This box contains slides of presentations given from possibly 1990-1997 by Jacqueline E. Darroch (formerly Jacqueline Darroch Forrest). Some of the binders in these boxes contain handwritten notes regarding the order of the slides etc.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_803e1a1c3ea03b588e10abc7f5f1e02b" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Bright red binder, "Unintended Pregnancies: Why are there so many?"</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 item)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1990/1997" type="inclusive">approximately 1990-1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e416e5d403dbd60c208b058d466f6ce0"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_300af05e83173b7c54bbdf9242803095" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Large navy blue binder, multiple lecture topics</unittitle>
                     <unitdate normal="1990/1997" type="inclusive">approximately 1990-1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_40f8fe5ee4d18b89c9162b3fec6fc308"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_b958a821a845d39eab186e625eed359f">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>- U.S. Women's Perceptions of and Attitudes about the IUD J.E.D.
-Long-Acting Hormonal Contraceptives in the United States J.E.D.
-The Value of Contraception Felicia H. Stewart MD (OPA)
-What U.S. Data Tell Us Now about Norplant- 1995 National Survey of Family Growth- J. Darroch Forrest
-Handwritten note on Jacqueline Darroch Forrest stationery
-What We Learned from the 1995 National Survey of Family Growth J.E.D.
-Unintended Pregnancy: What is it and What difference does it make? J.E.D.
-Women's Interest in Microbicides J.E.D. and Jennifer J. Frost
-State Estimates of Annual New STD Cases J.E.D.
-Unintended Pregnancy: What is it and what's behind it? J.E.D.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_61003891ef913548fde7e97bc9850044" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Black binder with metallic spine, multiple lecture topics</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 binder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1990/1997" type="inclusive">approximately 1990-1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ce79834791812ba9cbb6c0f0900f3680"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_ac166100edbfc3b1e0728638d67a770c">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>-An Epidemic of Anti-Abortion Violence in the United States- David A. Grimes MD, Jacqueline
Darroch Forrest, Alice L. Kirkman, Barbara Raford</p>
                     <p>-Family Planning and Planning Families: An International Comparison Elise F. Jones, Jacqueline Darroch Forrest, Stanley K. Henshaw, Aida Torres
-Who Fits into the "Second Transition?"- Jacqueline Darroch Forrest
-Abortion Update: Medical Aspects of Pregnancy Termination
-WHO-The Risk Approach in Health Care (no title slide, but slides themselves are labelled with this)
-Health Care in the United States Jacqueline Darroch Forrest
-Risk and Responsibility: Teaching Sex Education in America's Schools Today 1989 The Alan Guttmacher Institute</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_be7b277b16045cb4bcc4377482726e31" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Black binder 1, multiple topics</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 binder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1990/1997" type="inclusive">approximately 1990-1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_7b1d421f80a93d5993be8b03003d8bf2"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_e89dc2853c830123baf65b3e859961bf">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>-begins with slide 91-001 Abortion rates, 1987 by income (no title page)
-two titles slides: Contraceptive Use and Access to Services: Needs of Low-Income Women and Sexual and Reproductive Behavior in the United States (both J.D.F.)</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_fdaad3e060cf5d1ee0af6e8f13c19d22" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Black binder 2, multiple lecture topics</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 binder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d59a82ab5a5cbd95433e9d6581397648"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_54b8be6c7646cd3e2d5b7e1a8915ab9a">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>-The Life Cycle and Contraceptive Needs: The thirties and beyond J.D.F.
-Why Isn't Every Pregnancy Planned? J.D.F.
-Stages of Women's Reproductive Lives: Times for IUD or Norplant J.D.F.
-some incomplete collections of slides
-title slide Epidemiology of Unintended Pregnancy and Contraceptive Use J.F.D.
-Twenty-Third Ortho Annual Birth Control Study 1991</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b168b5f018579d6f7f418f8b446f8faf" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Red binder, "Clinical Trials"</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 binder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a8986fd0dc65163e2f94a6a574f53b5b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630013232]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_4fb7ae7021472bdf295e4d1eb7938a92">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>-no title slide, but note "93-001-027 War [Women at Risk]  Win [Women in Need] ests-SPPA"
-Demographics of Barrier Contraceptive Use J.D.F.
-Oral Contraceptives
-maybe Epidemiology of Unintended Pregnancy and Contraceptive Use J.F.D.
-Sex and America's Teenager- The Alan Guttmacher Institute 1994
-Paper items tucked into the back of the binder "The History of Contraception Museum" and a chapter about the menstrual cycle
-Hand written note "1994"</p>
                  </scopecontent>
               </c03>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_3ee5a789f988fbc6508f624cf9dbe115" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Guttmacher Institute research files, staff files and project records</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-S-0052</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.5 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(6 record cartons)</extent>
               </physdesc>
            </did>
            <acqinfo id="aspace_685addf500b8ec7f349c819b98c660b4">
               <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
               <p>Records created and held by the Guttmacher Institute and prepared by Smith student intern Kyra Gilbreath.</p>
            </acqinfo>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_da7ea8041824ce969b00bf83fe315cdc">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>These records include notes, proposals, meeting information, drafts and critiques, correspondence, literature related to Guttmacher Institute projects, budgets, background information, data analysis, and statistics relevant to projects.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_7a76894a167b9e6f5d4b2d381d6b7f29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dr. Jacqueline E. Darroch's Files on Contraceptive Methods</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(7 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_f80403a30d0ac2c1a83d24a1634f735c">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Jacqueline E. Darroch is a Senior Fellow at the Guttmacher Institute. She has been involved with the Guttmacher Institute since 1978. As Interim President in 2003 and Senior Vice President from 1996 to 2004, she provided leadership for the organization's policy-focused research and public education on sexual and reproductive health. She oversaw developments and opportunities in the areas of research, theory and methodology, health care delivery and financing, public opinion and behavior, and local, state, federal and international policies and programs. In addition, she worked to obtain funding from private foundations, the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services' Office of Population Affairs. Dr. Darroch also held the positions of Director of Research (19781988), Vice President for Research (19882002) and Vice President for Science (20022004).
Dr. Darroch served as Associate Director for Reproductive Health at the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation from 2004 to 2006. She is the author or coauthor of more than 100 articles and publications on sexual behavior, fertility, family planning, maternal and child health, teenage pregnancy and abortion.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_896b2e62abde243390c445171b9419e1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>This box contains selections from Dr. Darroch's files on contraceptive methods. These are folders containing correspondence, Guttmacher internal memos, handwritten notes, and publications authored by Dr. Darroch. Much of what is here discusses the controversy surrounding early IUDs and the potential consequences of pulling IUDs from the market.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_6e5e13ee2718818f1817bdeedd0252f1" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Norplant correspondence and product info</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1989/1995" type="inclusive">1989-1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_2fe86cd2cb68ab783b8caacd2afed341"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_9d2c2f5f84714769218727d73ed2c48f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Non-Cp Hormones</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1985/1993" type="inclusive">1985-1993</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_66e3115242a37acef32cc59c08df6df5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_087df1ff085d14fcce15c34c518a0bf7" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Alza correspondence, company, and product information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1987/1991" type="inclusive">1987-1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_08fa4d9b59395acfd0d4236162ec8c51"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_61119949293f7cef7a566ffdbc3f1ae0" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>End of IUD background information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1986/1986">1986</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_7f0e78abbc78dd9958b211d277616a84"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_e6f3c34835b4e8cb0de5e139f2ef2d90" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>IUD articles and correspondence </unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1980/1987" type="inclusive">1980-1987</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_bf74f3b0df4e28bbf4d9b9b161bf0131"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_73b8a8670f90fd00e9531159ecf1817d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>End of IUD article</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1985/1988" type="inclusive">1985-1988</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_66d9b0ff5b6215c0f9551a6932518a90"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_e34d9a4444a3b2126bb716b2dc2237b9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>March of Dimes 1991</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(10 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_ef6ef70acc7b113401b2f236d80d5eb4">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>"The March of Dimes (MOD) and The Alan Guttmacher Institute (AGI) have agreed to seek funding for a national project on availability, accessibility and use of prenatal care. A proposal will be prepared during 1991, submitted to foundations and/or the March of Dimes grants committee, with the expectation that if funds can be raised for this project, work will begin in early 1992. </p>
                  <p>The national project would have two main components: the collection of county level data on availability and accessibility of prenatal care and possibly of health care for children under age two. This information would be collected by MOD chapters, under the supervision of their national and regional staff, and with technical assistance from the AGI. MOD chapter staff and/or volunteers would survey providers using questionnaires and procedures designed by the AGI in consultation with the MOD. The AGI would be responsible for checking, editing, coding and keypunching survey questionnaires, for creating a clean computer file for analysis and for producing detailed tabulations.
"-the compilation of new data on use of prenatal care services, similar to those published in the recent Institution publication: Prenatal Care in the United States: a State and County Inventory. This requires acquiring and processing detailed vital statistics files for 1987, 1988 and 1989. County level tabulations would be produced and analyzed."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8fb5383c42849e7084f3d964050f28d9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>These project materials demonstrate the "behind the
scenes" work that goes into a large-scale collaboration. They include information on the pilot study, correspondence, meeting notes and reports, proposals, and expense reports.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_e37adc7470fef9da19c254225d31cd24" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Pilot study handbook: March of Dimes Prenatal Care Needs Assessment</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991-07/1991-07">1991 July</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_5bfd3aeb5e5bb5acca1412852c508d03"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_7957d8052c89e1f6724f80d9524ae93f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes prenatal care needs assessment questionnaire</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_76f701e88778924515f6baa40e3e3abc"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8a6a5871ab1acc49e628d6b5b424ed4b" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes/Guttmacher Institute pilot study</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(3 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">1991-1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_064434d72fb284cdadb8f03573c203db"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a4ed8afe8fb2bdcd89ba4f4563098609" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes memos, correspondence, publications and surveys</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_c2761c45ed23820a183cba232ce29f7c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ec0bf04dd5dfe3a4b704c6b7f9600b9b" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence between MoD and AGI</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_07e7c42a6862dc661365b98db141d43d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_93bf35b15f422622b237b68ac2363e23" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes July meeting notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991-07/1991-07">1991 July</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e5ad9973373b96432866fed3ed516dc5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_0be0feec88b55b47ba8749b7cef3ace2" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes proposal</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">1991-1993</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_918d6d93c5ad3f3c5a6511e5d90d35cf"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_0a821b4a7d6e0a89b4aef07eca891f64" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>March of Dimes expenses</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_33209f6be74987d1ee57abeea38c2a85"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_8b8426bc680682f674ab1ef04c4557fc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Identifying Service Changes to Improve Contraceptive Use</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(3 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_21d586aef66f70f60b20d93d19a769a4">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>"Goal: The goal of this project is to contribute to the improvement of contraceptive use and the reduction of unintended pregnancy in the United States. To achieve this goal, the project focuses on three interrelated objectives:
1) "To provide a comprehensive, national frame of reference or "map" of key factors contributing to poor contraceptive use from women's perspectives, by surveying a national sample of sexually active women at risk for unintended pregnancy. This information will enable us to assess the relative importance and priority of these factors based on their contribution to women's difficulties in using contraception effectively."
2) "To match this map with information on contraceptive delivery practices in order to identify changes that have the greatest potential to reduce unintended pregnancy, by collecting data from a national sample of publicly funded family planning clinics and private doctors."
3) "To identify policy and programmatic implications and make concrete recommendations for next steps in service delivery and research that will help move knowledge into practice so as to reduce unintended pregnancy in the United States."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5a86847f4cb7ff9927378b4d4283698e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes project information, reports, and the following publications: "U.S. Women's One-Year Contraceptive Use Patterns, 2004" Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health, 2007; "Factors Associated with Contraceptive Use and Nonuse, United States, 2004" Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health, 2007; "Factors Associated with Contraceptive Choice and Inconsistent Method Use, United States, 2004" Perspectives on Sexual and Reproductive Health, 2008; "Public and Private Providers' Involvement in Improving Their Patients' Contraceptive Use" Elsevier 2008.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_5ed28e66d12b98fe1796c3268524cfa0" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Key project information (findings, American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists correspondence)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2000/2006" type="inclusive">2000-2006</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_586af2b23b399c2b5a19578e796c9ec8"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a53778fb47b995c4b85a9a847538e1ef" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Questionnaire development, physician's survey (planned publications by project, internal memos, survey cover letters, sample questionnaire)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1983/2005" type="inclusive">1983-2005</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e52cf6f39d627ed82afb92c7750690f8"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3f97b1cd0f2da994162d04417c0bb339" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Provider survey (extended follow-up of physicians by mail, telephone project final report, cover letter, IRB materials, questionnaires)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1982/2005" type="inclusive">1982-2005</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_971d38153122e454cc085f78a1f897d8"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_2c5c5126b3a0f96ef4111672f59489dc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cost of Contraceptive Coverage</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_3ea11e32bbfb042bf9dc7e939008189b">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>From the Project Description:
"Contraceptive Coverage in the Age of Managed Care (19981999)
With this one-year project, AGI will bring the best information to bear on the issue of access to contraceptive services and supplies through private insurance. The Institute will:
 1) Assess issues and information from existing research that have the potential to enlist the support of diverse groups for the expansion of contraceptive coverage and explore remaining questions and possible areas of contention;
 2) Synthesize and simplify existing research findings in a variety of public education materials; and raise awareness of the issues involved through dissemination, Web site posting and presentations to professional groups, organizations, opinion leaders and media selected for their ability to influence managed care organizations and consumers;
 3) Monitor major state and federal policy developments which would ensure coverage of the full range of contraceptive options for women covered by private insurance."
 
"Contraceptive Coverage in Private-sector Insurance Plans (1999)
 1) To mobilize support for contraceptive insurance coverage within the private-sector, AGI will assemble and work with a task force composed of a diverse group of key employers and employee benefits managers; labor union negotiators; large employers, insurers and managed care plans.
 2) In doing so, the Institute will identify arguments that may resonate with employers, insurers and managed care plans in order to persuade them to provide contraceptive coverage and messages that may convince labor unions and employee associations that contraceptive coverage is a vital component of employee health benefits and should be a priority in benefit-related contract negotiations with employers.
 3) "Finally, AGI will develop and widely disseminate a comprehensive action plan for private sector-focused activitiesincluding funding needs for such a planand begin reaching out to key commercial audiences with research and policy analysis from AGI and others on women's contraceptive needs, the limitations of current coverage and the benefits of coverage that is comprehensive.</p>
                  <p>"Contraceptive Coverage in Private-sector Insurance Plans (2001)
 1) AGI has undertaken a series of activities to ensure that contraceptives are affordable to all Americans. First, the Institute convened a working grouprepresenting labor, business, women's and reproductive health organizationsto refine and adapt persuasive
arguments (developed last year through AGI's contacts with business and insurance leaders) for the expansion of contraception in the private sector. The group is working to identify and involve new organizations and individuals that might be influential in the policy debate. This year, AGI will begin developing a methodology to quantify the costs and benefits of covering contraception in private insurance plans, to provide employers with a complete economic model they may consult in making coverage decisions.
 2) AGI is also examining employer-based health plans to map trends, monitor the needs of the uninsured and document options for those without coverage. AGI is building on its accomplishments in advancing contraceptive coverage in the public sector by making
staff expertise available to policymakers and activists who are working toward passage of the federal Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act and similar initiatives at the state level.
 3) Last year, AGI began an update of its 1998 study to ascertain the coverage of reproductive health services, contraception and abortion within private insurance plans overall. This information helped spur state actions to mandate contraceptive coverage in private insurance plans (13 states to date). Upon publication, the findings will be used to inform new efforts aimed at meeting Americans' needs for services."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c5e0bcb3d13b08e792358dda457407c0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes notes, internal memos, article drafts and handwritten notes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_022041375e82e1409c09646109eccb2d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Notes and internal memos</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2000/2002" type="inclusive">2000-2002</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b7e1d70ff8c2910bdcec271a1bb5195e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_10983e4786ceaaff30a18626673cc435" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Article drafts and handwritten notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2001/2003" type="inclusive">2001-2003</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_800f22532230f44e1a44c4cbeb1c6c0c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_e02cf8451b49251ac9b1c781e66ffa38" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>PPFA Access to Services/Fee Survey/AGI Physician Survey</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(6 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_d366ee3299d532d8a523953dc6d3eacc">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>These files relate to a 1986 project, PPFA Access to Services Teen Survey 1986.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_42d6d33adf78eef60412b8e08a1d706d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Many of these files contain surveys from the 1980s as well as internal memos. These folders were grouped together in the same storage box.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_dc325e1bd8bfb896df7caaab6022b6fc" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Fee Survey (questionnaires, cover letters, codebooks)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d21d3228892c39f954199f71f3d78eae"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4547ca50f6b886d58b6a18a1dae5167d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>AGI physician survey (methodology and report)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a0f128314f15e2be9acbb7a8f55b2f6b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_827e71f5b52fc7a2aad3fd9e97b21b63" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>PP access</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1985/1985">Summer 1985</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0e487cc76b8246aebc872d0332a07c1c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_19a6b988a33d8346183db8f23f49767c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>PPFA access study</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_327c0433a816bbd97839fb829e8e935a"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_1d3c83523dc28725af9dc01438bf4483" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>PPFA access study (coding and editing)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4168549fc68d95728da6574b58f281ee"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_e239810db78698a481c6ba91dd8c60f4" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family Planning Services in Industrialized Countries</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1987/1989" type="inclusive">1987-1989</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_9557a528a1f93ab15b02dec1df8147d3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                                type="box">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_79ae2c1df32001ebe62bb97994dbf39f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Impact of the Restriction of Medicaid Funding for Abortion</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4  folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(4 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_a4232b0dd4f8b9ba26d4a2ae317effa2">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>"Implementation of Congressional restrictions terminating federal funding for abortion except when necessary to save the life of the woman represents an extremely significant shift in U.S. public health policy. It has created an almost ideal laboratory for studying the consequences for both individuals and society of restricting access to abortion. The only previous case of such restriction occurred in Rumania in 1966. Michael S. Teitelbaum's study is now the classic
reference concerning its impact on subsequent fertility, supplemented by Nicholas H. Wright's study of effects on maternal and child health. Since the restriction potentially affected every woman and no alternative means of fertility control were readily available, the analysis of Rumanian experience was comparatively simple. While the current U.S. situation is fraught with
complexity, it nonetheless provides a rare opportunity to assess systematically the impact of such a policy change. The findings would be invaluable for both researchers and policymakers. It is therefore critical that evaluation efforts be planned and implemented without delay."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d374456e892ae6f5bc2f6a9c2b0be17f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes proposals, internal memos, correspondence, publications, figures, and meeting agendas.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_363ff57f1f60ef61db46334534606d43" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Abortion - Medicaid - Lindheim Study</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1977/1979" type="inclusive">1977-1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_eb92e8bf27957944959ec735a4126a1c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_7a865a5c1b2a63039fca8aef35800861" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Medicaid - Lindheim - Survey: restriction of funding/abortion</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1977/1979" type="inclusive">1977-1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_8bff578e44286857738f1761d89f70ac"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_6f4502bd473e9e97a8c3213871feda88" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Abortion funding publications</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1975/1979" type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_31a38c70fdec91b9d4a166fcb0ac52f7"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_971155d2e43554bb9fcd30bfc8664502" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Ab XIX correspondence, memos, figures</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_acc55d7595a5968a21bee059b3b87013"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c38119c88e8ae41c0d75342f94de3e46" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>STD Clinic Survey</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(26 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_3d63be78a45ad20637bdbeef77d15ac6">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Final Article: Public Health Departments Providing Sexually Transmitted Disease Services
Authors: David J. Landry and Jacqueline E. Darroch
Published by the Guttmacher Institute in Family Planning Perspectives 1996 (now Perspectives on Sexual and
Reproductive Health).
Description of the Study: "This project will describe and assess the adequacy of the nation's publicly-funded
sexually transmitted disease (STD) diagnostic treatment services. Information will be obtained by mailed survey
from a nationally representative sample of publicly-funded agencies that provide STD services. The results
from the survey will be compared with a 1995 AGI [Alan Guttmacher Institute] survey of agencies providing
contraceptive services to identify gaps and overlaps between the STD and family planning service providers in
outreach, clients served, services provided and referral arrangements. The project is funded under a grant from
DHHS' Office of Population Affairs (OPA) through an interagency agreement with the Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention. It is a component of a wide-reaching Alan Guttmacher Institute project, funded by
OPA, to reassess the nation's family planning and reproductive health needs."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1a9a90dcf1e8f54630e99fe5150af185">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes meeting notes, development notes, correspondence, code, fieldwork, statistics, results, and general information about the project</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_6943d169705b3161ea205e9504fb7b15" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>IOM Report</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b83deb895d39f85d3497d4afb89d3056"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_5432dedb19c802824b26bccad799849e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>STD SURV- pretest analysis</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b15da788e722663e06054f3da01bddec"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8b6eaff79f10066aa668fa44d6ea6588" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>CDC meeting proofs</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-06-30/1995-06-30">1995 June 30</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_511b386074c26979b4a6ad55c2107f15"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_1c950d617d0a9cdfc26821086953e3b3" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>STD SURV meetings</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-01/1995-10" type="inclusive">1995 Jan-Oct</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b8d07e2511c9ac1af251db99b2c5f8da"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b06f182d2aae09569f1d1cf6846b4920" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>STD SURV correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-05/1995-05">1995 May</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f2934ab4cc04869ea872aecedf9351f4"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_21c47cdb0351ff493fa175c21ab31e5d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>STD SURV/CDC meeting in New York</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996-03-25/1996-03-25">1996 March 25</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0b5bc40acb9b8c887302c369e6a6b184"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c8beca3bb3e10a1269a4f36fc6e51002" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Questionnaire development and pretest analysis</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d162a23167b72e3f8beadfdcc5d55a31"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_83d41ec176777c9c299549066e68ee1a" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Pretest materials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-05/1995-05">1995 May</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_64e979bee9ee79f322d7dd8188368d45"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b729607fcaf8951e964ea0799438f37e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>NACCHO survey</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_024cbe8d51a6621e6d006d09a4906392"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_989d4e775c944d46bce6da63121e8ccc" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sampling - NACCHO - CDC file</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_011c0550d6b222ff5944a18017f28387"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_67cdfe5d8f9d250ff0d92a2234006e9c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Fieldwork- Arkansas</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-12/1995-12">1995 Dec</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f11ab986fdf08b186123479ac4843ba7"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b28db5e9f82e8d22ed4c57550739f636" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>STD SURV- Est. of person days</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ae60920770ce37cdf9213c4ceb7ee67e"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_60f3fa55e5d80b0df73e20f504de0699" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Non-response phone calls</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6046da951b26c315c4b463e4e2b683db"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_95c2c110bc38c6f38f7dfadd29d701fe" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clinic survey OPA (CDC)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_28f87c2616ae3ae82b0f080dfa93419b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_09bb742a06c74513c11c302fd34a31ee" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clinic survey 2nd mailing</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-09-28/1995-09-28">1995 Sept 28</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a4f918b2354b37fecb21cd825fb5144f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_29bef9881b94499e4fc3ad5f2d84e78c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Clinic survey cover letter, 1st mailing</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_24c7c3ef372fcdc49131f8cb82c389cf"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_f84a6da37ab9c35b1a47376ec7439c9e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Survey returns pretest</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3855c05b54e9a86ed9077e2fbff6a527"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_06484b9679b7b07f2fccf51a8e8e7def" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>CDC - early sample, designs, etc</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_10ebb6784a9fa19a1951856d545747ac"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_88d83bcc88e325c1b3372d8ba59cea1f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Survey resends, clarifications, respondent comments</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6917227fb9b730dcfea6137a42dbe2e5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_062213a126ea77b4e9791181ed202350" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Survey letters, 3rd mailing</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_aa3296d7a41d46331821b6764f34f5f6"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_4301e4d7d9073d7e35faf99923e8b70b" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Field schedule information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f7225bd68e730c1c7d7dab7049543af9"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_69e537927c588eae7066328f9b8e2019" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Non-response f-up/unit districts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e7bcd3a7053ba281598d60243920e944"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d37e3530f4244258346194b25d772829" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Coding rules</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_6dd46ac343a79c20257770a73db2b4a3"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a142b32ea7c6f727d3c80d82c795a709" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Survey sampling</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_30adfab1ffd33a532b92799b222b07cf"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8d92ae5bf46784f2dbe72a5a9a8b838c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Codebook questionnaires</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0d954c4189846f0e7c6182463c170eef"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a1b5a64ff76d84bf54313a25da00f17d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unintended Pregnancy</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">21 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(21 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_63e3ce8cf54dffe27370339aa094a11e">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Purpose:
"The purpose of the project is to examine how the fact of a pregnancy being unplanned affects the health of the baby at birth and during early infancy. It is assumed that any such influence operates through the effect of the planning status of the pregnancy on the mother's behavior, which is, in turn, a primary determinant of the baby's well-being. The underlying hypothesis is that the unintended conception is associated with less personal input to promote the baby's health both during pregnancy and after the baby is bornThe investigation will evaluate the impact of unplanned pregnancy on women's behavior in two principal areas. The first consists of activities during pregnancy, and the second is care of the infant after birth. It is not possible, however, to identify and test the effects of planning status on all behaviors that could have a bearing on the health of the child. For this reason and because the ultimate significance of the mother's behavior lies in its close association with the health of her infant, the indirect relationships between planning status and measure of the baby's well-being will also be examined."</p>
                  <p>Publications:
1) "Intention Status of U.S. Births in 1988: Differences by Mothers' Socioeconomic and Demographic Characteristics" Family Planning Perspectives, 1995. Kathryn Kost and Jacqueline Darroch Forrest.
2) "The Effects of Pregnancy Planning Status on Birth Outcomes and Infant Care" Family Planning Perspectives, 1998. Kathryn Kost, David J. Landry, and Jacqueline E. Darroch.
3) "Predicting Maternal Behaviors During Pregnancy: Does Intention Status Matter?" Family Planning Perspectives, 1998. Kathryn Kost, David J. Landry, and Jacqueline E. Darroch.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_eee9894eadb737e51fd32f50b3da53e4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes planning meeting information and notes, financial and grant information, papers and drafts, and data.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_9a6e4241a818b59ae938c98898f406d6" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Galleys Stage I, Products</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1998/1998">1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b033eb031564a036443d78fc3372e227"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_1d5884431c4e478788e0bb35c380a105" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Intention Status (try 1)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_14b26e2f3ddd262825e6c2ca4e6a358d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_37c279351ecf8de50f303abfe84f0297" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Institute of Medicine (IOM)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1994" type="inclusive">1993-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_bdfe155d72dbd4f31d5d526c3a719b9a"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_03602f0307f3510b5555735e65fd60fa" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Meetings/advisory panel</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1998" type="inclusive">1995-1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4e4e07e21097c8c1c91ffd8090175cef"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_8ab20e9ec3c88ab147eebea3fd5e742e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>National Institute of Child Health and Human Development planning proposal</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_ecd007cb234190fb6e5b808ad370895a"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_62d0ce94d2f33ee6cf74c33b7cb74b5f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>National Institute of Child Health and Human Development planning status - financials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1996" type="inclusive">1993-1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e7c7833d16157e656ac14bb24a7c228d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_12654c456d0280000cd37093c9ff76d9" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Shannon Grant</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_4d3135f558e1ca181951a53bfed3ad3f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_9b7ac1b979cccd4e4c7ff9eafd20ba32" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Preg. behavior article (Family Planning Perspectives)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1998" type="inclusive">1997-1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_da3672a6215c785d73538228fe6d1fc7"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3b2c6d419733bd0c4c98af9ed1424fcd" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Year II financials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a64fe8faa60b6d571e956046c878e8bf"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_9dc08a69d2ec93803a8d0d8bfee54613" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Year III financials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1996/1996">1996</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0fff258620682bff80542439d9ad0ee5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_7f26c2f9e98fdfa6125d5044062b6644" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Unintended pregnancy - 2nd article</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1998" type="inclusive">1997-1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_10ed709867e97991722fae214f08aabb"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_dcae0fe1d0e6f3b732a00b24390211ee" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Advisory meeting materials</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994-11/1994-12" type="inclusive">1994 Nov-Dec</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f86843530878a11c44ed935a08331842"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d44acdbce2db295c4079420442535793" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Planning status proposal</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3b643c61d4764ad9e9dfc2442503c3b4"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_9eb41af4a6be36e4e3d33172c662eef4" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Population Association of America (PAA) paper and drafts</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_940e16d28794bed81a4a9881e97e5f6a"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_600e5f33e530986eb1f62c27fcce76d7" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Planning status - consult with Rodriguez</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-10-15/1995-10-15">1995 Oct 15</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_cbbb3a8b17ebf454a411052b7c61ca02"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_cf3eee20ca40547b5b0441390bc31fd7" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Stage I final stepwise</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1995-08-01/1995-08-08" type="inclusive">1995 Aug 1-Aug 8</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_693a0dc08efe67aa27e9ccf2dab73618"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_df75729cec00aa3f50f1af0ebabc6126" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>January 1997 meetings</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997-01/1997-01">1997 Jan</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_7f76e6cfdfeb605ec052abfdae5dfd79"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c260152cb88473012b35d2c0ce5e50f5" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Data documentation</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997-01/1997-01">1997 Jan</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_73348ce20291434341e2f9be86e86c00"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_b1db832649b505f51719bfe25006e187" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Stage II Vars: birth characteristics</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1994/1995" type="inclusive">1994-1995</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3c8578874e6cb4616b379939f91b55ba"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_75a9cfd9b5e754eff4900d091f841d98" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Action articles (drafts)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1997/1997">1997</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_09ff6c4bed8296a4fde3bfb161854d41"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_239f5150194caf0bfd9c098b5c4a35b8" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Proposals and articles</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1998" type="inclusive">1993-1998</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3c243f77e3b9502975976130d63edd54"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073467]"
                                type="box">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6bf3bad12b9b05cf428a9f101ca6e867" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"TP3" project files, or, "Successes of the Past, Opportunities for the Future: Reevaluating Teenage Pregnancy in the 1990s"</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(15 folders, contents of two binders in four folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_7c3a86a9709ca492e680bb7e64386906">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>From the Funding Proposal to the Charles Stewart Mott Foundation:
"Summary:
The Alan Guttmacher Institute (AGI) proposes to refocus and reorient attention on the problems of teenage sexual activity, pregnancy, abortion, and childbearing for the 1990s. To do so, AGI will collect and analyze the most recent information on these issues, synthesize the data, and present the findings, conclusions and recommendations in a new chartbook. Like its immediate predecessor, the Institute's 1981 Teenage Pregnancy: The Problem That Hasn't Gone Away, the updated version is intended to be a major source of information, presenting complicated research data in a simple and cohesive fashion and pointing to opportunities for policy and program action. With this publication, AGI will place teenage pregnancy within the larger context of what has been learned about adolescent and high-risk behavior in recent years as well as in the context of the concurrent increase in poverty, the decrease in services, the attacks on family planning programs, the growth of AIDS among adolescents, and the need for reproductive health services among young people. To enhance the chartbook's effectiveness, an extensive public education/outreach effort will be targeted to an audience of 5,000 policymakers, program planners, community leaders, activists, professionals working with youth and the press."</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5674d027d87d6d7e56807aa6fc1a0757">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Information from all stages of the project, including proposals, drafts, meeting notes, figures and comments, questionnaires, and general notes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_7fe32fa055358ed87bdcb82674a13cc7" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Teen Pregnancy 3 meeting notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_078a0e97a8ae739f0f8d57ad04cc3ce1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_86628816440435664b446e771f82af11" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>MCHB meeting</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-10-06/1993-10-06">1993 Oct 6</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d87531c221c1b385055a9280484d5ee9"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_2f8d6efd540ac8a03bb8ec8fa6905de8" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Gag rule information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_85e05a5eb6e53c4c669d7e111c6cc399"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_756cb886924d3c4d5c418b827e3800f4" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Advisory panel meeting</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992-09-18/1992-09-18">1992 Sept 18</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_b2ff37ed89031da21d41c40d1fde1a09"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a1af15badd4d696c8b030847b9c92f98" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 Edit #2 figures only, comments from OSN</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-12-30/1993-12-30">1993 Dec 30</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0ecd9373fed68a3859f06efe24812594"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_f18a428e0301b2102d522098211def4f" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 Meeting round 4</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-10-20/1993-10-20">1993 Oct 20</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_556a1929ccf16a8ed228da0e9185f573"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_16b66335abf5bfda3af5e28c25968567" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>David Landry (DL) notes for TP3 draft #3</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-10-18/1993-10-18">1993 Oct 18</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d152b1c90ad6bd2f9dce96acc5bbf66b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c6a675bf48879b765b0fa588ab5a75f8" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 Draft #2</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-09-21/1993-09-21">1993 Sept 21</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_99e8307fc82e00e8294077146f0d7dad"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_dab1dc002c2194ff6458253948010ed9" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 Draft #3 meeting</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993-10-20/1993-10-20">1993 Oct 20</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_864836c4b0c39a7f2d5304db77af35d0"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d261f9d28d87e8d2e2aee802004df7e5" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Questionnaires</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_9c4695781bb11916330b5be57a3d0f9f"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_08c70e01a2f7b674ad90c36d726c3bd3" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Other Guttmacher related publications</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_77b1053484997f7534ad69e4bd8d429b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_5a9be4e6fa4efbd670436f46a90e63f8" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 projects in progress</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_25dde9e89c5fb503551cbfff29a9ad70"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_575bd845748aeba5a0144c9020453a33" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>NMIHS (National Maternal and Infant Health Survey) notes</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/1993">1993</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_8cab8b023f3587a3b9792573749971c7"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_96ce58d20124e80564eab5c9d0535be6" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Background for TP3</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1990/1992" type="inclusive">1990-1992</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_3624ad69bf278e98a9e190422c2eff0d"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_feb4b8ea40da48f88bf80f7558990581" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>TP3 final paper articles and references</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1987/1994" type="inclusive">1987-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0fb1a5c9a08d6bbd0ea02e0611387def"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c2c84b02dabdf9c32b65c17ecdc21dd2" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Binder of figures and proposal</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e31f3aa95a183e320266db0326e24fa9"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_1bd2de9fd9f62d28fd128f89495f40d1" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Binder of project notes and figures</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1992/1994" type="inclusive">1992-1994</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d01f7bbd3beccb4c149ba4eff6d35d49"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073475]"
                                type="box">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_f4aff0afd3e238c0cc56f457e72c0a62" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Christopher Tietze files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(18 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_c94116ed30a9b5f556ce17373d6c3737">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>Christopher Tietze, a physician and respected authority on abortion, contraception, and pregnancy, began working for the Population Council in the 1970s. He authored several iterations of the report "Induced Abortion: A World Review." At the time of his death in 1984, Tietze was in the process of compiling the sixth edition of this fact book. The Guttmacher Institute undertook the completion of this project.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c9cf4fa29ff74d7418f99ca6af801b1d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>These files mostly consist of Tietze's correspondence and handwritten statistics sent to him by health officials around the world. What is particularly compelling about these files is that they represent the work that Tietze did in his final years, and the folder in Box 2 "1985 Abortion Fact Book" contains copies of the letters that he dictated on his last ever day in the office.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_0d6e9b725d1e88c1b52c612c1f883716" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"1975 and before = gestation and gest x age" (statistics)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1975/1975">approx 1975</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_aeff303b0cf11b342dac71a588183302"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_d09ca9e8cca13c4fb469cd4bf8920417" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Abortion Fact Book clippings, notes, statistics, correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(13 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1968/1985" type="inclusive">1968-1985</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_9fb92ea219cb58969e69dd2337dccfe1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_a5e703d0d61dd8d2ca04ebeca21b2502" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Deaging Data"</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1973/1980" type="inclusive">1973-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_2b1bc18187c105e4e7cba761b395d7ce"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_65806048314932ad3d4769e8b0beb010" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Induced Abortion: A World Review" by Christopher Tietze</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 items</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 book)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_832209d3da00d03434cec902012fbaf4"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3c398ea2567831e605bbc8860ae3de9c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>World Health Organization mortality from abortion stats</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_fb2fe8463ca0d42d8cba830b290443d5"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_6fab83cb47a5b9036825a9ccae84d37a" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Tietze correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_03dce34e007dae1f61dc1234887f0696"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073483]"
                                type="box">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_4131417f052d178b0537a65d04c2ce10" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Abortion in Guatemala</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(9 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial id="aspace_cd16c1b80340f49334ce16a5e6dbf34b">English and Spanish</langmaterial>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_89637314ce740b8c5a397ee1b70796bf">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>These files relate to research that took place in the mid-2000s about abortion in Central America. While these files primarily relate to abortion in Guatemala, there are some folders that contain information about Honduras and Nicaragua.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_66c5304280ef9da102d851b8f34daeae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Although these files give a less complete picture of the project, there are outlines and subsequent drafts that demonstrate the process of preparing a paper for publication. Files in this box are in both English and Spanish.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_22f4db217b21ff77ca1150dec34d02da" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Drafts, notes, articles, and email correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2005/2006" type="inclusive">2005-2006</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_11ce5e7aa8cc29213e83cb45908d1817"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_6a68d7d35ced911f3e81ba9bd76ba75a" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Outlines, drafts, and reviews</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2006/2007" type="inclusive">2006-2007</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_a8cd5b64b2618e08c9a636b95f104d18"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_83984c3934d4b11b8f31034a099c5dda" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"ACA: references to look up" email correspondence and memos</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2004/2005" type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_47c9a6a728cc6c10ab5cf3f18cf84d5c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_034b1dffcba3e3f8520bea06af96f248" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"RIB-2s General (all 3 countries)" (paper reviews and correspondence)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2006/2007" type="inclusive">2006-2007</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_39349c388a130a379abbf3e18727efc1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_6098bd4c6d2a2b7a10ee65043630c47e" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>HPS/HFS post-abortion care forms</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2003/2003">2003</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_9c61a511286803409fcd6012a5d4cb05"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_ed69ddb4b671961de48f2146021d0f48" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Honduras RIB-2" (information about Honduras in English and Spanish)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2001/2007" type="inclusive">2001-2007</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_736a26713454cb07017a6ab20a6832ce"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_3e1c00e2427079df9bbc4c45e8cae1cc" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Nicaragua RIB-2" (information about Nicaragua, English and Spanish)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="2005/2006" type="inclusive">2005-2006</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_488e3195fdd0aee564c417d893c9a894"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_324310337b31ca0a721db65f950f7d80" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Guttmacher publications </unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1993/2006" type="inclusive">1993-2006</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_75009c9e3dacd73ff99d696adfa3ad92"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_34f45769effd6a23a6a5c876e8934f1f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>5 Year Plan files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">58 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(58 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
               </did>
               <bioghist id="aspace_29c5c7b0387c398d0c41e8a8e070d063">
                  <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                  <p>These [files] are the entire contents of a box sent to storage in 1998. These files were deemed to be significant, and Guttmacher decided that they would be best preserved and utilized at the Sophia Smith Collection.</p>
               </bioghist>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7913b72bca0e57455874cc5f71d91c5f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>From the inventory sheet: "It is a bit difficult to pin down exactly which projects these files relate to. Many of the files relate to Title X and subsequent litigation. Some of the files relate to a project "Five Year Plan Family Planning Study." The dates of the files in these two boxes seem to range from the 1970s through the late 1980s."</p>
                  <p>"Five Year Plan Family Planning Study" refers to multiple projects conducted for various organizations by the Guttmacher Institute, all iterations of the same core idea to study family planning through various lenses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <c03 id="aspace_ef1d79ba878e5116146c8c1d5915f02c" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>"Pop 81" population statistics and notes on race, poverty distribution, marital status, and income, plus programming information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(6 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_f4f15369d411beaad6872af37ca49681"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_59345e631ef3a1edbeb4d148b1b8c985" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>FY 1971 city and county study of family planning services and patterns (includes proposals, negotiations, questionnaires, study materials)</unittitle>
                     <unitdate normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_40f93a9eb3e1003dc2bf982de770ba4b"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
                  <bioghist id="aspace_8ed529ac4b696ba2bbdd2ba3a236d22e">
                     <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
                     <p>From the questionnaire cover sheet: "This national survey is one part of a larger study which has been designed to: (a) estimate the number of women in need of subsidized family planning care and the number who received subsidized medical family planning services in fiscal year (FY) 1971; (b) identify the existing and potential resources for provision of family planning services; and (c) analyze the manpower utilization patterns of agencies which provide family planning services." The survey was conducted by the Guttmacher Institute in cooperation with the Council on Population of the American Public Health Association, the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, the American Hospital Association and the Association of State and Territorial Health Officers.</p>
                  </bioghist>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_f6044dd8d3b7d49c2aa5acc43470dbcf" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family planning-related articles and reviews (including material by Joy G. Dryfoos)</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(4 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1976/1980" type="inclusive">1976-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_86b6f93f7caf78db0af6787ac3047e7c"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_5ed9c078022674652ad7616267dd1e59" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Planned Parenthood court documents and relevant state bills</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1978/1986" type="inclusive">1978-1986</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_c679788e9656aeb80de3532331556107"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_148345bfab1517813744b4a37d156023" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Guttmacher Title X background, memos, correspondence, and legal information</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1987/1991" type="inclusive">1987-1991</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_d6f28f07698e3073706f2ea75633a8c4"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073491]"
                                type="box">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_da0110f1976e9da29a315c251d97e263" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>NICHD (National Institute of Child Health and Human Development) family planning five-year plan evaluation and progress report</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_57dabeba08e0e60317f70fe9c4e4f0d2"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073509]"
                                type="box">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_68e0bc8ef461c163ed6f90f14037b8af" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>DHHS (Department of Health and Human Services) family planning five-year plan contract, progress reports, methods, statistics, data, and analysis</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(15 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1980/1982" type="inclusive">1980-1982</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_9d822b10662c46048e4edce57c8c0ce1"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073509]"
                                type="box">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_009df2f80b8d19faa6c021ea38054b2d" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>DHEW (Department of Health, Education, and Welfare) family planning five-year plan contracts, progress reports, relevant literature, technical proposals, and correspondence</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(7 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1976/1980" type="inclusive">1976-1980</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_e9f8c645deac935bb28d3d2ecb666672"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073509]"
                                type="box">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
               <c03 id="aspace_c3b26dba0d6e535afde7b70d14aaf9e5" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>NCHS (National Center for Health Statistics) five-year plan proposal and budget</unittitle>
                     <physdesc altrender="whole">
                        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 folders</extent>
                        <extent altrender="carrier">(2 folders)</extent>
                     </physdesc>
                     <unitdate normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate>
                     <container altrender="Record carton"
                                id="aspace_0a79c86cc87f553cb920058fd795eda2"
                                label="Mixed Materials [310183630073509]"
                                type="box">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c03>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_7380df09ab8853f3581afa32d34ee01d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Original inventory sheets</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Record carton"
                             id="aspace_414f8b58dd68eb1f57cfefbac6555a87"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630073459]"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
