<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">mnsss602</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Mary Daly papers <num>SSC.MS.00637</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>July 2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-01-02 16:15:30 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-07-02</date>
            <item>Description updated with accurate restriction info, updated to DACS minimum standards; finding aid published.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Mary Daly papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Daly, Mary, 1928-2010</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00637</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">108.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(90 boxes. Other materials in the collection: Posters, and art work for book jackets; framed poem.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1928/2010"
                   type="inclusive">1928-2010</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_343c6db928645410285afc039e994b23">Mary Daly (1928-2010) was a radical feminist theologian, author, lecturer, and professor of religious and women's studies. This collection includes records of her personal and professional life. While the colleciton is mostly open for research, it currently has not been processed, in the sense that the materials have not been appraised for archival value, and archival arrangement and description beyond creating minimal box lists has not been done.</abstract>
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_f2262c14e794bcc97a8e0b6b6e4aecff">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Mary Daly started donating her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2009. This collection is comprised of six separate accessions received from Daly and her estate in 2009-2010, and one received in 2012: 09S-13, 09S-72, 10S-17, 10S-32, 10S-48, 10S-81, 12S-38.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_b3cd52438a14c62fd1ebd49af376e026">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Mary Daly, a radical feminist theologian who referred to herself as a Positively Revolting Hag, was born in Schnectady, New York, in 1928, the only child of a homemaker mother  and a traveling salesman father. She was raised Catholic and attended Catholic schools. Early in her childhood, Daly had mystical experiences in which she felt the presence of divinity in nature. </p>
         <p>She received a BA in English from the College of St. Rose in Albany, NY in 1950; an MA from Catholic University of America in 1952; and a Ph.D. in Religion from the School of Sacred Theology, St. Mary's, Notre Dame, in 1954. Unable to find a school in America that would allow a woman to obtain a"canonical" Doctorate in Sacred Theology, she went to Fribourg, Switzerland, where the education was state-controlled and could not legally exclude women. There she received a Doctorate in Theology and a Ph.D. in Philosophy as well as a Licentiate in Sacred Theology. </p>
         <p>When she returned to the United States in 1966, she took a tenure track position at Boston College. Her first book, <title render="italic">The Church and the Second Sex</title> (1968) was influenced by a visit to Rome during Vatican II. The book, called a"searing expose of Christian misogyny, especially in the Catholic Church," critiqued the patriarchal structure of the Catholic Church and its detrimental effect on shaping women's lives and self-image. The book established Daly as a radical feminist theologian and a powerful voice of dissension, and Boston College fired her soon after its publication. However, amidst student protests and public outcry, Daly was reinstated and given tenure. </p>
         <p>She went on to teach at Boston College for thirty-three years and published seven more books: <title render="italic">Gyn/Ecology: The Metaethics of Radical Feminism</title> (1978), <title render="italic">Pure Lust: Elemental Feminist Philosophy</title> (1984), <title render="italic">Beyond God the Father</title> (1985), <title render="italic">Webster's First New Intergaliactic Wickedary of the English Language</title> (with Jane Caputi;1987), <title render="italic">Outercourse</title> (1992), <title render="italic">Quintessence</title> (1998), and <title render="italic">Amazon Grace</title> (2006).</p>
         <p>Daly regularly toured nationally and internationally, lecturing, speaking and teaching at over three hundred college and universities. In addition to her own work, Daly was connected to many other feminist scholars, theologians and radicals of her day including Adrienne Rich, Diana Davies, Andrea Dworkin, Artemis March, Sonia Johnson, Jane Caputi, Merlin Stone, Janice Raymond, Robin Morgan, Julia Penelope, Gloria Steinem, Roseanne Barr, Pauli Murray, Linda Barufaldi, and Emily Culpepper. Daly retired from Boston College in 1999, although she claimed she was forced to do so. She died in Gardner, Massachusetts in January 2010.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_af1233780eab708029a198940be95170">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Most of this collection is open for research, with the following exceptions and caveats:</p>
         <p>Portions of the collection are resticted due to containing student information. Researchers may request access to materials in boxes identified as containing restricted student information, and they will be reviewed in response to demand. Boxes 18, 55, and 78 have been reviewed by this process and are currently available to research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ef9ca6220fd60e7c9cbf00f7cc28daa3">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Mary Daly papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00637, Smith College Special Collection, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_ffa156d442d20ff0c3fd463a7a38fce2">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Mary Daly. It includes correspondence, including fan mail; drafts and galleys of many of Daly's books; financial information; research files and subject files (on topics including students, colleagues and public figures); documents pertaining to legal disputes with Boston College in 1969 and 1999; personal files re: health, pets, automotive, investments, medical, etc.; books; and teaching materials, including course outlines, syllabi, and confidential student records.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <processinfo id="aspace_13069e9714420eac9d4a78de9d58336e">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>This collection has not been processed, in the sense that the materials have not been substantially appraised for long-term value, and archival arrangement and description beyond creating minimal box lists has not been done. The arrangement and description of materials may change in the future as iterative processing occurs. Researchers are encouraged to document their citations with this in mind.</p>
         <p>Boxes which have been identified as containing restricted student records will be processed on demand as requested by researchers who wish to access other materials currently housed in the same boxes.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_7b675893b236e7c2ac3f382e68a356c2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owned copyright, Mary Daly assigned the copyright in her works donated to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. </p>
         <p>For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Mary Daly, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_6374c7e8ca67dc74e26b3d2df687e337">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Container lists created at the time of accessioning are available upon request. Please contact Smith College Special Collections for copies of these lists.</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <appraisal id="aspace_255340ae21757b66ec3efa5d6bc6570e">
         <head>Appraisal</head>
         <p>Confidential student records as defined by FERPA have been removed from the collection and destroyed as they are found during on-demand reviews. To date, four folders of this type of material have been destroyed.</p>  
      </appraisal>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Catholic Church -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Catholic women -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminism -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminist spirituality -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminist theology -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminists -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Goddess religion -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian activists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian feminism -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians -- Massachusetts -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Religions -- Study and teaching -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Spirituality -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Universities and colleges -- Massachusetts -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women authors, American -- 20th century -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women college teachers -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women radicals -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh85147562" source="lcsh">Women in Christianity</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women in the Catholic Church -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's rights -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's studies -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women and religion -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Boston College -- Faculty</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Rich, Adrienne</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Caputo, Jane</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Davies, Diana</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dworkin, Andrea, 1946-2005</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Johnson, Sonia</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Morgan, Robin</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Stone, Merlin</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Contracts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Fliers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Galley proofs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Hearings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Mailing lists</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Manuscripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Medical records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newsletters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newspapers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Periodicals</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publicity</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Scripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">syllabi</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
