<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss560</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Black Women's Health Imperative records <num>SSC.MS.00487</num>
            </titleproper>
            <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-04-15 11:37:50 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:22-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-02-21</date>
            <item>Legacy record was updated to include recent accessions</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Black Women's Health Imperative records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname authfilenumber="people_4760" source="local_inmagic-people">Black Women's Health Imperative</corpname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00487</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(11 record cartons)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1983/2016" type="bulk">1983-2016</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_1edd260495473238d54dd50e5a401306">Women of color, reproductive rights, and women's health advocacy organization. The records consist of materials pertaining to the administration and the public outreach work of the BWHI, including board of directors files reports, correspondence, conference materials, photograph albums, memorabilia, and audiovisual materials. There is a large amount of promotional and educational materials produced by BWNHP including pamphlets, posters, brochures, fact sheets, newsletters, self-help manuals, and videos. There is also a small amount of material pertaining to Byllye Avery as founder of BWHI. [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_467a775ce11834f108d70a73a69df2b1">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accruals id="aspace_e52f408ed2932066fd7b332ec0d2e8c3">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records. Accession numbers: 03S-45, 05S-44, 09S-83, 15S-87, 2018-S-0033. Accessions were received on the following dates: 2003-06-27, 2005-08-15, 2009-07-21, 2015-10-20, 2015-11-19, 2018-05-11.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Black Women's Health Imperative began donating their records to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2003. Periodic additions to the collection are expected.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <altformavail id="aspace_admin-altform">
         <head>Additional Formats</head>
         <p>Original video recordings have been copied to digital files for research use. Playlist available online: http://www.smith.edu/libraries/libs/ssc/audiovisuals.html.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Black Women's Health Imperative, originally called the Black Women's Health Project (BWHP), then the National Black Women's Health Project (NBWHP), was established by Byllye Avery in 1981 as a program of the National Women's Health Network in Atlanta, GA. At the first National Conference on Black Women's Health Issues, held at Spelman College in 1983, the BWHP became an independent national organization. Its purpose was to develop and disseminate self-help methodologies, including "group psychosocial therapy techniques..to empower Black women to attain healthy living and overall physical, mental and spiritual wellness." In 1984, having been incorporated and renamed the National Black Women's Health Project, the organization purchased a national headquarters in Atlanta, affectionately known as The Mother House. One of the NBWHP's first initiatives was to begin holding quarterly task force meetings to gather information about and to develop a cohesive perspective on black women's health issues. Another primary facet of the organization's work has consistently involved networking and collaborating with black women in other countries on health issues (Africa, South America, the West Indies, as well as the United Nations Fourth World Conference on Women in Beijing, China and the Beijing + 5 NGO Host Committee). The organization has produced and published numerous films, videotapes and books pertaining to Black women's health issues.</p>
         <p> Key projects, some of them ongoing, include implementation and promotion of a national fitness program, Walking for Wellness (1992); the Domestic Violence Initiative (1995); development and implementation of substance abuse education and prevention programs on eight "historically black" college and university campuses (1996); REACH 2010, a study of intervention strategies to reduce cardiovascular risk among Black church women in New Orleans, LA (2000); development of the Black Women's Wellness Study, a weight management pilot program undertaken in partnership with the University of Pennsylvania (2001); <title render="italic">Because I am a Queen</title>, a national television campaign and online smoking prevention and cessation program directed to Black women (2002); and Take Your Loved One to the Doctor Day, a national multimedia campaign to promote gynecological visits, also directed specifically to Black women, undertaken in partnership with the USDHHS (2002). In 2003, the organization was instrumental in convening the National Colloquium on Black Women's Health, "to generate a national sense of urgency to address the unequal burden of health issues borne by Black women." In 2003, the organization changed its name to the Black Women's Health Imperative.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_51a38760e982e8aa4e88e8ee14f53e75">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>This online finding aid currently provides detailed description of only the most recent additions to this collection. Additional materials are described in unpublished lists that can be sent to you upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Black Women's Health Imperative Records, Sophia Smith Collection, MS 00487, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Accessioned by Burd Schlessinger, 2003</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_add-related">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Associated material can be found in the <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/sophiasmith/mnsss205_main.html">Loretta Ross Papers</extref>; the Byllye Avery Papers; and the <extref href="http://asteria.fivecolleges.edu/findaids/sophiasmith/mnsss291_main.html">Voices of Feminism Oral History Project</extref> (Loretta Ross and Toure).</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The records consist of materials pertaining to the administration and the public outreach work of the BWHI, including board of directors files reports, correspondence, conference materials, photograph albums, memorabilia, and audiovisual materials. There is a large amount of promotional and educational materials produced by BWNHP including pamphlets, posters, brochures, fact sheets, newsletters, self-help manuals, and videos. There is also a small amount of material pertaining to Byllye Avery as founder of BWHI.</p>
         <p> [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, BWHI has assigned the copyright in their unpublished works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by BWHI, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women -- Health and hygiene -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women -- Medical care -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women -- Mental health</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women -- Social conditions -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women health reformers -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Health care reform -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Health education of women -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Public health -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Reproductive health -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Reproductive rights -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women -- Health and hygiene -- Africa -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women -- Health and hygiene -- Social aspects -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women's health services -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Avery, Byllye, 1937-</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">National Black Women's Health Project</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Black Women's Health Imperative</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Brochures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Pamphlets</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Posters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publications</genreform>
    
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4058"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Avery, Byllye</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Goler Blount, Linda</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Goler Blount, Linda</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_461c2f0308c1ce3ca2be8ab56d21bae4" level="item">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Index Us: What Healthy Black Women Can Teach Us About Health</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-S-0033</unitid>
               <origination label="source">
                  <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Goler Blount, Linda</persname>
               </origination>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.01 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(1 folder)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
               <container altrender="Record carton"
                          id="aspace_8e6764d594edecedfffff15f61e047ed"
                          label="Mixed Materials"
                          type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_260e9fed16f834ba370a28d1f8a56d41">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>From "About IndexUS": "The first health index focused exclusively on healthy Black women.  It's based on 20 years of data from the Boston University Black Women's Health Study (BWHS), specifically, information from 38,706 BWHS participants who reported their health as excellent or very good.In 2013, when they responded to questions about their health, the average age of women in this study was 55."</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <acqinfo id="aspace_6eb0b350a5dbc43d75a2f234740d5a76">
               <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
               <p>Donated by Linda Goler Blount</p>
            </acqinfo>
            <controlaccess>
               <persname encodinganalog="600" role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Goler Blount, Linda</persname>
            </controlaccess>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
