<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00361</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid for Saint Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section records <num>SSC.MS.00631</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019-01-02</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-01-03 08:29:50 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-01-02</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Saint Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="local">Saint Joans International Alliance, U.S. Section</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00631</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(25 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1963/2014"
                   type="inclusive">1963-2014</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_96c975de324ca3a3a84b776419e26192">The St Joan's International Alliance was established in England in 1911 as the Catholic Women's Suffrage Society, to encourage support within the Catholic Church for woman suffrage. Once women's suffrage was attained in Great Britain in 1918, the organization gradually broadened its role to include other social issues affecting women, eventually including abolition of child and forced marriage; slavery traffic; the political rights of women; equal access to education, vocational training, and economic opportunities; family law and elimination of discrimination against women. In the church, the Alliance has petitioned for revision of the marriage liturgy, revision of the canons of the code that adversely affect women, and admission of women to the diaconate and priesthood. Materials in these records includeaterials include correspondence, meeting minutes, reports, conference materials, membership files, publicity materials, audio recordings, articles, clippings, books, pamphlets and memorabilia.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_79136dfb02d10b30eaf56fe670081ce7">English, French, Italian, German</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_679c93c3080ce2523ae9059148c3c7c2">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Gabrielle Jeffery and May Kendall founded the St Joan's International Alliance in England in 1911. Its initial name was the Catholic Women's Suffrage Society. Their goal was to create an organization which would encourage support for woman suffrage within the Catholic Church. Men were encouraged to join but could not hold posts in the group. The organization soon established international relations and had members in twenty-four countries from five continents. Once women's suffrage was attained in Great Britain in 1918, the organization gradually broadened its role to consider other social issues affecting women. In 1923 it was renamed the St. Joan's Social and Political Alliance. The name was changed again, in 1954, to the St Joan's International Alliance. After the Second World War, the organization's areas of interest expanded further to include abolition of child and forced marriage, slavery traffic, and traffic in persons; the political rights of women; equal access to education, vocational training, and economic opportunities; family law and elimination of discrimination against women. Since 1952 it has been recognized as an official consultative body by the UN, UNESCO and the World Labour Organisation. In the church, the Alliance has petitioned for revision of the marriage liturgy, revision of the canons of the code that adversely affect women, and admission of women to the diaconate and priesthood on the same terms and under the same conditions as men.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b96f4246413c09eb9aa888e21e3b3704">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The St Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section records document the organization's early efforts to encourage support for woman suffrage within the Catholic Church and later to promote ordination of women priests and broader social issues affecting women in the Church and society. The records also document the work of the SJIA the United Nations section in promoting women's rights at the international level including such causes as the abolition of child and forced marriage and slavery traffic; political rights of women; equal access to education and economic opportunities; and family law. Types of materials include correspondence, meeting minutes, reports, conference Tmaterials, membership files, publicity materials, audio recordings, articles, clippings, books, pamphlets and memorabilia.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a5dbc31c147fba7a3196acd008f264cf">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>With the exception of Box 6, this collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections. Collection is stored offsite; researchers must give 48 hours advance notice. Box 6 is closed and quarentined due to serious preservation issues.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ed569fe3a84a7e41571cb2327ced60ad">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>C. Virginia Finn, St. Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <phystech id="aspace_11fa4023a33e94fc4eec4497db00494e">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <prefercite id="aspace_dd099827268fbb8328710c528a6c7896">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Saint Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section records, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00631, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <userestrict id="aspace_ba29aa8bf6fde3ac22da7d3924cde037">
         <head>Donor and acquisition-related notes</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, C. Virginia Finn has assigned the copyright of Saint Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Saint Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.Donor requests that when something is quoted that acknowledgement be given to the author if designated in the records. Sometimes a member would ask that her name not be publiushed; in such an event please use initials only. Please credit St. Joan's International Alliance, U.S. Section as the source.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminism -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Ordination of women--Catholic Church</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Sexism -- Religious aspects</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women in the Catholic Church -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's rights -- Religious aspects -- Catholic Church</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women -- International cooperation -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's rights -- International cooperation -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Catholic Church -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">St. Joan's International Alliance. United Nations Section</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">St. Joan's Social and Political Alliance</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Agendas</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bylaws</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Directories</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Mailing lists</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Minutes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Brochures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newsletters</genreform>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local_inmagic-collection">St. Joan's International Alliance. United States Section</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
