<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00478</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Ruth Backes papers <num>SSC.MS.00478</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-12 10:38:03 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-12</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Ruth Backes papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Backes, Ruth</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00478</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(4 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1964/2007"
                   type="inclusive">1964-2007</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8f6621a3c9066d722612ebc35927f7ac">This collection consists of Ruth Backes' journals, beginning in 1968 and continuing through 2002, documenting her life as a coordinator of mental health training, a mental health researcher, and a counseling psychologist at a private practice.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f84188635db7a59f7c90a7a526becf37">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4b22511aef0539ce96135df645b4bd10">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Smith Special Collections received the collection as a gift from Ruth Backes in 2003 and 2008.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_13b7b611d7ff8da17e82a4708c69ef62">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Ruth Dean Emerson (Backes) was born August 25, 1918 in Mount Vernon, New York, to Harriet Crofut and Robert Stewart Emerson. She earned her B.S. from New York University in 1939. She went on to work as Assistant Director of Health Education for the YWCA, first in Baltimore, MD (1939 to 1941) and then in New Haven, CT (1941 to 1944). From 1944 to 1946 she was Program Director for the USO Club in Corner Brook, Newfoundland, and from 1946 to 1948 worked for the YMCA in Wallingford, CT as Director of the Women and Girls Department. She married Frederick Tregonning Backes in 1948, with whom she had three children: Peter (1949; deceased), Jill (1951) and Kim (1951). From 1948 to 1964 Backes stayed home to raise her three children, all the while remaining actively involved in such community organizations as the YMCA (Board member for six years), the League of Women Voters, the Community Concert Association, the Wallingford Garden Club (Board member for four years), the Wallingford Mental Health Association, and the local PTA (President for two years). During this time she was also a columnist for the Wallingford Post. In 1964 Backes and her husband divorced. From 1964 to 1966, she was employed as Coordinator of Volunteer Services at the Undercliff Mental Health Center in Meriden, CT, and from 1966 to 1974 she was Coordinator of Education and Information at the Connecticiut Mental Health Center in New Haven. From 1975 to 1977, she was Coordinator of Training for the Berkshire County Department of Mental Health. She earned her M.Ed. in 1978 and her Ed.D. in 1985, both at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst. From 1977 to 1982 Backes served on the faculty of the Antioch Graduate School in Keene, NH. She has been a research associate at the Center for Research on Women at Wellesley College and at the Five College Women's Studies Research Center at Mount Holyoke College. From 1978 to 2003, Backes was in private practice in Amherst as a counseling psychologist; in 2003 she moved to Florida. Ruth Backes died in November 2009.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_f9f51ad2e67af4ffce24a193b574149b">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>All accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_20873806c1b8d125cc4a0d0a57883391">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Ruth Backes papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00478, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1e4638e88be376bd70260fad4c3a1f51">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Ruth Backes Papers at Mount Holyoke College - primarily research files re: Frances Perkins</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_2b6558c59713ea7c8e378b860b632927">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection consists of Backes' journals, beginning in 1968 and continuing through 2002; the years 1968 through 1976 are spotty and inconsistent, but beginning in 1976 she wrote almost daily. The entries are to some extent topical and many are self-reflective, as well. Most entries have been transcribed by Backes, but some are handwritten. There is also a small amount of correspondence.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_f624c61a495cd2bc6cd6350584401a1c">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Backes has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Backes, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Backes, Ruth, 1918-</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Divorced mothers--United States--History--20th century--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Psychologists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women psychologists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">diaries</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_3401"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Backes, Ruth</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_3401"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Backes, Ruth</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
