<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00523</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Kay Gardner papers <num>SSC.MS.00523</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-12-20 11:42:25 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-12-20</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Kay Gardner papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Gardner, Kay</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00523</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(10 boxes. Other materials in the collection: Flat File)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1941/2003"
                   type="inclusive">1941-2003</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_e215ee36a9f24c42edc92d02baf97777">Kay Louise Gardner was born on Long Island, New York. Gardner was committed to making and promoting women's music, and was a founding member of the feminist lesbian band, Lavender Jane (1972), and of Women With Wings, a sacred singing circle. She also founded and recorded works with the New England Women's Symphony, in addition to being a prolific composer and recording artist in her own right. Her papers include musical scores, vinyl phonograph discs, audiotapes, videocassettes by Gardner, phonograph albums featuring other women artists, teaching materials, photographs, correspondence, subject files, a small amount of biographical information, posters for Kay Gardner concerts, and artwork.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ebd2c472c4b9820fb1d39fe9bf155df9">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Kay Louise Gardner was born on Long Island, New York to Enez Melkom and Karl Albert Gardner. She had one brother, K. Winston Gardner. Prior to coming out as a lesbian, she was in a traditional marriage in which she had two daughters, Juliana Smith and Jenifer Wilson-Smith. Gardner studied music at the University of Michigan and at the State University of New York at Stoneybrook, where she earned a Master of Music (Performance) in 1972. In 1998, she was ordained as a priestess by the Fellowship of Isis in Ireland and, upon her return to the U.S., founded the Temple of the Feminine Divine and the Isium Musicum, a three-year ordination program. She gained the attention of Maine citizens in the 1980s when she filed suit against the Bangor Symphony for sex discrimination, based on having applied for the position of conductor and learning later (having not been hired) that a memo had circulated among the musicians asking how they would feel about playing under a woman conductor. Gardner was committed to making and promoting women's music, and was a founding member of the feminist lesbian band, Lavender Jane (1972), and of Women With Wings, a sacred singing circle. She also founded and recorded works with the New England Women's Symphony, in addition to being a prolific composer and recording artist in her own right. Gardner received numerous awards, including an honorary degree from the University of Maine. Her book, Sounding the Inner Landscape: Music as Medicine, was published in 1990. She died in 2002.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_66acffd182ef8c7194897b825ad72cf6">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6a5e28287726fb754d33804fb8a7dcb1">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Kay Gardner papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00523, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_31bdfbf56772eab20bab4d3e1c8c9529">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Josten Music Library</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_1390db9df63596a6a348f79d6bacf688">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Kay Gardner papers are comprised primarily of musical scores, vinyl phonograph discs, audiotapes, and videocassettes by Gardner, as well as phonograph albums featuring other women artists. The substantial collection of recordings of"women's music,"circa 1970s-80s includes such artists as Alix Dobkin, Chris Williamson, June Millington, Holly Near, Meg Christian, Linda Shear, Lavendar Jane, the Berkely Women's Music Collective, and others. Gardner's teaching materials, including slides, pertaining to music as a form of spirituality and its use as a therapeudic methodology are also included, as are photographs, correspondence, subject files, a small amount of biographical information, posters for Kay Gardner concerts, and artwork.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_ab303553b311efb50230dc04d61993a5">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Kay Gardner has stated that the copyright on "musician compositions" be retained by Kay's daughters, Juliana Smith and Jenifer Wilson Smith; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Kay Gardner, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Gardner's daughters, Juliana Smith and Jenifer Wilson Smith, have asked that people requesting copies of compositions for performance use secure permission from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ada50ffb1121864ce3cbb3879bab64f9">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Kay Grdner's papers were received from Colleen Fitzgerald on 2005-09-20. Additional accessions were received on 2005-07-17, 2005-09-01, 2006-02-09, 2012-04-04.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <phystech id="aspace_176c4de7ab21ab364fc930de3ceb6ddd">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Goddess religion--History--20th century--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian musicians--History--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians--Songs and music</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Music--Instruction and study--United States--History--20th century--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Music--Manuscripts--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Music therapy</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women musicians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women composers--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women priests--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's music--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gardner, K. (Kay)

</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">CD-Roms</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Music scores</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Phonograph records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Posters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Biographical notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gardner, Kay</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
