<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00135</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Helen Krich Chinoy papers <num>SSC.MS.00135</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-16 11:21:14 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Helen Krich Chinoy papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00135</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1975/1981"
                   type="inclusive">1975-1981</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_0fa74169fa557b3727950bd449a28a89">Helen Krich Chinoy, a long-time professor at Smith College, was a pioneer in theatre education and one of the leading theatre historians in the United States. In an academic career spanning nearly half a century, Chinoy was an inspirational teacher and chair of the Smith College Theatre Department as it moved into a modern new center for the performing arts. Her books, <title render="italic">Actors on Acting</title>, co-authored with her sister-in-law, the theatrical agent Toby Cole, and <title render="italic">Directors on Directing</title>, also with Cole remains in print nearly 50 years after they were first published. Together, these two volumes, which are widely read by theatre students and professionals, remain her most influential work.Much of Professor Chinoy's research was focused on the role of women in the arts, and led to the publication, in collaboration with Linda Walsh Jenkins, of <title render="italic">Women in the American Theatre</title> in 1981. Chinoy was married to Ely Chinoy, a distinguished sociologist at Smith College who died in 1975. She died in 2010 at the age of 87.This collection consists primarily of research files related to the book <title render="italic">Women in the American theatre: careers, images, movements : an illustrated anthology and sourcebook,</title> edited by Helen Kroch Chinoy and Linda Walsh Jenkins (1981).</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_73f8d71606133db06b6b075f0c2545f9">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Helen Krich Chinoy, a long-time professor at Smith College, was a pioneer in theatre education and one of the leading theatre historians in the United States. In an academic career spanning nearly half a century, Chinoy was an inspirational teacher and chair of the Smith College Theatre Department as it moved into a modern new center for the performing arts. She taught courses on theatre history, theories of acting and directing, Shakespearean production, and women in theatre. She was also a prolific writer and editor. Her first book, <title render="italic">Actors on Acting</title>, co-authored with her sister-in-law, the theatrical agent Toby Cole, was a widely acclaimed exploration of the craft of acting as told by the theatre's greatest practitioners in their own voices. It has been continually in print since 1949. She and Cole continued their collaboration with <title render="italic">Directors on Directing</title>, a book described by one reviewer as the guide to the"unknown theatre" of the director. It too remains in print nearly 50 years after it was first published. Together, these two volumes, which are widely read by theatre students and professionals, remain her most influential work.
 
 Much of Professor Chinoy's research was focused on the role of women in the arts, and led to the publication, in collaboration with Linda Walsh Jenkins, of <title render="italic">Women in the American Theatre</title> in 1981. An updated revised edition came out in 2005. The book, based on a series of original interviews and essays, explored the contributions of women to theatre in the United States."Her scholarly work championed those who changed the rules of theatre," recalled Professor Kiki Smith, a long-time colleague at the Smith College Theatre Department." She challenged some of those limits herself, whether by recognizing the contributions of women or stretching the boundaries of theatre to include topics and perspectives previously ignored." In her later years, Professor Chinoy's research focused on the Group Theatre, the pioneering theatrical troupe established in the 1930s by Harold Clurman, Cheryl Crawford, and Lee Strasberg. She conducted interviews with most of the key figures, collected original documents and other material, and authored several scholarly articles. She also served as academic adviser to the 1989 PBS Masterpiece Theatre documentary Broadway's Dreamers: The Legacy of the Group Theatre, produced by Joanne Woodward, and shared in the show's Emmy Award. She was at work on a book about the Group Theatre at the time she fell ill.
 
 Helen Krich Chinoy was married to Ely Chinoy, a distinguished sociologist at Smith College who died in 1975. They had two children: Claire Chinoy and Mike Chinoy.She died in 2010 at the age of 87.
 
 [from obituary by Marlene Wong for the American Society for Theatre Research listserv, 2010]</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_89ed04df9a524614b9e29e7e7a0c8fd8">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_8cbb2ca67ff2053497dee21dd2ad9ecb">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Helen Krich Chinoy papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00135, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_9ecd6aeee27c9e56c1eb78427d577dfd">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection consists primarily of research files related to the book <title render="italic">Women in the American theatre: careers, images, movements : an illustrated anthology and sourcebook,</title> edited by Helen Kroch Chinoy and Linda Walsh Jenkins (1981).</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_cf0a54f0bc1aede453cbc7c20eb08292">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Helen Chinoy has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Chinoy, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_21ba3041fa90917a4e1efb80eb6ecb06">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>This collection was donated by Helen Chinoy.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Chinoy Helen Krich</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh85047759" source="lcsh">Feminist theater</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh85147627" source="lcsh">Women in the theater</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women dramatists, American--20th century--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_1468"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Chinoy, Helen</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Chinoy, Helen Krich</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
