<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00473</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Howard Parad papers <num>SSC.MS.00473</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-17 09:01:13 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-05-16</date>
            <item>Updated legacy finding aid and published.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Howard Parad papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_3310" source="local_inmagic-people">Parad, Howard</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00473</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(11 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1915/2002"
                   type="inclusive">1915-2002</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_be630162f3f13fed7ee3e0ffdf57321b">Howard Parad is a Licensed Clinical Social Worker (LCSW) and served as Dean of the Smith College School for Social Work from 1956 to 1971. The collection contains materials pertaining to Parad's career as a practioner and teacher of clinical social work, including correspondence, syllabi, lecture notes and speeches, essays drafts and published articles, research data, and subject files.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ccd35973a5382cdaa12ea169f22fc720">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Howard Parad was born on March 17, 1923 in Boston, Mass to Harry and Matilda (Salzman) Parad. He earned an A.B. in in social science in 1943 from Harvard University (magna cum laude), a M.S.W in 1947 from the Boston University School of Social Work, and a D.S.W in 1967 from the Columbia University School of Social Work. He married Libbie Greenbaum in 1944; their three children are Harry, Jonathan and Sarah. </p>
         <p>As a Licensed Clinical Social Worker (LCSW), Parad's experience includes work in military psychiatric social work and public health, and extensive practice in child, family, couple, and adult psychotherapy. He was a caseworker for the Greater Boston Family Service Association from 1947 to 1954, and assistant program director of the Hecht Neighborhood House in Dorchester, Mass. from 1948 to 1949. He was a member of the Boston University faculty from 1950 to 1956, and served as Dean of the Smith College School for Social Work from 1956 to 1971. He was employed by the University of Southern California School of Social Work (1971-1988). He has served as consultant to many programs, including the California Department of Mental Health, the National Institute of Mental Health, the Veterans Administration, Kaiser Permanente, Cedars-Sinai, the U.S. Army Medical Corps, and the National Kidney Foundation.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1fb55e36ba04a7ef535d264b34e31055">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This is a process-on-demand collection. It must be screened by an archivist for third parties identified in case histories before being used by researchers. Please contact the archives a minimum of two weeks in advance of your visit for access.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a0c4a4d79ddbcaf1a59b87175e9bbfeb">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Howard Parad papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00473, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_96f37b6499b46c8ea1181fb7f031bc3c">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection contains materials pertaining to Parad's career as a practioner and teacher of clinical social work, including correspondence, syllabi, lecture notes and speeches, essays drafts and published articles, research data, and subject files. Primary areas of interest include crisis intervention and management, particularly the role of social work in emergency medical treatment and short-term care.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2131a4fbdccb1842d93177036768771f">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was donated by Howard J. Parad on 2002-11-08.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_65038ad4a8ab67aadf193ebcff732763">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that he owns copyright, Howard Parad has assigned the copyright in his works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Howard Parad, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Smith College. School for Social Work--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Social work education--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Social workers--United States--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Parad, Howard, 1923-</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Annual reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Biographical notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bulletins</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Brochures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">lecture notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">syllabi</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Essays</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Transcripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Oral histories</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Book</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Parad, Howard</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
