<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00404</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Dwight family papers <num>SSC.MS.00404</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-17 12:26:08 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Dwight Family papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00404</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(9 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1785/1940"
                   type="inclusive">1785-1940</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_77ab518b11af30b701a28c135ebece79">The Dwight Family was a prominent New England family. Elihu Dwight, born 1763, graduated from Dartmouth College in 1790 and married Lydia White (1777-1846) in 1801. He studied medicine with Dr. Ebenezer Hunt of Northampton, MA and practiced medicine in Northampton and South Hadley until he retired at age 70. He died June 1, 1854. Elihu and Lydia Dwight had seven children; their youngest, John, born in 1819, married Nancy Shaw Everett.
 Nancy Shaw Everett (1817-1892) was the adopted daughter of Metcalf Everett, a cousin of Edward Everett, the prominent American politician, pastor, educator, diplomat, and orator. Everett served as U.S. Representative, U.S. Senator, the 15th Governor of Massachusetts, Minister to Great Britain, and United States Secretary of State. She was a member of the first senior class of Mt. Holyoke Seminary. Following her graduation she became preceptress of a school in Woodstock CT in 1839. The Dwight Family papers contain correspondence, writings, printed material, and memorabilia. The bulk of the papers consist of correspondence (originals and typed copies) of Elihu Dwight M.D., his son John, John's wife Nancy Everett Dwight and John and Nancy's oldest son Rev. Melatiah Everett Dwight. Also included are excerpts from Elihu Dwight's medical diary, a report of a journey he made in 1789, business papers and accounts, and sermons and items related to Melatiah's ministry.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_6ed2559d8e1aa5a88e9be335526c25d4">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Elihu Dwight was born on October 22, 1763. He graduated from Dartmouth College in 1790 and married Lydia White (1777-1846) in 1801. He studied medicine with Dr. Ebenezer Hunt of Northampton (Mass.) and practiced medicine in Northampton and South Hadley (Mass.) until he retired at age 70. He died June 1, 1854. Elihu and Lydia Dwight had seven children, their youngest, John, born in 1819, married Nancy Shaw Everett.
 Nancy Shaw Everett was born June 17, 1817 in Foxboro, MA and was adopted at an early age by her uncle Melatiah Everett of Wrentham. Her father, Metcalf Everett was a cousin of Edward Everett, the prominent American politician. She was a member of the first senior class of Mt. Holyoke Seminary. Following her graduation she became preceptress of a school in Woodstock CT in 1839. She left that position to marry John Dwight in 1841 in Wrentham, MA. They had five children. She died on November 2, 1892, in New York City.
 John Dwight and his wife Nancy Shaw Everett Dwight moved to New York City in 1846 and he began the manufacture of bicarbonate of soda. He was head of the firm of John Dwight and Co. for 50 years and from 1896 was president of Church and Dwight Company.
 Melatiah Everett Dwight, the eldest son of Nancy Shaw Everett and John Dwight, was born October 15, 1841 in South Hadley. He was a Congregational minister, serving a church in Onarga, Illinois. He married musician Helen M. Kirby, of Jacksonville, ILL, in 1845. They had five children.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_87fb077f2ef57f364278714eb5dc29a2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_a0c27c5fe7e73d13d4ee45dd7111ef54">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Dwight Family papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00404, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_83a5eedeea313c9b653323f4708c45dd">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Originals of some letters at Mt. Holyoke. Civil War letters at Yale.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_6093933d6ddfff46c5e6306bf5e08b1f">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Dwight Family papers contain correspondence, writings, printed material, and memorabilia. The bulk of the papers consist of correspondence (originals and typed copies) of Elihu Dwight M.D., his son John, John's wife Nancy Everett Dwight and John and Nancy's oldest son Rev. Melatiah Everett Dwight. Also included are excerpts from Elihu Dwight's medical diary, a report of a journey he made in 1789, business papers and accounts, and sermons and items related to Melatiah's ministry.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_e8d0d0e492cfcf13709d1f012ee475e9">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that they own copyright, Louise B. Caldwell has assigned the copyright of Dwight Family works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by the Dwight Family, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_b335f13d16179fb083ebe2883f2eafb2">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was donated by Louise B. Caldwell.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dwight family</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dix, Dorothea Lynde, 1802-1887--Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Physicians--Northampton (Mass.)--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Clergy--Illinois--Onarga--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States--Social life and customs--18th century--Sources</geogname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Northampton, Mass--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">South Hadley, Mass--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Mount Holyoke College--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Family--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical care</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Women</geogname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Nurses--United States--History--19th century--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Ephemera</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Accounts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="lcsh">Business records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dwight Family</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
