<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00618</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz papers. <num>SSC.MS.00618</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-12-20 09:15:55 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-12-17</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_4536" source="local_inmagic-people">Horowitz, Helen Lefkowitz</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00618</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(25 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1908/2016"
                   type="inclusive">1908-2016</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_6231b53f984bdc2d77ac2e793538c79d">Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz is a professor emerita of History and American Studies at Smith College and a writer, whose research ranges over a number of areas: urban life, cultural philanthropy, women, higher education, biography, sexuality, sexual representation, censorship, intimate life, understandings of health and illness, understanding of the landscape, and tourism. Papers include writings by Horowitz, correspondence, and materials pertaining to published books, teaching, and professional engagements.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_00555ae8baf1e22edfdec1318a6f62f2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Closed during donor's lifetime unless donor grants permission for access. In case of incapacitation, Power of Attorney may grant permission.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_b0e02ce3bf1cc56e4540f398eb57ae3a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Collection is stored offsite; researchers must give 48 hours advance notice.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accruals id="aspace_781ac55faa64eb41ba98fb8af2116192">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic accruals to collection are expected.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ad61b2dce4d83a6ee6857ad91317e0ba">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Donated by Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_6f8ed35411945762abb90afe10987153">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz was born in Shreveport, Louisiana on Jan. 31, 1942, to David Lefkowitz, Jr. a rabbi at Temple B'nai Zion, Shreveport and Leona Atlas Lefkowitz, rebbetzin, tutor in math, informal college counselor, civic worker, community board member, and housewife. Helen received her B.A. from Wellesley College in 1963, and her American Studies Ph.D. from Harvard University in 1969. She continued learning at MIT, Union College, Scripps College, and the University of Southern California, where she taught before coming to Smith College, where she has been the Sydenham Clark Parsons Professor of History. Horowitz is the author of the following books: Culture and the City: Cultural Philanthropy in Chicago from the 1880s to 1917 (1976); Campus Life: Undergraduate Cultures from the End of the Eighteenth Century to the Present (1988); Alma Mater: Design and Experience in the Women's Colleges from Their Nineteenth-Century Beginnings to the 1930s (1993); The Power and Passion of M. Carey Thomas (1994); Rereading Sex: Battles Over Sexual Knowledge and Suppression in Nineteenth-Century America (a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize in History in 2003); and The Flash Press: Sporting Male Weeklies in 1840s New York (2008), co-authored with Patricia Cline Cohen and Timothy Gilfoyle. She was co-editor of Love Across the Color Line: The Letters of Alice Hanley to Channing Lewis (1996); and editor of Landscape in Sight: J.B. Jackson's America (1997), and Attitudes toward Sex in Antebellum America (2006). Horowitz enjoys working in a number of fields that connect her interest in American history with women's studies, landscape studies, architecture, education, biography, sexual representation, law, and medicine. She is married to fellow historian, Daniel Horowitz; the couple have two children, Benjamin and Sarah.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5959b709f826bf8a3969fa47fe81ae98">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00618, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_5bb1fbcdd4d18ee22e9bd83a95ff4d30">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz papers include writings by Horowitz, correspondence, and materials pertaining to published books, teaching, and professional engagements. Writings include proofs, drafts, and research materials for articles and books; high school, college, and graduate school essays; M.A. thesis and doctoral dissertation; and reviews of writings by others. Teaching materials include graduate student papers, teaching files, lecture notes and course packets, syllabi, and course notes. Other professional materials include correspondence; photographs; documents pertaining to speaking engagements, including drafts of lectures; most recent CV; and grant proposals and projects. Also included are VHS tapes of Helen Horowitz lectures, PBS History Detectives, Alumnae Achievements Dinner and Our Grandmother's Legacy by Scarlet Riley.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_0eb8f4b868d1e10d1c8090f4bd666df3">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Historians -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women historians -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Smith College -- Faculty -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Love across the color line : the letters of Alice Hanley to Channing Lewis / edited by Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz and Kathy Peiss.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Landscape in sight : looking at America / John Brinckerhoff Jackson ; edited by Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">The flash press : sporting male weeklies in 1840s New York / Patricia Cline Cohen, Timothy J. Gilfoyle, and Helen Lefkowitz Horowitz ; in association with the American Antiquarian Society.</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Contracts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Electronic mail</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Typescripts</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Horowitz, Helen Lefkowitz</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
