<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00567</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Theological Opportunities Program records <num>SSC.MS.00567</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-15 09:19:25 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-15</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Theological Opportunities Program records</unittitle>
         <origination label="source">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_4279" source="local_inmagic-people">Dodson Gray, Elizabeth</persname>
         </origination>
    
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00567</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(15 boxes. Other materials in the collection: two items loose on shelf)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1973/20011"
                   type="inclusive">1973-20011</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_a62d23504bbb15bc353177b57d79e545">The collection contains materials documenting the programs and administrative functions of the Theological Opportunities Program (TOP), a feminist lecture series started by Harvard Divinity School faculty for the general public.  Lecturers included faculty from other Harvard Schools, as well as lawyers, legislators, authors, journalists, environmentalists, psychologists and psychotherapists from the Greater Boston area.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a3e2f2d0efa58f829fc28f77c95f3da7">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections. Collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be somewhat difficult to use. AV materials may not be used until in-house use copies are made.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_eb8887b950196e353ece7df8c148af16">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Collection was recieved as a gift from Elizabeth Dodson Gray in 2007 and 2011.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_360f332ae76ab541869e9ab2cc86d465">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>The Theological Opportunities Program (TOP) began in the fall of 1973 as a Thursday morning fall and spring lecture series by Harvard Divinity School faculty for the general public, a public which turned out to be predominently women. Over the first decade the women doing the planning (and also those attending) became increasingly feminist, and so did the topics for the lectures and the format of the meetings. In the late 1970s and the 1980s, the series gradually increased in length to ten Thursdays in each series, and in the mid-1980s the sessions became half-day conferences with two or more speakers. In the early 1980s, faculty from other Harvard Schools began to be invited to speak, as well as lawyers, legislators, authors, journalists, environmentalists, psychologists and psychotherapists from the Greater Boston area. The organization has disengaged from Harvard and is ongoing.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_a009b28fd299dd9578fd3a04e143c232">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The collection has container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ff5b13daefdb60c666257b20df8adb2d">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Theological Opportunities Program records, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00567, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_426b9d0c2b4ac7637327bb4130713380">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Materials documenting the TOP programs and administrative functions, including correspondence and notes; information about speakers; financial information; schedules and fliers; artwork commemorating TOP milestones; sketches and drawings of TOP speakers and meetings by Sylvia Gilman, Ann Wiseman and Prill Hinckley; registration forms documenting who attended TOP events; transcripts in pamphlet form of TOP talks; and audiovisual recordings of TOP speakers and events. The book Sacred Dimensions of Women's Experience (1988), edited by Elizabeth Dodson Gray, TOP coordinator, is also included, as is a memoir written for her daughter by Marisue Blue (1995), and the book The Kids Book of Awesome Stuff by Charlene Brotman (2007).</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_3ad4a21053d190d6a1e47a85d0c865c0">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, TOP has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by TOP, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Ecofeminism--Religious aspects</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminism--Religious aspects</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminist spirituality--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminist theology--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Religions--Study and teaching--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women and religion</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women--Religious life</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gray, Elizabeth Dodson, 1929- (ed.). Sacred dimensions of women's experience--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gray, Elizabeth Dodson, 1929-</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Transcripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Book</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Programs</genreform>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local_inmagic-collection">Theological Opportunities Program</corpname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4279"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Dodson Gray, Elizabeth</persname>
    
  
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local_inmagic-collection">Theological Opportunities Program</corpname>
    
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="local_inmagic-collection">Theological Opportunities Program</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
