<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00717</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Forward Together records <num>SSC.MS.00717</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-03-14 16:07:44 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-03-13</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Forward Together records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="local_inmagic-collection">Forward Together</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00717</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(1 container, 3 posters)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1998/2013"
                   type="inclusive">1998-2013</unitdate>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_0a7ffaa8ce58fd5d18180d63fb1ac1ce">Spanish, Vietnamese, Chinese, Khmer</langmaterial>
         <abstract id="aspace_d5efb9f24d99be6652cb28316f00f746">Founded in 1989, Forward Together is a multi-racial organization dedicated to working for reproductive justice. The collection includes APIRH/ACRJ/Forward Together publications, VHS tape, and posters. Digital files include photographs, Board documents, staff information, staff planning and strategy session documents, Strong Families documents, Youth Organizing documents, and video footage.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accruals id="aspace_f3cb47c29221368c1f52d98f5dc91502">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic accruals to collection are expected.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2cb689348677f550ab32618426293421">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>According to their Web site, "Forward Together is a multi-racial organization that works with community leaders and organizations to transform culture and policy to catalyze social change. Our mission is to ensure that women, youth and families have the power and resources they need to reach their full potential. By developing strong leaders, building networks across communities, and implementing innovative campaigns, we are making our mission a reality." Founded in 1989 in the wake of the US Supreme Court's "Webster" decision as the Asian Pacific Islanders for Choice (APIC), the organization broadened its focus in 1992 to more than just abortion rights and became Asian and Pacific Islanders for Reproductive Health (APIRH). Based in Oakland, California, APIRH conducted a critical survey in 1993 of the API communities in San Francisco, Sacramento, and Los Angeles that provided evidence that these communities supported a woman's right to choose. These findings were contradictory to the commonly held belief regarding Asian Americans and abortion rights, thus the report gained APIRH national notice amongst pro-choice organizations. During the 1990s, APIRH initiated several programs, including The HOPE for Girls Project, as they also increased their focus on Southeast Asian women and girls and, within their community organizing, making explicit the connection between environmental justice and reproductive rights. In 2004, executive director (since 1999) Eveline Shen oversaw yet another metamorphis as APIRH became the Asian Communities for Reproductive Justice (ACRJ), reflecting a growing connection to the broader movement for reproductive justice groups organized by women of color. In recognition of their program Strong Familes, in 2013 ACRJ changed its name once again to Forward Together. While still working for reproductive justice, Forward Together is committed to other issues as well and to connecting "to other sectors based on our shared interest of ensuring that all families can thrive". [Source: http://forwardtogether.org]</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_57568c2197c95e61ad56b4f735756aaf">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access:
Researchers must sign access agreement before using materials relating to youth in program, agreeing not to identify individuals (handwritten on box list).</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <phystech id="aspace_8a5927984a04a46c67482764768e1e2f">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>
         <p>This collection contains materials received from the donor in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <userestrict id="aspace_6139989eedc92a6c05c1ac6d8d0866b9">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that they own copyright, Eveline Shen has assigned the copyright of Forward Together's works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Forward Together, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a01f4ad1a9451e6e6e0f0881b49c757e">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>APIRH/ACRJ/Forward Together publications, VHS tape, and posters. Digital files include photographs, Board documents, staff information, staff planning and strategy session documents, Strong Families documents, Youth Organizing documents, and video footage.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_7b112fd7154ce5c70b52d681d9c0a172">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Donated by Eveline Shen, Executive Director of Forward Together, 2013.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Asian American women -- Health and hygiene -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women -- Health and hygiene -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">California -- Social conditions</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gay rights -- united States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Latina women -- Health and hygiene -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Reproductive health -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Reproductive rights -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Youth -- Services for -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Shen, Eveline, 1968-</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newspapers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newsletters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Pamphlets</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610"
                   authfilenumber="people_5143"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Forward Together</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
