<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00624</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Nancy Boyd Webb papers <num>SSC.MS.00624</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-20 10:35:31 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-06-20</date>
            <item>Updated finding aid and published.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Nancy Boyd Webb papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Webb, Nancy Boyd, 1932-</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00624</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(9 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1981/2013"
                   type="inclusive">1981-2013</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_27d493cc8b5b229d1f994c45a03e5232">Nancy Boyd Webb is a clinical social worker and distinguished university professor emerita at Fordham University Graduate School of Social Service where she held the endowed James R. Dumpson Chair in Child Welfare Studies and where she founded, directed and taught in the Post-master's Certificate Program in Child and Adolescent Therapy for 22 years until her retirement in 2008. Her papers include conference and workshop materials, course notes, reports, and writings on child therapy, trauma, and bereavement.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2d65c087e4bfdef12327e7410d003649">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Nancy Boyd Webb is a clinical social worker and distinguished university professor emerita at Fordham University Graduate School of Social Service where she held the endowed James R. Dumpson Chair in Child Welfare Studies and where she founded, directed and taught in the Post-master's Certificate Program in Child and Adolescent Therapy for 22 years until her retirement in 2008. She earned her B.A. cum laude at Radcliffe College (1954), her M.S.S. at the Smith College School for Social Work (1956), and her D.S.W. at the Columbia University School of Social Work (1977). In her retirement, Webb continues to offer three categories of professional services: keynote presentations and conference workshops; education and staff training; and consultation and individual and group supervision. She is a prolific author and scholar in the areas of child therapy, trauma, and bereavement, and has published 13 books on these topics since 1991. She has received numerous honors, including Smith College's Day-Garrett Award, the Clinical Practice Award of the Association for Death Education and Counseling, and the designation of Distinguished Scholar by the National Academies of Practice in Social Work. In addition to teaching and writing, Dr. Webb consults with agencies and schools on the topics of child trauma and bereavement.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_aa126557fda9b69bf191a31890952f98">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection must be screened by an archivist for case histories identifying third parties before being used by researchers. Please contact the archives a minimum of two weeks in advance of your visit for access.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_866feb6189206d837f3e9cd2d3c69530">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Nancy Boyd Webb papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00624, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f12217c9dfe670ce3de84bda570e48e8">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Papers include conference and workshop materials, course notes, reports, and writings on child therapy, trauma, and bereavement.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_bd6a5cbff04daa4b1f5213dedc1e8716">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Nancy Boyd Webb has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Nancy Boyd Webb, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_c65e42d36c7a0098bf4ff18ae361718b">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Nancy Boyd Webb donated her papers on 2008-07-25.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Child psychology--Study and teaching--History--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Fliers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300248280" source="aat">Brochures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300048715" source="aat">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300028051" source="aat">Books</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Webb, Nancy Boyd, 1932-</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
