<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00299</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow collection of research materials on Olive Schreiner <num>SSC.MS.00299</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-16 15:12:23 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-05-16</date>
            <item>Updated legacy finding aid and published.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow collection of research materials on Olive Schreiner</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_981"
                      role="res"
                      source="local_inmagic-people">Tetlow, Elizabeth McGinnis</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00299</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(2 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1874/1981"
                   type="inclusive">1874-1981</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_4131ee4aa5930fc66d210e8bbe65ad01">Born on the Cape of Good Hope, South Africa, Olive Schreiner was a writer in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. This collection consists primarily of research materials on Schreiner gathered by Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow for a proposed biography.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_469c0664e31272dd27caa0764660e933">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Olive Schreiner was born on the Cape of Good Hope, South Africa in 1855, the ninth of eleven children born to missionaries Rebecca Lyndall and Gottlob Schreiner. Schreiner moved frequently with her family and received no formal education but she was intensely curious, read widely and, on her own, became a "free-thinker." From the ages of 14 to 26 she worked as a governess for various European families in Africa. In 1881 she went to England intending to study medicine at the Royal Infirmary but after a short stay there she gave up on medicine and decided to be a writer instead. </p>
         <p>She published <title render="italic">Story of an African Farm</title> in 1884, which became a best-seller, and formed important relationships with people such as Edith Nesbit, Eleanor Marx, and Havelock Ellis. Schreiner returned to South Africa in 1889 and, after suffering from bad health and writer's block, she published <title render="italic">Dreams</title> (1891), <title render="italic">Dream Life and Real Life</title> (1893), and the polemical, pro-Boer <title render="italic">Trooper Peter Halket of Mashonland</title> (1897). </p>
         <p>In 1894 she married Samuel Cronwright (who hyphenated his name with hers and became Samuel Cronwright-Schreiner) with whom she campaigned for suffrage, racial justice, and for the Boer cause. She was interred during the Boer War, during which she wrote <title render="italic">Women and Labor</title> (1911). She returned again to England in 1913 and was active in the peace movement. After her death in 1920, her husband published her novels <title render="italic">Undine</title> and <title render="italic">From Man to Man</title>.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_51d13a8cb62d46ddf0e3ede406a7eeb2">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow collection of research materials on Olive Schreiner, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00299, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a1734cbfaaacd08eef102d34af0118e3">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow collection of research materials on Olive Schreiner consist primarily of research materials gathered by Betty Tetlow for a proposed biography. In addition to Tetlow's own manuscript drafts and correspondence with writers such as Doris Lessing, Marilyn French, and other scholars and biographers of Schreiner, these papers include published articles about Schreiner; newspaper clippings; notes; transcriptions, photocopies, microfilms of Schreiner's letters from other repositories, and Schreiner's writings. Schreiner's significant correspondents include Eleanor Marx, Havelock Ellis, Karl Pearson, and H. Bryan Donkin. Major themes addressed by the collection include 19th century feminism, Victorian sexuality, 19th century English literary circles, South Africa, peace, 19th century medicine, and women writers.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_5648f8d08c8600ebb3bc06c3aa48223f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_44156277f70595eaf4bca2c3f9709a4d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that he owns copyright, Peter Raine has retained copyright in the works of Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow donated to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Elizabeth McGinnis Tetlow, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_caddd73c2374a60b54b35f38ebb5e67c">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lessing, Doris May, 1919- --Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">French, Marilyn, 1929- --Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Socialism--England--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Carpenter, Edward, 1844-1929</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Hinton, Howard, 1867-1948</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Pearson, Karl, 1857-1936--Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Schreiner, Olive, 1855-1920</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Stead, W.T. (William Thomas), 1849-1912</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Levy, Amy, 1861-1889</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Marx, Eleanor--Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939 --Correspondence</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">South African literature (English)--20th century</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bibliographies</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publications</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Schreiner, Olive</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
