<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00635</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Froma Walsh papers <num>SSC.MS.00635</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019-06-19</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-19 10:31:24 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-06-19</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Froma Walsh papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_4650" source="local_inmagic-people">Walsh, Froma</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00635</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(1 box. Other materials in the collection: Digital files on server.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1982/2004"
                   type="inclusive">1982-2004</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_fa8fbd6a4d13d616551008e31db4814d">Froma Walsh is the Mose and Sylvia Firestone Professor Emerita in the School of Social Service Administration and Department of Psychiatry, Pritzker School of Medicine at the University of Chicago. This collection includes Dr. Walsh's professional papers including her CV, and her books and articles relating to family therapy.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_e8ad9846b44a839927132126d288260f">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Froma Walsh received a BA with honors in Psychology at the University of California, Berkeley in 1964. After serving in the Peace Corps in Morocco, she earned an MSW at Smith College in 1970, with fieldwork in the Yale Department of Psychiatry and Yale Child Study Center. She received her PhD in Human Development at the University of Chicago in 1977. Dr. Walsh was on the faculty at Yale University Medical School; Michael Reese Medical Center; and Northwestern University Medical School, Department of Psychiatry and Family Institute, before joining the faculty of the University of Chicago, where she is the Mose and Sylvia Firestone Professor Emerita in the School of Social Service Administration and Department of Psychiatry, Pritzker School of Medicine. She is also Co-Director and Co-Founder of the Chicago Center for Family Health. Walsh is a leading expert on a family resilience practice approach in fostering recovery from crisis, trauma and loss; navigating disruptive life transitions; and mastering ongoing challenges with chronic, multi-stress conditions and widespread disasters. Areas of expertise also include: contemporary family diversity and challenges; and spirituality in clinical practice. She is a licensed clinical psychologist and an AAMFT approved supervisor, and past editor of the Journal of Marital and Family Therapy and past president of the American Family Therapy Academy (AFTA). She has received many honors and awards for her work, and is a frequent speaker for national and international conferences, and consults widely on resilience-oriented community mental health training and services.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4c96e3563baf8ca3c4e782fc309d4b37">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Froma Walsh papers, SSC-MS-00635, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_8b372f1ce1a095434ad9ee6c2385389c">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection is comprised of Dr. Walsh's professional papers including her CV, presentations and material related to her books and other writings.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_bb7c14be356648f0922d63b50e884a7d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_ca71e500eaed8903413f050eb965da51">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Froma Walsh has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Dr. Walsh, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_c4de4861069e74ab7c30918ccf137974">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>This collection was donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by Dr. Froma Walsh.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Family psychotherapy -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Family social work -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Social case work -- Study and teaching -- United States -- History</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Digital files on server</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300048715" source="aat">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300028051" source="aat">Books</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Walsh, Froma</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
