<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc000644</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Martha Ackelsberg papers <num>SSC.MS.00644</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-23 09:41:26 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Martha Ackelsberg papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Ackelsberg, Martha A.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00644</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(19 boxes. Other materials in the collection: flat file; digital file.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1929/2014"
                   type="inclusive">1929-2014</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8a03417ea760e1221eb7409b0cd36067">Martha Ackelsberg is the William R. Kenan Jr. Professor Emerita of Government and Professor Emerita of the Study of Women and Gender at Smith College. Born in 1946 in New York City to Socialist Zionist parents, Ackelsberg earned a bachelors degree in social studies from Radcliffe College, and a masters and doctorate degrees in political philosophy from Princeton. While at Princeton, she explored anarchist theories of justice in Godwin, Bakunin and Kropotkin, and her dissertation focused on anarchist theory and practice during the Spanish Civil War. In 1991 she published her book,<title render="italic">Free Women of Spain: Anarchism and the Struggle for the Emancipation of Women.</title>Ackelsberg was a political science professor at Smith College since 1972. She has written extensively on the topics of women's community activism, gender and public policy, feminist and democratic theory, and women in Jewish communities.This collection includes documentation of Ackelsberg's involvement in Northampton, Massachuesetts, affordable housing and sustainable development initiatives, including materials pertaining to the displacement and relocation of tenants living in Smith College-owned buildings, to make way for the new Ford Engineering Building. There are extensive materials relating to Ackelsberg's involvement in various Jewish activism organization and projects. Also included are transcriptions of interviews with and notes about members of the organization Mujeres Libres, mostly in Spanish, for her 1991 book.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_acbc303d22ba5b7d5535b252bac9cd3d">English, Spanish, French, Polish, Basque</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ea36077f1d511a130d933f15eebb7973">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Martha Ackelsberg is the William R. Kenan Jr. Professor Emerita of Government and Professor Emerita of the Study of Women and Gender at Smith College. Born in 1946 in New York City to Socialist Zionist parents, Ackelsberg earned a bachelors degree in social studies from Radcliffe College, and a masters and doctorate degrees in political philosophy from Princeton. While at Princeton, she explored anarchist theories of justice in Godwin, Bakunin and Kropotkin, and her dissertation focused on anarchist theory and practice during the Spanish Civil War. In 1991 she published her book,<title render="italic">Free Women of Spain: Anarchism and the Struggle for the Emancipation of Women.</title>Ackelsberg has been a political science professor at Smith College since 1972. She has written extensively on the topics of women's community activism, gender and public policy, feminist and democratic theory, and women in Jewish communities.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_331d953455e444e83cdb4b87f345235e">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection includes documentation of Ackelsberg's involvement in Northampton, Massachusettes' affordable housing and sustainable development initiatives, including materials pertaining to the displacement and relocation of tenants living in Smith College-owned buildings to make way for the new Ford Engineering Building. There are extensive materials relating to Ackelsberg's involvement in various Jewish activism organization and projects. Also included are transcriptions of interviews with and notes about members of the organization Mujeres Libres, mostly in Spanish, for her book,<title render="italic">Free Women of Spain: Anarchism and the Struggle for the Emancipation of Women.</title>(1991).There are also records of the Jewish feminist spirituality collective B'Not Esh, which Ackelsberg donated, some of which are closed to researchers.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_b5499dcc2fb0c576edc91cff5cb90493">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open with following restrictions on access: One document box (Box 11 in Acc.#14S-34) of personal correspondence is closed until 2064; one record carton (Box 10 in Acc.14S-35) containing records of the Jewish feminist spirituality collective B'Not Esh material, which were donated by Ackelsberg, are closed indefinitely.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_c5370ff46288333a324564812c1f68af">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Martha Ackelsberg papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00644, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_2bf5d34ddddff523bb5fb4968e1ada67">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Judith Plaskow papers, B'not Esh Records, Documenting Lesbian Lives student oral history project: http://www.smith.edu/library/libs/ssc/lives/lives-intro.html, Yiddish Book Center interview: http://archive.org/details/MarthaAckelsberg13september2011YiddishBookCenter</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <userestrict id="aspace_d96766889b15d54f8b6c9540a722de9b">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Martha Ackesberg has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Ackelsberg, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_9cb93ef74cdc3b0dd2457e4f07dce322">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>These papers were donated by Martha Ackelsberg between 2009 to 2016.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Anarchism -- Spain -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Housing policy -- Northampton (Mass.)</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Jewish women</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Northampton (Mass.) -- Social conditions</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women anarchists -- Spain -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smith College -- Faculty</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Agendas</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Minutes</genreform>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminists--United States---History--20th century--Sources</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Northampton (Mass.)--Politics and government</geogname>
    
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Jewish lesbians--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300048715" source="aat">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300027261" source="aat">Proposals</genreform>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" rules="rda" source="local_inmagic-collection">Mujeres Libres (Organization : Spain)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
