<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00572</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Isabel Miller papers <num>SSC.MS.00572</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-12-19 09:02:23 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-12-18</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Isabel Miller papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="naf">Miller, Isabel, 1924-</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00572</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">44 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(39 boxes. Other materials in the collection: Poster and photographs in flat file)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1937/2009"
                   type="inclusive">1937-2009</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_12e8ec8d636c262b69777f294f009b67">Alma Routsong (pseudonym Isabel Miller) was born in 1924 in Traverse City, Michigan, the daughter of a nurse and a police officer. She was the author of nine books, many concerning lesbian feminist themes. The collection includes diaries, correspondence, research and manuscript materials, astrological charts of women, books by Miller (some in foreign languages); books from Miller's library; photographs; transparencies of Miller's family, friends and travels; memorabilia; artwork; and articles, clippings and printed materials.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_8fac0501b3a1c3c2825dcbcc6242287f">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Alma Routsong (pseudonym Isabel Miller) was born in 1924 in Traverse City, Michigan, the daughter of a nurse and a police officer. She interrupted her college studies to join the WAVES. While serving in the armed forces she met Bruce Brodie, whom she married in 1947. She completed her undergraduate degree in 1949 having taken advantage, along with her husband, of the postwar GI Bill. Miller gave birth to four daughters (Natalie, Joyce, Charlotte, and Louise) before divorcing Brodie in 1962. She was the author of nine books, many concerning lesbian feminist themes: <title render="italic">Gradual Joy</title> (1953), <title render="italic">Round Shape</title> (1959), <title render="italic">A Place for Us</title> (1969), <title render="italic">Patience and Sarah</title> (1972, 1994), <title render="italic">Love of Good Women</title> (1986), <title render="italic">Side By Side</title> (1990), <title render="italic">Dooryard Full of Flowers</title> (1993), and <title render="italic">Laurel</title> (1996). Isabel joined the Gay Liberation movement in 1970 and was active in the lesbian communities of New York City and mid-Hudson Valley region of New York. She spent time at Kate Millett's Artist Colony and was an officer of the Daughters of Bilitis. She lived in Poughkeepsie New York with her partner Julie Weber. Isabel Miller died of ovarian cancer in 1996.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_906c0338a9478a1597ebc444766083a2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_9f46f79b55ef74b98194e1ce591052cc">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Isabel Miller papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00572, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b20a1013afaabeb4d9d1c0838901b8c3">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>The collections of "Birkby Babes", including Phyllis Birkby, Sidney Abbott, Dolores Alexander, Barbara Love, and Kate Millett's Artist Colony/The Farm.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_778eb12b65956f77606dc6dbed70fe2b">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Isabel Miller papers include diaries (beginning when she was in her early teens), correspondence offering rich documentation of her personal life, from her years as a member of WAVES during World War II and as wife and mother of four daughters in a traditional heterosexual marriage, to her coming out as a lesbian and her life thereafter. Research and manuscript materials document the evolution of her profession as an author of lesbian fiction, the best known of which is <title render="italic">Patience and Sarah</title>. The collection also offers a personal record of the lesbian communities of New York City and the mid-Hudson Valley region, from the 1960s to 90s and includes transcripts of a lesbian consciousness raising group, extensive personal correspondence, and documentation of Miller's spiritual interests, including her numerous astrological charts of women. Correspondents include Sidney Abbott, Dorothy Baker, Noel Phyllis Birkby, Barbara Love, Dolores Alexander, Joan Casamo, Linda Clarke, Kate Millett, Diane Stevenson, Mildred Stewart, and May Swenson. The collection also includes books by Miller (some in foreign languages); books from Miller's library; photographs; transparencies of Miller's family, friends and travels; memorabilia; artwork; and articles, clippings and printed materials.  A small amount of material generated by Miller's partner, Julie Weber, is also included.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_03ec2cf858836b532fbe04773bb62d13">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was received from Julie J. Weber on October 1, 2007. Other accessions were received:
Accession #07S-39 received on 2007-05-29
Accession #09S-33 received on 2009-04-17
Accession #09S-46 received on 2009-06-02</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c965b8c8674b0f0f95d29029ce878688">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Isabel Miller's four daughters own copyright of the published books <title render="italic">A Gradual Joy, Round Shape, Side by Side, A Dooryard Full of Flowers, and Laura</title>. Isabel Miller's daughters and her former partner, Elizabeth Deran, jointly own the literary rights to <title render="italic">Patience and Sarah</title> (originally <title render="italic">A Place for Us</title>) and <title render="italic">The Love of Good Women</title>. Copyright to the remainder of Isabel Miller's papers, published and unpublished, is the property of the Sophia Smith Collection. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Isabel Miller, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <phystech id="aspace_8b2b3a3e89d01e08f6e930c8e7a25a5d">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women authors, American--20th century--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminist spirituality--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian artists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian feminism--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian communities--New York (State)--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians--Fiction--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Baker, Dorothy, 1907-1968</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Birkby, Phyllis</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Abbott, Sidney</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Love, Barbara</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Millett, Kate</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Routsong, Alma, 1924-</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">diaries</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Manuscripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Posters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_1769"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Weber, Julie</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Miller, Isabel, 1924-</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
