<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00632</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Katherine Triantafillou papers <num>SSC.MS.00632</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-05-15 16:09:29 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-05-13</date>
            <item>Updated legacy finding aid and published.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Katherine Triantafillou papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_4617" source="local_inmagic-people">Triantafillou, Katherine</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00632</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">30 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(25 containers)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1955/2007"
                   type="inclusive">1955-2007</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_6e824483fa294a4e8eaed592220db4dd">Katherine Triantafillou was the first openly gay person to practice law privately in Massachusetts when she opened her doors in 1975. She continues to specialize in lesbian and gay issues, and offers legal council for victims of domestic violence and other disadvantaged citizens. Her papers contain biographical information, correspondence, photographs, AV material, syllabi and course packets from courses she taught at several Boston area law schools, documentation of cases she litigated, and materials documenting her involvement in the Massachusetts Lesbian and Gay Bar Association and the National Lesbian and Gay Bar Association.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_70b74a95a7cd96948f74c723a972e407">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Katherine Triantafillou was born 23 Sep 1950. She earned a B.S. from the University of Michigan in 1972, a law degree from Suffolk University in 1975, and a M.A. in Public Administration from the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University in 1999. In 1975, Triantafillou opened a general practice out of her apartment on Beacon Hill that included real estate, prenuptial agreements, co-parenting and co-habitation agreements, adoption, guardianship, small business matters, litigation, estate planning, family law, personal injury, criminal law, civil rights, and corporate law. She was the first openly gay person to practice law privately in Massachusetts; she specialized in lesbian and gay issues, and legal advocacy for victims of domestic violence and other disadvantaged citizens. From 1976 to 1980, Triantafillou provided legal counsel to Transition House Massachusetts, a shelter for battered women, helping to incorporate the organization and to obtain its tax-exempt status. In 1977, she designed and supervised the Transition House Legal Advocacy Program, which trained volunteers to give legal assistance to battered women. From 1990 to 1995, Triantafillou was adjunct professor of law at Suffolk University Law School (family law), Northeastern University Law School (sexual orientation and the law), Boston University (paralegal training programs), and the University of Massachusetts. From 1984 to 1990, she was a member of the Governor's State-Wide Anti-Crime Council and the Battered Women's Working Group. Triantafillou served on the city council of Cambridge, Massachusetts from 1994-1999; during her tenure as Councilor, she helped establish a Domestic Violence-Free Zone for the City of Cambridge; increased coordination among city departments in responding to violence against women; assessed services provided to victims of domestic violence; led efforts to maintain rent control; advocated for affordable housing; spurred full implementation of the Domestic Partnership Ordinance; supported the needle exchange program run by Cambridge Cares About AIDS and the City Hospital; led efforts to increase minority hiring in the City and to ensure availability of equal job opportunities to minorities, women, and Cambridge residents; and advocated for increased funding for services to children and to the elderly. Triantafillou wrote the domestic violence legislation known as the Abuse Prevention Act, and is also the author of <title render="italic">Do Your Own No-Fault Divorce</title>, <title render="italic">Have You Been Beaten By The Man You Live With?</title>, <title render="italic">Representing Non-Traditional Families</title>, <title render="italic">Legal Rights of Battered Women Handbook</title>, and <title render="italic">How To Use the Law</title>. She edited The Massachusetts Police Institute Training Manual on the Abuse Prevention Act, and has trained hundreds of police officers on the legal issues and rights of battered women. Triantafillou's groundbreaking case, Adoption of Tammy, established the right of unmarried couples to jointly adopt in Massachusetts. She is a founder and former co-chair of the National Lesbian and Gay Bar Association, and the Massachusetts Lesbian and Gay Bar Association. She lectures frequently in continuing legal education seminars through the Massachusetts Bar Association and the Massachusetts Continuing Legal Education Foundation.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_871b080d06c4f8face8f9d3053c0e841">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4686cb74db54e8be208d232c487fe95f">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Katherine Triantafillou papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00632, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a7ade588053ca09694eb669aac783a17">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Katherine Triantafillou papers contain biographical information, including school records and early writings; correspondence; photographs; documentation of her campaign for, and tenure as, City of Cambridge (Massachusetts) Councilor; tapes of the Cambridge Community TV show,"Cambridge Inside,"and related documents; audiotapes of the radio show"Closet Space", and related documents; Triantafillou's leading role in implementing the City of Cambridge's anti-domestic violence ordinance and other anti-discrimination legislation; syllabi and course packets from courses Triantafillou taught at several Boston area law schools; documentation of cases litigated by Triantafillou, including violence against homosexuals (Boston Firefighters), adoption by unmarried couples (Cooksey-Love), and employment discrimination against homosexuals (Madsen vs Christian Science Monitor); and her involvement in the Massachusetts Lesbian and Gay Bar Association and the National Lesbian and Gay Bar Association.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_a66ede43d9f4c1c0f7c3dd905ba2d1a3">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>This collection was donated by Katharine Triantafillou on 2008-11-03.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9d145cfaf7cb2efdfc4184722ac01f4a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Katherine Triantafillou has retained copyright in her works donated to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Katherine Triantafillou, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <phystech id="aspace_f2ea998f0663d9b6f5862160fd8c40f3">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Abused women -- Services for -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Cambridge (Mass.) -- Politics and government</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Divorce -- Law and legislation -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Family violence -- Law and legislation -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gay couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Homosexuality -- Law and legislation -- United States.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lawyers -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian feminism -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians -- Massachusetts -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Same-sex marriage -- Law and legislation -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Unmarried couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women in politics -- Massachusetts</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women lawyers -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Awards</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bills (Legislative records)</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Biographical notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Business cards</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Buttons</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bylaws</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Legal documents</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Legislative documents</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Manuals</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Membership applications</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Membership lists</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Memorandums</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newspapers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Plaques</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">press releases</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Speeches</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Trial proceedings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Triantafillou, Katherine</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
