<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00509</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Fran Worden Henry papers <num>SSC.MS.00509</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-12-21 09:54:55 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-12-21</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Fran Worden Henry papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00509</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(20 boxes. Other materials in the collection: Flat file)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1961/2017"
                   type="inclusive">1961-2017</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_e1c0f2b74db15f72f4d114fa38bd5bde">Fran Worden Henry became executive director of the first Massachusetts Governor's Commission on the Status of Women in 1973. Subsequently, she served as the director of the President's Citizens Advisory Committee for Women under Gerald Ford (1975-1976) and, later, the as Northeast conference coordinator for the President's International Women's Year Commission under Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter (1976-1978). She has written extensively on women in business and other topics. This collection includes personal papers, such as diaries and letters, professional writings and political and feminist memorabelia among other materials.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_d524f7d7a2694600396478cefdaae2f8">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Frances Worden Henry was born in St. Albans, NY to Dorothea Louise Ziegler, a legal secretary, and John Chadwick Worden, a carpenter and boat captain. Her siblings are brothers Don (b. 1943) and John (b. 1951), and a sister, BJ (b.1949). She began working at age 14 doing cleaning and babysitting and worked every summer and most school years doing clerical, factory, or retail jobs. She graduated from the New School for Social Research in 1971 and then began working for the Emergency Employment Act in Massachusetts, helping unemployed people find work. In 1973 she took on her first explicitly feminist position when she became executive director of the first Massachusetts Governor's Commission on the Status of Women. Subsequently, she became the director of the President's Citizens Advisory Committee for Women under Gerald Ford (1975-1976) and, later, the Northeast conference coordinator for the President's International Women's Year Commission under Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter (1976-1978).
 
 After working from 1978 to 1980 as the Director of Communications for Appropriate Technology International, a non-profit organization serving indigenous organizations in developing countries that operated out of Washington D.C., Henry returned to school, graduating from Harvard Business School in 1982 with a Masters in Business Administration. She has written about her experiences as a woman at Harvard Business School in her book <title render="italic">Toughing It Out at Harvard: The Making of a Woman MBA</title> (1983).
 
 For the first ten years post-business school Henry owned Management Consultants, a strategic planning consulting practice, and she served as a partner in Enterprise Associates, a marketing and financial services business that included clients such as the National Academy of Sciences and the Woods Hole Research Center. In 1992, however, she resumed her work as a professional feminist by starting the organization Stop It Now! which has pioneered the use of public health strategies to prevent child sexual abuse, reaching abusers and those who know them through media and community action campaigns. Henry left Stop It Now! voluntarily in 2004.
 
 In addition to her paid employment, Henry has also served on many boards of directors including the Association for the Treatment of Sexual Abusers and the Diana, Princess of Wales Memorial Fund (US).</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_de8dd3ac700d2d458ff3b2fe2e160f7e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>These papers are closed until Fran Henry's death; permission from Henry is required until then.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_07d57cc32d3dc2303966de78d137ede3">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Fran Worden Henry papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00509, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1d48c6113eea01703884cca19931f53b">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Stop It Now Records, Voices of Feminism Oral History Project, Susan Rubin papers on International Women's Year and subsequent conferences</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_f873853e8b7b4133d1b92641ad1d9569">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The papers include Fran Henry's writings on women in business and documents pertaining to organizations in which she was involved as a business management consultant. Personal papers document her life through extensive correspondence with family, friends, and her husband, Robert Henry; appointment books and a small amount of biographical information are also included. Political buttons pertaining to the Civil Rights and Women's Liberation movements offer a glimpse into the political climate surrounding those issues in the 1960s and 1970s. Drafts of an unpublished book by Fran Henry, and related materials, document her research on the sexual abuse of children. The papers also include a recording made at the 2017 40th reunion of the 1977 International Women's Year Conference.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_92ea216dd035e0133957e618ee08127e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Fran Henry has retained copyright until her death in her works donated to Smith College. After her death, copyright in these works will transfer to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Henry, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4ecbb8416d2593434abfd5dcbae9cdd1">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>With the exception of some posters, all materials were donated by Fran Worden Henry. Collection includes accessions 2010-S-0087 and 2011-S-0028.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Henry, Fran Worden</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Stop It Now! (Northampton, Mass.)</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Businesswomen--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminists--Massachusetts--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Child sexual abuse--Prevention--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">International Women's Year, 1975</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">International Women's Decade, 1976-85 -- Congresses</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Agendas</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Appointment books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Electronic records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Minutes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Posters</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publications</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Memorandums</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Typescripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
    
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
