<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00484</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Blanche Wiesen Cook papers <num>SSC.MS.00484</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019-06-20</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="https://libraries.smith.edu/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-06-24 10:13:23 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2019-06-20</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated to current standards and published</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Blanche Wiesen Cook papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Cook, Blanche Wiesen</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00484</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(7 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1933/2006"
                   type="inclusive">1933-2006</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_96e0fe3f8a8cdd70c5e7bd1af7ab4a28">Blanche Wiesen Cook is a scholar and widely published author. This collection includes materials pertaining to Cook's biography of Eleanor Roosevelt; to her professional activities in the field of women's history and women's studies, including audio and video recordings of her lectures, speeches, and television appearances; and a small amount of biographical information.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_028b9e363a1d8fd03a56acd678b89d5d">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Blanche Wiesen Cook, a scholar and widely published author, received her B.A. from Hunter College in 1962, and her M.A. and Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins in 1964 and 1970, respectively. She has taught history at the John Jay College of Criminal Justice since 1968. Cook is active in numerous professional organizations and is the author of several books, including <title render="italic">Crystal Eastman on Women and Revolution</title> (1978), <title render="italic">The Declassified Eisenhower: A Divided Legacy for Peace</title> (1984), and <title render="italic">Eleanor Roosevelt: A Biography</title> (1992). She has published widely in scholarly journals. Cook is a founding member and officer of the Peace History Society. She lives in New York City with her partner Clare Coss.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8450ea2ddd9e596c40dbcbbe6e7d62ae">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>With the exception of the AV materials, this collection must be screened by an archivist for restricted material before being used by researchers. Please contact the archives a minimum of two weeks in advance of your visit for access.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_c12862c7dbc3bb0221f25c8155f50c3c">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Blanche Wiesen Cook papers, SSC-MS-00484, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b332741f3777d81d3e87382bf7b4ee1e">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Interview in Living U.S. Women's History (Oral History Project), Clare Coss papers, papers related to Peace History Society at Swarthmore College peace collection</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_d6f980c6dfba582109e2566773b97aa8">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Blanche Wiesen Cook papers include materials pertaining to Cook's biography of Eleanor Roosevelt; to her professional activities in the field of women's history and women's studies, including audio and video recordings of her lectures, speeches, and television appearances; and a small amount of biographical information.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_16c76f01f0708f83a263dbf4a4589c06">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>These papers were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by Blanche Wiesen Cook.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1579f1caa52acbf3dab4a8f8ecfdedd9">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright of her works, Blanch Wiesen Cook has retained copyright of her unpublished works until her death in her works donated to Smith College. After her death copyright in these works will transfer to Smith College. Copyright in published works will remain with her heirs. Other materials in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Wiesen Cook, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">College teachers--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian feminism--United States--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women historians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Biographical sketches</genreform>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminists-United States-Biography-Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">correspondence</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_1484"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Cook, Clare Coss and Blanche Wiesen</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
