<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00651</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Marietta Pritchard papers <num>SSC.MS.00651</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2019</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-02-15 14:25:38 -0500</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Marietta Pritchard papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00651</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1973/2009"
                   type="inclusive">1973-2009</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_684e1490425a2ba2c71ee1f274bd506b">Marietta Pritchard is a writer, editor and activist in Massachusetts. She was born in Budapest, Hungary to Eva Furth Perl and George Perl. The family immigrated to the U.S. in 1939 and settled in Scarsdale, New York. Pritchard graduated from Scarsdale High School in 1954, and received her B.A. from Radcliffe College in 1958; she went on to earn a M.Ed. from the University of Massachusetts in 1973. She has been married to Amherst College professor William Pritchard since 1957; the couple has three sons. From 1964 to 1976, Pritchard taught in public and private schools. From 1970 to 1977 she was a member of Amherst Town Meeting, and she has volunteered in ESL and GED programs and at the Hospice of the Fisher Home in Amherst. From 1977 to 1989, Pritchard was features editor at the Daily Hampshire Gazette in Northampton, MA; from 1989 to 1990, she was senior editor of New England Magazine; and since 1989 she has worked as a freelance writer and editor for publications, organizations and individuals.These papers include materials pertaining to Pritchard's unpublished book about the Amherst Women's Liberation support group, which started in 1969. Included is the complete typescript, entitled <title render="italic">"Life Support: A Women's Group Four Decades Later"</title>; questionnaires; interviews with former members (audio recordings and transcripts); correspondence; and notes.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_94695dedd027c60818f2791d67419664">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: Interview tapes, transcripts, and related papers are closed until Jan 1, 2029 (Accn 09S-78, boxes 1&amp;2); Original AV and born-digital materials may not be used; research use copies must be made.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accruals id="aspace_29ad55aa4add3ac38b7ba16d4d1075b0">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records. Accession numbers: 09S-78. Accessions were received on the following dates: 2009-09-24.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <bioghist id="aspace_fc1e3003b4628de2b36dd44d5b95f6a5">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Marietta Pritchard is a writer, editor and activist in Massachusetts. She was born in Budapest, Hungary to Eva Furth Perl and George Perl. The family immigrated to the U.S. in 1939 and settled in Scarsdale, New York. Pritchard graduated from Scarsdale High School in 1954, and received her B.A. from Radcliffe College in 1958; she went on to earn a M.Ed. from the University of Massachusetts in 1973. She has been married to Amherst College professor William Pritchard since 1957; the couple has three sons. From 1964 to 1976, Pritchard taught in public and private schools. From 1970 to 1977 she was a member of Amherst Town Meeting, and she has volunteered in ESL and GED programs and at the Hospice of the Fisher Home in Amherst. From 1977 to 1989, Pritchard was features editor at the Daily Hampshire Gazette in Northampton, MA; from 1989 to 1990, she was senior editor of New England Magazine; and since 1989 she has worked as a freelance writer and editor for publications, organizations and individuals.
 
 The Amherst Women's Liberation (AWL) support group, the subject of her unpublished book, formed in 1969. By 1970 it had grown to one hundred members, meeting weekly in support groups and a large monthly forum in a church. Study groups on abortion and birth control, archves, continuing education, and welfare were formed. In December 1970, AWL opened the Valley Women's Center (VWC) with action groups, a newsletter, speaker's bureau, staff group, free personal counseling, and welfare advocacy and counseling.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_651786c1251bf311b1ac05ebd461ea98">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Marietta Pritchard papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00651, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_e4fbb548868ed5298ec06d214cce7674">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>These papers contain materials pertaining to Pritchard's unpublished book about the Amherst Women's Liberation support group, which started in 1969. Included is the complete typescript, entitled <title render="italic">"Life Support: A Women's Group Four Decades Later"</title>; questionnaires; interviews with former members (audio recordings and transcripts); correspondence; and notes. The collection also includes other writings by Pritchard and subject files on women's issues. Photographs of Pritchard (electronic) were added in Dec. 2010.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_826d548233a306ac286fefbb22190b93">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Marietta Pritchard has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Pritchard, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_4569a95d380dfc233eb1878f02a807c7">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>unknown</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminists -- Massachusetts -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Amherst (Mass.) -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Amherst Women's Liberation</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Interviews</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Manuscripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Computer media</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Pritchard, Marietta</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
