<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss">ssc00502</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Patricia Lee Lewis papers <num>SSC.MS.00502</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-12 12:48:28 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-12</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Patricia Lee Lewis papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="source">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Lewis, Patricia Lee</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00502</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(20 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1966/2013"
                   type="inclusive">1966-2013</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8628919163d1d5099b0748965109002f">This collection documents Patricia Lee Lewis' personal life, education, and several different careers; her political activism; her work in rural, community-based agriculture; and her evolution as a creative writer and teacher of that craft.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_aa974b69eaf1e886edadec58f973ff36">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_69d532e5263abd77110c308d2ba9a0a7">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was received as a gift from Patricia Lee Lewis in 2004, 2008, and 2015.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_b01156e2fd75c1b854bcdc5c01da7b4c">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>
Patricia Lee Lewis (formerly Pat Lewis Sackrey) was born and raised in Texas. After working as a business manager for ten years and having two children (a son, John Henry Sackrey, and a daughter, Ponteir Sackrey), she earned her A.B. in Anthropology from Smith College in 1970. Lewis' early political activism (circa 1969 to 1974) focused on women's issues, during which time she co-founded the Valley Women's Center in Northampton, Mass. and Everywoman's Center at the University of Massachusetts, Amherst. From 1972 to 1974, she served as Director of Continuing Education for Women at the University of Mass. From 1974 to 1976, Lewis worked in the Mass. Office for Children, as Supervisor of Community Development for Berkshire, Franklin, Hampden, and Hampshire Counties. In 1977, she held the position of Consultant to the Superintendent of the Belchertown (Mass.) State School for Retarded Citizens, and from 1977 to 1981 she worked as Rural Development Specialist for the Mass. Cooperative Extension Service at the University of Mass. Amherst. From 1975 to 1979, she served on Mass. Governor Michael Dukakis'Commission on the Status of Women. Lewis was a self-employed tree farmer from 1981 to 1983, and in 1983 was appointed Executive Director of the Hilltown Community Development Corporation in Chesterfield, Mass. In 1984, she was elected County Commissioner for Hampshire County, MA, which position she held until 1988. From 1991 to 1996, she served as District Director and Director of Marketing for Congressman John W. Olver. Galvanized and inspired after joining Pat Schneider's Amherst Writers and Artists Workshop in 1986, Lewis eventually went on to earn her MFA in Creative Writing from the Vermont College of Union University (1998). She is a Senior Partner in Amherst Writers&amp;Artists, and a member of the Austin Writers League and the American Poetry Society. Her poetry, fiction and feature articles have appeared in journals, anthologies, and newspapers. She lives and works at Patchwork Farm Retreat in western Massachusetts, which she founded in 1992, where she leads writing retreats and workshops. She has also led retreats for writers in Indiana and in her home state of Texas, as well as in Scotland, Costa Rica and Mexico.  </p>
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_fbf9414d99bf1ea3cd75286a3ff12218">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Some accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_b5b946d060f5f5ee5767f59df8d5700d">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Patricia Lee Lewis papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00502, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_17440a35354ceb4c64ba4d55d3478389">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Valley Women's Center Records, Pat Schneider Papers, Valley Women's History collaborative Records, UMass Special Collections</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_8d5c20ac3081f988296e359f939bb625">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection consists of diaries, correspondence, articles, clippings and memorabilia documenting Patricia Lee Lewis'personal life, education, and several different careers; her political activism; her work in rural, community-based agriculture; and her evolution as a creative writer and teacher of that craft.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_15d270d6b1090969a9a3236d5838b1b2">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Lewis has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Lewis, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Authors, American--20th century--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminism--Massachusetts--History--20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Valley Women's Center (Northampton, Mass.)--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Feminists--Massachusetts--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Businesswomen--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Poets, American--20th century--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Address books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Appointment books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">diaries</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Speeches</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Greeting cards</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Oral histories</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="fmo" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lewis, Patricia Lee</persname>
    
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_2290"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Lewis, Patricia Lee</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
