<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manosca">ca01010</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Academic Departments records <num>CA.MS.01010</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-17 09:59:04 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Academic Departments records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="lcsh">Smith College.</corpname>
         </origination>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
         <unitid>CA.MS.01010</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">63 boxes plus oversized material</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1890/1890"
                   type="inclusive">1890-present</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_174d3ff7d4e4cc85b94c597b8efd8721">The collection contains papers of academic departments, including Interdepartmental, Sciences, Languages, and Social Sciences.  The collection has publications, syllabuses, source notes, department records and memos, photographs, and material on departmental clubs.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_7a512a7e86bb873e43d08c8676acc956">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.</p>
         <p>Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently.
Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently.
Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation.
Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 y</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_c997579de40c7103479e1cf23b6a6696">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_9b8b50ce85f10b49ae3078615a78ae0e">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Many of the accessions have container lists and accession records that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_794b8be5280039f72b4e281fb9773aff">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Academic Departments records, College Archives, SC-MS-01010, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_bdb436663c9409d6f0cebf1495428d0b">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Academic Departments records are organized alphabetically by department name, except for sub-categories.  They include the following departments: Interdepartmental (American Studies etc.), Sciences (Chemistry, Geology, Hygiene and Bacteriology, Physics, Sociology, Zoology), Languages(Italian, Russian, etc), Social Sciences (Sociology), etc.  The collection contains such material as publications, syllabuses, source notes, department records and memos, photographs, and material on departmental clubs.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_5b148d0b33f5d8fe85865d3625d39fb6">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
