<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manosca">ca01039</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Smith College Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty records   <num>CA.MS.01039</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-04-18 15:53:58 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty records</unittitle>
         <unitid>CA.MS.01039</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">603.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(453 record cartons, 44 archive letter boxes, 1 archive legal box, 16 archive half-letter boxes, 1 archive half-letter box, 8 flat file boxes, 2 card file boxes = 525 boxes total)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1946/2018"
                   type="inclusive">1946-present</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_ea3331e2410ea22309d8f2131a0b1f7e">The Office of the Provost and Dean of the Faculty directs and integrates the varied academic efforts of the college to create a thriving community and supports faculty across the arc of their professional lives—through curricular innovation, compensation, professional development and external grants.  The Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty records contain files on tenure and promotion committees, meetings, inactive faculty, personnel.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_d0e90851199e35dddc4a0d38bce7de5b">English.</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a01443fd4fb5c48753ea2e7f39835fbc">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.</p>
         <p>Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently.
Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently.</p>
         <p>Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation.</p>
         <p>Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.</p>
         <p>In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_fdd981c64f7aa53e5274c31577144632">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Office of the Provost and Dean of the Faculty directs and integrates the varied academic efforts of the college to create a thriving community and supports faculty across the arc of their professional lives—through curricular innovation, compensation, professional development and external grants.</p>
         <p>The Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty began as Dean of the Faculty in 1946. This office only lasted until 1948 and then re-emerged in 1978. In 1998, it obtained its current title, Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_cfaf65b1f37e040ca9110187fd34b28d">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p>Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty records, College Archives, MS ca01039, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts. </p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_1d414c82e3fb1b47b7c1594f15467a95">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Part of this collection has been processed, most has not, in the sense that archival arrangement and description beyond creating minimal box lists has not been done. The arrangement and description of materials may change in the future as iterative processing occurs. Researchers are encouraged to document their citations with this in mind.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_9076040d38fa489c92e50db4d810cc1a">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Office of the Provost/Dean of the Faculty records contain files on tenure and promotion committees, meetings, inactive faculty, personnel.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_991d59f432211a851cb8f977827156c1">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Materials in this collection may be governed by copyright. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. Researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_fdc843bf1f8f96e212746e149786a2ed" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Committee on Tenure &amp; Promotion files</unittitle>
               <unitid>2018-A-0055</unitid>
            </did>
            <c02 id="aspace_bcd0a1ebd5ad502688aed671da7bc1fe" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faculty tenure and promotion files</unittitle>
                  <physdesc altrender="whole">
                     <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">48 folders</extent>
                     <extent altrender="carrier">(48 folders)</extent>
                  </physdesc>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2016/2018"
                            type="inclusive">2016-2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Record carton"
                             id="aspace_e8aa020a9aa5c0c7d2b95cc4430cb93b"
                             label="Mixed Materials [310183630073517]"
                             type="box">1</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
