<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manosca">ca01002</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Special Events and People collection <num>CA.MS.01002</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-16 13:11:36 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Special Events and People collection</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="lcsh">Smith College.</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.01002</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">40 boxes plus oversized material</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1900/1999"
                   type="inclusive">c. 1900-1999</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_c94a8cdead41d13a93ab39efa4ca618a">The collection contains materials relating to special events and people hosted by Smith College, including files on disasters, anniversaries, lectures and symposiums, and War Service in World War II.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_a3463f49499e9b29817016acd74479a5">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.  Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently.  In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_ce6783edde6cd6a7e2332969a9daaf25">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_64e0676a24e284c05fbe7334656c86e1">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Two parts of the collection, the Sophia Smith Bicentennial Celebration and the War Service materials, have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_721d1af46ba3275c17ea01fe0d15b458">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Special Events and People collection, College Archives, CA-MS-01002, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_06847617abe906815956dee2797b3ec5">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection contains materials relating to special events and people hosted by Smith College.  Files on Anniversaries include material on college anniversaries in l900, l925, 1950, and 1975. Files on Disasters include news clippings on fires, thefts, murders, disappearances, suicides. Files on Lectures include photographs, press releases, and news clippings on guest lecturers. Files on Prizes include correspondence and news clippings. Symposiums files include correspondence, photographs, programs, news clippings, publications. Files on War Service includes photographs, organization records, news clippings, publications, personal papers of participants, campus and local activities, War Service Board records.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_4afe0a6427088614cc8e436426a7d3e1">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
