<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manosca">ca01011</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Graduate Work records <num>CA.MS.01011</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-17 10:48:40 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Graduate Work records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname source="lcsh">Smith College. Department of Graduate Studies.</corpname>
         </origination>
    
    
         <unitid>CA.MS.01011</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">35 boxes plus oversized material</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1919/1919"
                   type="inclusive">c. 1919-present</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_09e0fd7bd603868cd39aebebd052c54f">Graduate Work records include files on individuals who did graduate work at Smith, information on Smith graduate programs, and non-degree programs.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_04588897c9f0e0d77acca62fde59af2a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.  Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students.  In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_062b36c35d32b2fa4b0fe15e2714d7be">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Source unknown.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_38e52c1904aefffaf64f9247151415fa">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Many parts of the collection have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_102ae2adc12ac2e9c5a3ba2444d8ff25">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Graduate Work records, College Archives, CA-MS-01011, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_0fb4cf7f5a10a84400a2909cb1c91a31">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Graduate Work records include files on individuals who did graduate work at Smith; information on Smith graduate programs (such as the Summer Schools of Italian and Music, the masters program in Physical Education, and the School for Social Work); and non-degree programs (such as the Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests, Alumnae College, and the Project on Women and Social Change).  Additional program records are filed elsewhere.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_8c4734fb209f05ce66b3538c01c88278">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College. Department of Graduate Studies.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="naf">Alumnae College</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College. School for Social Work.</corpname>
  
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="naf">Alumnae College</corpname>
    
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Smith College. School for Social Work.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
