<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Minimum Finding Aid (completed)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manosca">ca01001</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to Articles about Smith College collection <num>CA.MS.01001</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-16 11:43:10 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Articles about Smith College collection</unittitle>
         <unitid>CA.MS.01001</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 boxes plus oversized material</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1873/2018"
                   type="inclusive">1873-present</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_51d39c4710b88435889f1749c4ec7db2">Cartoons, newspaper clippings and published articles about Smith College from a wide variety of sources.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8d3bbadb45be500da942251b7da432be">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.  In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_693020d506c5ff451c48dd0997cad7fd">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>This collection was started by the mother of Nina Brown, Smith College Class of 1879.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_153235cfbc4b68a506044195676bbeae">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>This collection of newspaper clippings was started by the mother of Nina Brown, Smith College Class of 1879.  It has been added to over the years.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_c5d875e03050d1aa486c434f1a604648">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The collection has a finding aid, including a container list, that is available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_0629a4fe5453e34aae9b953dc3dae004">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Articles about Smith College collection, College Archives, CA-MS-01001, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_5d120a16db1701f86a1fd7c4bf850a33">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection contains cartoons, newspaper clippings, and published articles about Smith College, beginning in 1873.  A majority of the clippings are from newspapers around the country.  In addition, articles written by Smith College graduates make part of this collection.  Materials are added periodically to the collection.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_ecf07003b5e765d05c364dfc93cd612f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Smith College retains copyright of materials created as part of its business operations; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="naf">Smith College.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
