<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="manosca">ca01021</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid for Smith College web archive <num>CA.MS.01021</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Margaret Jessup</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Smith College Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/college-archives"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-24 11:40:29 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Smith College Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Smith College web archive</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <corpname authfilenumber="source_163" source="local_inmagic-source">Smith College Office of College Relations</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>CA.MS.01021</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 collection</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(approximately 50 archived websites )</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="2015/2018"
                   type="inclusive">captured 2015-2018; subsequent captures are ongoing</unitdate>
      </did>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a7d57e97f196297488ca194514c99938">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Smith College web archive includes archived versions of the official college website content and  related blogs and social media created by academic and administrative departments, academic centers, alumnae and student groups. Content includes news media; academic programs; conferences and other events; student organizations; and alumnae activities. </p>
         <p>A wide range of academic and student groups, special projects blogs and social media sites exist outside of the official Smith College website's domain. Some of those represented in the archive include: the Women's Narratives Project; Smith College Society of Women Engineers; Engineers for a Sustainable World at Smith College; Al-Iman: SC Muslim Student Association Facebook page; Center for the Environment, Ecological Design, and Sustainability blog; Center for Religion and Spiritual Life blog; Lewis Global Studies Center; Disability Alliance Tumbler page; African Women's Leadership Conference; Community Garden blog; Hack At Smith: Smith Hackathon events site; and Impressions: Journal of and for Smith Students around the world.</p>
         <p>Since 2015 over fifty Smith College websites have been added to the Smith College web archive and new content is added on a regular basis. Once the initial capture of a website is completed, periodic captures are conducted as long as the site is active. </p>
         <p>The Smith College web archive can be viewed through the <extref a="https://archive-it.org/collections/6152">Archive-It web archiving service</extref>: https://archive-it.org/collections/6152</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_195edc1da32bd91dfa21cc6dcef921a0">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Smith web archiving program was implemented in 2015 and is administered by the Smith College Libraries with the goal of collecting and preserving web content associated with Smith College, as well as selected websites of organizations and individuals whose records and papers are held in the College Archives and Special Collections.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_9fd445de62c56664552203a0fa2e2109">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Most archived websites in this collection are available for public viewing immediately. Exceptions may be made if the website creator/owner requests a restriction  an archived site be restricted for a specified time.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_13bcdba1bf7b5a5ad3cc270cd4dfb58e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright to web content created by or for Smith College, is owned by Smith College; however, copyright in third-party content on these websites may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Smith College, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Smith College--History--Sources</geogname>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Electronic records</genreform>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smith College -- Faculty</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smith College--Students--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_6a3abd1cce432c74a34629debdedcdda" level="file">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Smith College archived websites</unittitle>
               <dao actuate="onrequest"
                    audience="external"
                    href="https://archive-it.org/collections/6152"
                    show="new"
                    title="Link to Smith College web archive"/>
            </did>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
