<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss584</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding Aid to the Alison Bechdel papers <num>SSC.MS.00633</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2015</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-03-20 17:29:08 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:23-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Alison Bechdel papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="lcnaf">Bechdel, Alison, 1960-</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00633</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(36 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1984/2013"
                   type="inclusive">1984-2013</unitdate>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_1299c24b507f32de38d6b7f40bcba1f7">English</langmaterial>
         <abstract id="aspace_4775b109f47b780e40ee6de2d4700a5d">This collection is comprised of materials related to works created by Alison Bechdel. It includes business correspondence, character and topic development files, manuscript edits, press interviews, reviews, press releases, and a broad range of texts, sketches, and notes that formed the basis for Bechdel's work from the mid-1980s through the early 2000s.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Alison Bechdel was born in Lock Haven, Pennsylvania to Bruce Allen Bechdel--high school English teacher, antiques dealer, and funeral director--and Helen Fontana Bechdel--high school English teacher and amateur actress. Her family also owned and operated a funeral home, dubbed the Fun Home by Bechdel and her two brothers.</p>
         <p> Bechdel earned her A.A. in 1979 from Simon's Rock Early College (now Simon's Rock of Bard College) and her B.A. from Oberlin College in 1981. She applied to many art schools but was rejected. She worked in various publishing industry office jobs in New York City from 1981 to 1985, and as a production writer for Equal Time in Minneapolis, MN from 1986 to 1990. According to the autobiographical <title render="italic">The Indelible Alison Bechdel</title>, she began "Dykes to Watch Out For" (DTWOF) as a single drawing labeled: "Marianne, dissatisfied with the morning brew: Dykes to Watch Out For, plate no. 27." An acquaintance recommended she send her work to <title render="italic">Womannews </title>newspaper, which began publishing the strip regularly beginning with the July-August 1983 issue. After a year, other outlets began running the strip, and it was syndicated in 1985.</p>
         <p> In 1988, Bechdel began a short-lived, page-length strip about the staff of a queer newspaper, titled <title render="italic">Servants to the Cause</title>, for <title render="italic">The Advocate</title> newspaper. The success of DTWOF allowed Bechdel to quit her day job in 1990 to work on the strip full-time. Bechdel has written and drawn autobiographical strips, has done illustrations for magazines and websites, and has written numerous books, including <title render="italic">Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1986), <title render="italic">More Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1988),<title render="italic"> New Improved! Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1990), <title render="italic">Unnatural Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1995), <title render="italic">Hot, Throbbing Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1997), <title render="italic">The Indelible Alison Bechdel: Confessions, Comix and Miscellaneous Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (1998), <title render="italic">Dykes and Sundry Other Carbon-based Life-Forms to Watch Out For</title> (2003), <title render="italic">Invasion of the Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (2005), <title render="italic">Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic</title> (2006), and <title render="italic">The Essential Dykes to Watch Out For</title> (2008). Four of Bechdel's books have won Lamba Literary Awards for humor, and <title render="italic">The Indelible Alison Bechdel</title> won a Lambda Literary Award in the biography/autobiography category. In February 2004, Bechdel married her partner since 1992, Amy Rubin, in a civil ceremony in San Francisco; they separated in 2006.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access:</p>
         <p>Boxes 7-20 of accession 2008-S-104 must be used with great care; researchers may not disrupt the order of materials.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Alison Bechdel has retained copyright in her artwork donated to Smith College. To the extent that she owns it, Alison Bechdel has assigned the copyright in all other materials in this collection to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. </p>
         <p>For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Alison Bechdel, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Alison Bechdel Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <accruals id="aspace_admin-accruals">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic additions to collection are expected.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <processinfo id="aspace_e128eabac525e6077e68b153fed7b101">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Materials in Boxes 7-20 of 08S-104 arrived from Bechdel in three large plastic tubs and were reboxed while maintaining their original order. The materials are in chronological order from the bottom up and have multiple pages related to each strip. Each strip's pages are not clearly identified as being together, but are by order of sheets in box, from bottom up. So, for example, the bottom of Box 7 contains materials dated around 1984, and the top of box 13 contains materials dated around 2002.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_c0e4abc6078166a84d4c63c02a015de2">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Alison Bechdel papers document the illustrative and written works created by Alison Bechdel. It includes business correspondence for Stationery Flux (S.F.), the business used for Dykes to Watch Out For merchandise, character and topic development files, manuscript edits, press interviews, reviews, press releases, and a broad range of texts, sketches, and notes that formed the basis for Bechdel's work from the mid-1980s through the early 2000s.</p>
         <p>The bulk of the collection documents development files for the syndicated comic strip <title>Dykes to Watch Out For</title> and <title>Servants to the Cause</title> are included. Also included are post-syndication/pre-publication edits for Bechdel's book, <title>Dykes to Watch Out For</title> and <title>Fun Home</title>.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_9e06f9b2fd5dfbace804fb26fcf221d8">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>This collection has not yet been processed, so is arranged by accession.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cartoonists--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian artists--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbianism in art</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbianism--United States--Caricatures and cartoons</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian feminism--United States--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">American wit and humor, Pictorial</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bechdel, Alison, 1960-. Dykes to watch out for -- Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Cartoons (humorous images)</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">press releases</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publicity</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Reviews</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Sketches</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Drawings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="dnr" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bechdel, Alison, 1960-</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
