<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="in_progress"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss606</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Jennifer Abod papers <num>SSC.MS.00513</num>
            </titleproper>
            <subtitle>Finding Aid</subtitle>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-02 11:38:13 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-08-02</date>
            <item>Amanda Ferrara updated the resource record.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Jennifer Abod papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00513</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(10 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1975/2007" type="inclusive">1975-2007</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_77dc7910c4ee1493f7833b46ba53247f">Jennifer Abod is an audio and video documentarian. She hosted and produced programs on community, public, and commercial radio in New Haven, Philadelphia and Boston for nearly twenty years. In 1988, she created Profile Productions to produce and distribute audio and video projects featuring feminist and lesbian activists, cultural workers, particularly women of color. The collection documents a range of topics, primarily second wave feminism and women's rights, abortion, gay and lesbian rights, race relations, and numerous individuals involved with those issues. The collection almost entirely consists of audiovisual materials (video and audio tapes) pertaining to Abod's work as a filmmaker.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accruals id="aspace_d4df67ab461e0831a178e60dbb39b248">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records: 20005-S-0002, 2008-S-0083. Accessions were received on the following dates: 2004-12-22, 2008-08-14.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <accruals id="aspace_f94797049584b5c77042d9f8169658f6">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic accruals to collection are expected.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <bioghist id="aspace_364e279c7ae233d4f866a366e4c2b229">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Jennifer Abod (1946- ) is an audio and video documentarian. She was born in Chicago, Illinois and holds a PhD in Intercultural Media Education and Women's Studies. </p>
         <p>Jennifer Abod hosted and produced programs on community, public, and commercial radio in New Haven, Philadelphia and Boston for nearly twenty years. She was the first woman in Connecticut to host a nightly AM radio talk program, <title render="italic">The Jennifer Abod Show</title>, which she ran for four years. She is a co-founder of the New Haven (CT) Women's Liberation Rock Band, and co-writer of <title render="italic">Liberating Lydia</title>, the first feminist radio soap opera. </p>
         <p>In 1988, Jennifer Abod created Profile Productions to produce and distribute media featuring feminist activists and cultural workers, particularly women of color and lesbians who influence broad constituencies. She developed the skills necessary to pursuing her interest in documenting women's lives while working for Digital Equipment Corporation where she directed, wrote and produced corporate audio and videotapes. Her first audio documentary was <title render="italic">Audre Lorde: An Audio Profile</title> (1988), and she completed her first feature video documentary, <title render="italic">The Edge of Each Other's Battles: The Vision of Audre Lorde</title>, in 2002. Abod has also organized and moderated Fighting Racism: White Feminist Stories, a panel and work session at the National Women's Studies Association Conference, which has provided an opportunity for white women to reflect and learn from each other's experiences after years of work. </p>
         <p>Abod has lectured widely, teaching at the Univeristy of Massachusetts, Boston; Worcester State; Hofstra University; and California State University, Long Beach. She has also facilitated workshops on such topics as the making of the Audre Lorde film, creating feminist documentary, and the role of film and culture in social justice movements.</p>
         <p>Jennifer Abod married her partner of more than 30 years, Angela Bowen (1936-2018), in 2013.</p>
         <p>Source: <extref href="http://www.jenniferabod.com/about-jennifer-abod.htm">Jennifer Abod's website</extref>.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8455fc2a4501e19a78cd5f2d90b0d971">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_e794f066ae0d9f9511d87b31e3746dc1">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Jennifer Abod papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Special Collections, Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_22f38e7d885d2456e3f6fb6bca05cc58">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Jennifer Abod Papers consist almost entirely of audiovisual materials (video and audio tapes) pertaining to her work as a filmmaker. There is also a small amount of correspondence and press releases. The papers document a range of topics, primarily second wave feminism and women's rights, abortion, gay and lesbian rights, race relations, and numerous individuals involved with those issues. There is a substantial amount relating to her documentaries on African American feminist and writer, Audre Lorde. </p>
         <p>Other individuals include Phil Donohue, Joseph Beam, Sarah Caldwell, Barbara Johnson. Recorded events and shows include the Jennifer Abod Show, I Am Your Sister, Harvard Women's Studies, Writing for Radio, International Women's Day, A.T. C. Franklin Park, Fifth of July, Sojourner Show, Gay Pride Week.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Abortion -- Political aspects -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">African American women -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American feminists -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminism and motion pictures</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008103671" source="lcsh">Feminists -- United States -- Biography</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gay rights -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women motion picture producers and directors -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Motion pictures -- United States -- Production and direction</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Independent filmmakers -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lorde, Audre</subject>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="n97841742"
                   rules="dacs"
                   source="lcnaf">Bowen, Angela (Angela Doreathia Bowen), 1936-2018</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
