<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss493</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding Aid to Dyke TV records <num>SSC.MS.00656</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2010</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-03-20 15:49:25 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:20-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>03/20/2018</date>
            <item>This finding aid was updated to reflect accurate copyright ownership and that donor has agreed for video to be published on open internet.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Dyke TV records</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="lcnaf">Dyke TV</persname>
         </origination>
    
    
    
    
    
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00656</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">93 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(80 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1993/2007"
                   type="inclusive">1993-2007</unitdate>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_3c79db14d98ae6cf68fa678cfe1427c3">English</langmaterial>
         <abstract id="aspace_00336943e611e3404b85ae123ddc4bf8">Television production company; Lesbian business. Collection includes video tapes, raw footage, and DVD dubs for Dyke TV programs. The materials cover a wide range of topics, including but not limited to lesbians in sports, artists, gay pride, childhood and coming of age stories, political issues, gay and lesbian civil rights, sexuality, lesbian parenting, HIV/AIDS and other health issues, incest survivors, lesbian domestic violence, and women's rights. [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Dyke TV was created by Ana Maria Simo (playwright and co-founder of Lesbian Avengers), Linda Chapman (theater director and producer) and Mary Patierno (independent film and video maker). The first show aired in New York City, June 8, 1993. Dyke TV produced national documentary television programming, by and for lesbians, designed to empower and to enhance the visibility of diverse lesbian communities; it mixed art, news, sports, political commentary, health coverage, music, and video as it examined issues of lesbian culture. The program reached over 6.5 million households nationwide, and was screened at many national and international film and music festivals. The half-hour weekly cable television show featured a five-minute news segment covering issues relevant to lesbian lives from a lesbian perspective; an in-depth look at an issue of particular interest to the lesbian community, including such topics as the International Dyke March at Stonewall 25, the murder of Brandon Teena, Camp Sister Spirit under siege, lesbians in the military, domestic partnership, and state-wide ballot initiatives and other anti-lesbian and anti-gay activities of the Christian Right; and interviews with lesbian artists, showcasing their work. Dyke TV won a Hometown Video Festival Award in 1994.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The records contain show master tapes, editor's master tapes, raw footage, and DVD dubs for <title render="italic">Dyke TV</title> programs. The materials cover a wide range of topics, including but not limited to lesbians in sports, artists, gay pride, childhood and coming of age stories, political issues, gay and lesbian civil rights, sexuality, lesbian parenting, HIV/AIDS and other health issues, incest survivors, lesbian domestic violence, and women's rights.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <phystech id="aspace_admin-access">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies. Viewing copies of most final broadcast shows are available.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that they own copyright, Sangfroid LLT (the production company that created Dyke TV) has retained copyright in works donated to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Sangfroid LLT, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p> Dyke TV Records, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <altformavail id="aspace_admin-altform">
         <head>Additional Formats</head>
         <p>Selected Dyke TV episodes and the complete show logs have been digitized and are available to <extref href="https://media.smith.edu/departments/ssc/dyketv/dyketv1993_playlist.html">view online</extref>.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Dyke TV Records were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by producers Sally Sasso and Mary Patierno in 2009.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.</p>
         <p> Accessioned by Burd Schlessinger, December 2009</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_add-related">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Additional Dyke TV materials were donated to the Lesbian Herstory Archives, Brooklyn, NY</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1fdc264c003188b71429f780a61bafdb">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian activists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States -- Social life and customs</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Documentary television programs</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Gay rights -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Chapman, Linda</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Patierno, Mary</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Sasso, Sally</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Simo, Ana Maria</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publicity</genreform>
    
    
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4773"
                   role="dnr"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Patierno, Mary</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_3476"
                   role="dnr"
                   source="lcnaf">Sasso, Sally</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4773"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Patierno, Mary</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" authfilenumber="people_3476" source="lcnaf">Sasso, Sally</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Chapman, Linda</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Simo, Ana Maria</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
