<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="in_progress"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss"/>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Jane Fonda papers <num>SSC.MS.00477</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Amanda Ferrara</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-06-14 14:22:31 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
    
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Jane Fonda papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n79103680" source="lcnaf">Fonda, Jane</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00477</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">68.90 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(132 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1946/2016" type="inclusive">1946-2016</unitdate>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_4b006179f2f99350fe92715cd1fdd498">English</langmaterial>
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_68f2d42761a89401bd6226a6f2c7eeac">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>This collection was donated in 16 transfers from 2003-2016.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accruals id="aspace_e30812426895839071ea25c7584d3be1">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Additional donations of materials are expected.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <bioghist id="aspace_ab496708fe2fbd5434998624b9a0b413">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Jane Seymour Fonda was born in New York, New York, on December 21, 1937 to actor Henry Fonda (1905-1982) and socialite Frances Seymour Brokaw (1908-1950). She has one brother, Peter Fonda (1940- ). She received her primary and secondary education at the Brentwood Town and Country School in Los Angeles, CA; the Greenwich Academy in Greenwich, CT; and the Emma Willard School in Troy, NY. She attended Vassar College from 1955-1957, through her sophomore year.</p>
         <p>
Fonda travelled to France in the summer of 1957, and enrolled in the art school Académie de la Grand Chaumiére in the fall. She lived in Paris until the winter of 1957, when her father insisted that she return home to New York City. In the summer of 1958, Henry Fonda moved the family to a house on the Santa Monica beach in Los Angeles where Jane befriended Susan Strasberg, daughter of actor, acting teacher, and director, Lee Strasberg. Strasberg accepted Jane into his fall 1958 private Method Acting classes in New York City. Fonda worked for the Ford Modeling Agency to finance her lessons. In 1959, Fonda made her Broadway debut in <title render="italic">There Was a Little Girl</title>, earning her the New York Drama Critics' Circle award for "the most promising actress of the year for drama," and a Tony nomination for Best Performance by a Featured Actress in a Play. Her first film role was in<title render="italic">Tall Story</title>(1960). Fonda opened in her second Broadway play,<title render="italic">Invitation to a March</title>, in the fall of 1960.</p>
         <p>
Between 1960 and 1964, Jane Fonda made six movies including <title render="italic">Period of Adjustment</title>(1962),<title render="italic">Walk on the Wild Side</title> (1962),<title render="italic">The Chapman Report</title> (1962),<title render="italic">In the Cool of the Day</title> (1963),<title render="italic">Sunday in New York</title> (1963), and<title render="italic">Les Félins</title> (1964). Fonda was approached by the film director Roger Vadim (1928-2000) in 1963 to film a remake of<title render="italic">La Ronde</title>, but dismissed the offer. Later, Fonda and Vadim officially met at her birthday party in December 1963 and entered into a relationship. Despite Fonda's initial objection, the pair filmed <title render="italic">La Ronde</title> in 1964. Fonda and Vadim lived together in France co-parenting Vadim's two children Nathalie and Christian with their mothers, Annette Stroyberg and Catherine Deneuve, respectively. Fonda travelled between California, New York, and France for work, ultimately purchasing a home in France in 1965 before her marriage to Roger Vadim in August 1965. </p>
         <p>
Fonda became attune to global and American social and political issues. While filming <title render="italic">Hurry Sundown</title> (1967) in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, Fonda began to understand both overt and nuanced racial disparities, as well as the fight for Civil Rights not only in the South and in the United States on the whole. Her next two films,<title render="italic">Barbarella</title> (1968) and<title render="italic">Tre Passi Nel Delirio (Historia Extraordinarias/Spirits of the Dead)</title> (1968), filmed with Vadim in Rome, also sparked a heightened awareness of women's sexual exploitation, most notably Barbarella. Fonda was also influenced by Vadim and friends' vehement opposition to American action in Vietnam and the anti-Vietnam War movement in France. </p>
         <p>
In 1968, Fonda and Vadim's daughter, Vanessa Vadim (1968- ) was born. They separated a year later.</p>
         <p> 
Jane Fonda spent much of 1970 touring the U.S., speaking out against the Vietnam War, and in support of groups representing disenfranchised communities, such as the American Indian Movement and the Black Panther Party. These activities earned Fonda a place on the Nixon administration's "enemies list," and eventually resulted in a 22,000 page FBI file.</p>
         <p> 
After her first cross-country tour, Fonda alternated living between Los Angeles, California and New York City before settling in L.A. In L.A., Fonda became friends with actor and activist Donald Sutherland. That same year, Fonda, Sutherland, and activist and physician Howard Levy created "an alternative to Bob Hope's traditional pro-war entertainment," a satirical anti-war revue, entitled<title render="italic">FTA</title> ('Free the Army' or Fuck the Army').<title render="italic">FTA</title> was "political vaudeville with an antiwar, pro-soldier theme…intended not only to support the soldiers' antiwar sentiments but to call attention to the way soldiers were dehumanized in the military." A documentary about the tour directed by Francine Parker, titled<title render="italic">F.T.A</title> (1972), was picked up for film distribution by American International.</p>
         <p>
In May 1972 Fonda received an invitation from the Vietnamese Committee for Solidarity with the American People, the Vietnamese cultural Association, and the Vietnam Film Artists Association to make a two week trip to Hanoi. It was on this trip that Fonda provoked major controversy by making several broadcasts over Radio Hanoi in which she urged American airmen to stop bombing the North. She met with groups of American prisoners of war (POWs), took photographs and film evidence of the American-created damage to the system of Vietnamese dikes, and also met with various Vietnamese citizens and soldiers. It was on this trip that Fonda was photographed sitting on a North Vietnamese anti-aircraft gun site. This incident was the origin of the epithet 'Hanoi Jane.' Following this, she returned to New York and dealt with the repercussions of her travel: accusation of treason, a call to boycott Fonda's films, and other political, professional, and societal backlash.</p>
         <p>
Fonda met activist Tom Hayden (1939-2016) in early 1972, and entered a relationship with him shortly thereafter. The two worked to create a national speaking tour, the Indochina Peace Campaign (IPC), for the fall of 1972. Jane officially divorced Roger Vadim in January 1973 in order to marry Hayden. They had one son together, Troy Garity (1973- ). Fonda's marriage to Tom Hayden in 1973 further galvanized her politically and together they engaged in grassroots organizing on such issues as increased community services, migrant workers' rights, and solar energy development; they founded the Campaign for Economic Democracy (CED), to "democratize" U.S. corporate culture; and organized national rallies in their campaigns against "unbridled corporate power" and nuclear energy. </p>
         <p>
Fonda embarked on her second U.S. tour in 1973 with Tom Hayden and Troy, and shortly after that, travelled again to North Vietnam. This second trip was to facilitate the creation of a documentary, <title render="italic">Introduction to the Enemy</title> (1974), "aimed at showing the human side of Vietnam, a view of the people's lives and stories very few Americans would otherwise ever see or hear." Haskell Wexler, an American cinematographer, filmed and co-directed the documentary with both Fonda and Hayden. </p>
         <p>
Fonda created her own production company, IPC Films, with friend Bruce Gilbert in the late 1970s. IPC Films produced <title render="italic">Introduction to the Enemy</title> (1974),<title render="italic">The China Syndrome</title> (1979),<title render="italic">9 to 5</title> (1980),<title render="italic">Rollover</title>, and<title render="italic">On Golden Pond</title> (both 1981).<title render="italic">The China Syndrome</title> and<title render="italic">On Golden Pond</title> were both nominated for Academy Awards.</p>
         <p>
In 1977, Hayden and Fonda bought land north of Santa Barbara, California, to create a performing arts summer camp for children called Laurel Springs. The camp ran for 14 years, until 1991, and used the performing arts to build self-esteem and cooperation among children of all races and socio-economic backgrounds. It was here that Fonda met Mary Luana (Lulu) Williams (1967- ), a child of Black Panther Party members, with whom Fonda fostered a mother-daughter relationship. After getting to know Williams over the course of three summers, Fonda adopted her in 1982, at the age of 16.</p>
         <p>
In 1979, Fonda opened a fitness workout studio in Beverly Hills, California. Its success led to the establishment of other such studios in California as well as the creation of five books, twelve audio programs, and twenty-three videotapes, including <title render="italic">Jane Fonda's Workout Book</title> (1981),<title render="italic">Jane Fonda's Workout Book for Pregnancy, Birth and Recovery</title> (1982), and<title render="italic">Women Coming of Age</title> (1984) with Julia Lafonda.<title render="italic">The Jane Fonda Workout</title> (1982) video remains the top-grossing fitness video of all time. In researching material for<title render="italic">The Workout</title>, Fonda addressed her long battle with bulimia and food addiction. In 2011, Jane Fonda created five new tapes for seniors, and re-released five of the most requested titles from the Original Workout series on DVD and in digital format in 2015.</p>
         <p>
Fonda and Tom Hayden separated in 1988 and divorced in 1990. Shortly after, Fonda met broadcasting mogul Ted Turner (1938- ) and also decided to retire from acting. She states, "For all intents and purposes, I had decided to stop acting and producing by the time I met Ted, but once I committed to the relationship, it became a done deal." The two married on Fonda's 54th birthday, December 21, 1991 and divorced in 2001.</p>
         <p>
During her time away from acting, Fonda's work in community service and philanthropy became more pronounced. In 1995, Fonda founded the Georgia Campaign for Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention (G-CAPP) to work to reduce the high rates of adolescent pregnancy in Georgia through community and youth development, sustainable economic development, and legislative advocacy. As a part of this work, Fonda studied the effects of sexual violence on girls and boys. In 2012, the G-CAPP Board changed the name of the group to the Georgia Campaign for Adolescent Power and Potential. </p>
         <p>
Using Laurel Springs as a model, Fonda also co-founded the Performing Arts Program for Youth (PAPY) in Atlanta in the early 1990s. Other organizations in which Jane Fonda has been involved include Goodwill Ambassador to the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA), Fonda, Inc., the Turner Foundation, the Women's Media Center (WMC), the Carter Center, Advocates for Youth, The Village Foundation of the National Task Force on African-American Men and Boys, Girls, Inc., and the Elton John AIDS Foundation.</p>

         <p>
After fifteen years in retirement, Fonda returned to acting in 2005 with the film <title render="italic">Monster-In-Law</title>, and has continued to appear in television and film alike since that time. She has appeared on Broadway in<title render="italic">33 Variations</title> (2009), and on television in<title render="italic">The Simpsons</title> (2014),<title render="italic">Grace and Frankie</title> (2015- ), and<title render="italic">The Newsroom</title> (2012-2014).</p>
         <p>In addition to winning two Academy Awards for <title render="italic">Klute</title> (1971) and<title render="italic">Coming Home</title> (1979), Jane Fonda has received several Oscar nominations for Best Actress:<title render="italic">They Shoot Horses, Don't They?</title> (1969),<title render="italic">Julia</title> (1977),<title render="italic">On Golden Pond</title>, and<title render="italic">The Morning After</title> (1986). Fonda earned a Tony nomination for Best Performance by a Leading Actress in a Play for<title render="italic">33 Variations</title> and was twice nominated for an Emmy for Outstanding Guest Performer in a Drama Series for<title render="italic">The Newsroom</title> in 2012 and 2013.</p>
         <p>
Her many honors and awards include a Humanitarian Award from The Hebrew University of Jerusalem in 1982; being named a Goodwill Ambassador for the United Nations Population Fund in 1994; receiving an Honorary Palme d'Or for career achievement by the Cannes Film Festival in 2007; being inducted into the California Hall of Fame in 2008; receiving the New York Women's Agenda Lifetime Achievement Award in 2009; and being selected as the 42nd recipient of the American Film Institute's Lifetime Achievement Award in 2014.</p>

         <p>
Jane Fonda is the author of three books, <title render="italic">My Life So Far</title> (2005),<title render="italic">Prime Time</title> (2011), and<title render="italic">Being a Teen: Everything Teen Girls &amp; Boys Should Know About Relationships, Sex, Love, Health, Identity &amp; More</title> (2014).</p>
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_11d7260018e90aa6116d98d4904f3bcc">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_3762b33e64104eb482c4f371477ecdca">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Jane Fonda papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Special Collections, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_e754dfe1382525fb750f866d8ac39712">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>
The Jane Fonda papers span the period of 1946-2016, and relate to both her personal and professional life.
</p>
         <p>
The first series contains biographical information about Fonda's personal life, as well as that of her family members. Of note is Fonda's FBI file.</p>
         <p>
The second series contains correspondence pertaining to both Jane Fonda's personal, and professional, life. Subjects include family members of Fonda, various friends and celebrities, as well as large sections of fan mail, and correspondence with U.S. Veterans.</p>
         <p>
The third series contains materials related to Fonda's professional life. This includes acting, conferences and festivals, interviews, and the philanthropic organizations Fonda has been involved with.</p>
         <p>
The fourth series relates to published and unpublished writings by Fonda. Of note are the annotated drafts of Fonda's auto-biography, <title render="italic">My Life So Far</title>. Many of the drafts are annotated (typed and handwritten) by Fonda, members of her family (her half-sister Frances (Pan) de Villers Brokaw Corrias), her ex-husbands Tom Hayden and Ted Turner, and other friends. Some drafts were reused for a secondary printing, and therefore there is text and annotations on both recto and verso of many. Early drafts of chapters are also found in various folders in the Research sub-series of<title render="italic">My Life So Far</title>, "Tom Era" being a good example.</p>
         <p>
The fifth series includes photographs and negatives related to Fonda's adolescent life, professional life, workout series, and family.</p>
         <p>
The sixth series contains audiovisual materials of a wide variety of formats and topics. These materials document three aspects of Fonda's life: her political activism, including that related to her anti-Vietnam War efforts; the Jane Fonda Workout series; and interviews and television appearances, featuring Jane Fonda and/or her third husband, Ted Turner. The Vietnam-era audiovisual materials are of particular historical value.
Of note are the digitized film and clips of the 1974 documentary, <title render="italic">Introduction to the Enemy</title>.</p>

         <p>
The seventh series contains memorabilia, including a cloth hat with a patch that states "Veteran of the 60's" and has multiple political buttons attached.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_2a3852f763e5d71c764a4bf081dac43f">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Jane Fonda has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Jane Fonda, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <appraisal id="aspace_9ace86e287aeb45dd795532c7961fbf3">
         <head>Appraisal</head>
         <p>Appraisal conducted in accordance with the guidelines and policies of the Sophia Smith Collection. Duplicates, material of little evidential or information value, and documents with sensitive information have been returned to Jane Fonda. Correspondence related to the Broadway play, 33 Variations, came to the Sophia Smith Collection with water damage. These letters have been photocopied and the originals have been returned to Ms. Fonda. Audiovisual materials related to the Jane Fonda Workout Series were returned to Ms. Fonda in 2010 for digital reproduction.</p>  
      </appraisal>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1f5f6020285db2c89e2c4ae7a20847ed">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>A complete filmography can be found on <extref href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_Fonda_filmography">Wikipedia</extref>.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <phystech id="aspace_9b8abf58762640578ac3c8c257a4f1a4">
         <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
         <p>As a preservation measure, researchers must use digital copies of audiovisual materials in this collection. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request the creation of and access to digital copies.</p>  
      </phystech>
      <arrangement id="aspace_7bb1f4f33bbe7ebaa9d1813f54e40a1e">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is organized in seven series based on type of content.
<list>
               <item>Series 1. Biographical Materias</item>
               <item>Series 2. Correspondence</item>
               <item>Series 3. Professional activities</item>
               <item>Series 4. Writings</item>
               <item>Series 5. Photographs</item>
               <item>Series 6. Audiovisual materials</item>
               <item>Series 7. Memorabilia</item>
            </list>
         </p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008117538" source="lcsh">Actresses -- United States -- Biography</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008103671" source="lcsh">Feminists -- United States -- Biography</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008107993" source="lcsh">Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States -- Biography</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2007102042" source="lcsh">Birth control--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh97002859" source="lcsh">Body image in women</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Physical fitness for women -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh98006709" source="lcsh">Reproductive health</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008114050" source="lcsh">Youth--Services for--United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Protest movements--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008113232" source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2010104697" source="lcsh">Peace movements--United States--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="n97081184" source="lcsh">Ensler, Eve, 1953-</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Fonda, Henry, 1905-1982</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" authfilenumber="n80098112" source="lcsh">Hayden, Tom</geogname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="n81028923" source="lcsh">Turner, Ted</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Steinem, Gloria</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_8f2b9f831102a3ec843b02207d3d9900" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Biographical materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>1</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.26 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(15 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1946/2016" type="inclusive">1946-2016</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7e60ffee4b8ba03241855d8008892994">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>This series contains biographical information about Fonda's personal life, as well as that of her family members. It includes the sub-series of Administration, Awards and Distinctions, Biographical Sketches, Calendars, Clippings, Education, Family, and FBI Files. </p>
               <p>
Awards and Distinctions is organized chronologically and alphabetically, and contains oversize items. Calendars are organized chronologically and alphabetically. Clippings are organized chronologically. The Family sub-series contains materials on Henry Fonda, Jane Fonda's father, and Mary Luana (Lulu) Williams, Jane Fonda's adopted daughter.</p>
               <p>
The FBI Files sub-series is organized chronologically and alphabetically and contains written annotations and flagged pages.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_c968641609e46383e39dee0ef073569e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               <unitid>2</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.67 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(4 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1957/2014" type="inclusive">1957-2014</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_15ff44b75656bd924ffe3363c3173cbf">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Correspondence series contains correspondence pertaining to both Jane Fonda's personal, and professional, life. There are two sub-series, General and Subjects. There are oversize materials.</p>
               <p>
Both the General and Subjects series are organized first alphabetically, and then chronologically, in each folder. Subjects include family members of Fonda, various friends and celebrities, as well as large sections of fan mail, and correspondence with U.S. Veterans.</p>
               <p>
Additional correspondence can be found in Series 3. Professional Activities and Series 4. Writings. </p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_808fdf34cf71e2e8cb95ffff9f25934a" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Professional activities</unittitle>
               <unitid>3</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9.59 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(22 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1953/2015" type="inclusive">1953-2015</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7704b9bdf53764b12e2e0eb7d211aa85">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Materials related to Fonda's professional life are arranged in four sub-series: Acting, Conferences and Festivals, Interviews, and Organizations and Philanthropy.</p>
               <p>
The Acting sub-series is arranged chronologically, and includes scripts, screenplays, clippings, correspondence, notes, musical scores, and contains oversize items. Correspondence related to the Broadway play, 33 Variations, came to the Sophia Smith Collection with water damage. These letters have been photocopied and the originals have been returned to Ms. Fonda.</p>
               <p>
The Conferences and Festivals sub-series is arranged alphabetically.</p>
               <p>
The Interviews sub-series is arranged alphabetically, and includes transcripts and notes from interviews where Jane Fonda is the interviewer and the interviewee. Some interviews are in French.</p>
               <p>
The Organizations and Philanthropy sub-series is arranged alphabetically and includes correspondence, administrative materials, subject files, clippings, posters, resource notebooks, financial statements, and speeches related to the many educational, philanthropic, and humanitarian organizations Fonda has created and/or supported. Some organizations include Fonda, Inc.; the Georgia Campaign for Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention (G-CAPP) (renamed as the Georgia Campaign for Adolescent Power and Potential in 2012), Atlanta Partnership for Arts in Learning (APAL), the Fathers' Resource Center; and Women's Media Center (WMC). There are oversize items.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <odd id="aspace_d5aae031a2c62ee2353293efa07a9548">
               <head>General</head>
               <p>GCAPP - Elizabeth Appley was Legislative Counsel for GCAPP</p>
            </odd>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_f16ecd296a69a03b0fe23b9451d6c499" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
               <unitid>4</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.93 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(31 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1954/2014" type="inclusive">1954-2014</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_1f3e98665548f7b1afc2120e18f2a8d2">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Writings series contains two sub-series, Published and Unpublished. </p>
               <p>
The Published sub-series contains writings by Jane Fonda. There is an extensive record of the materials authored by Fonda, including a self-help book about sexuality for teenagers, <title render="italic">Being a Teen</title> (2014), Fonda's memoir,<title render="italic">My Life So Far</title> (2005), and a book on aging,<title render="italic">Prime Time</title> (2011). </p>
               <p>
The <title render="italic">My Life So Far</title> materials include correspondence, drafts, general information, advertising and publicity items, notes, and research files. The correspondence is organized alphabetically. Upon accession, some folders in the Drafts section were empty. To preserve evidence of Fonda's writing and editing process, an original chapter list has been added to the beginning of the Drafts section, and the empty folders have been removed. Many of the drafts are annotated (typed and handwritten) by Fonda, members of her family (her half-sister Frances (Pan) de Villers Brokaw Corrias), her ex-husbands Tom Hayden and Ted Turner, and other friends. Some drafts were reused for a secondary printing, and therefore there is text and annotations on both recto and verso of many. Early drafts of chapters are also found in various folders in the Research sub-series of<title render="italic">My Life So Far</title>, "Tom Era" being a good example. There are oversize materials.</p>
               <p>
The materials related to <title render="italic">Prime Time</title> include correspondence, drafts, outlines, and research files. The correspondence is organized chronologically. </p>
               <p>
The Unpublished sub-series contains notes and speeches by Jane Fonda. The Campaign for Economic Democracy folder is associated with a box of slides. Many are annotated and have multiple drafts. Speech texts include Fonda's tribute to Gregory Peck, Fonda's AFI speech for Warren Beatty, the speech Fonda gave at her son and daughter-in-law's wedding, various graduation commencement speeches, and Fonda's 2011 TEDx session.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_787bd47d7f4f25d2b039911855052a23" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
               <unitid>5</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.67 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(2 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1964/2003" type="inclusive">1964-2003</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_deec8ae6b313265b89f1cdd818d9a089">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Photographs series includes photographs and negatives related to Fonda's adolescent life, professional life, workout series, and family. There are oversize items.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_789c340f591bb0491512619fe7876e9f" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Audiovisual materials</unittitle>
               <unitid>6</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">37.88 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(55 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1970/2014" type="inclusive">1970-2014</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_226ef4fd874e02cb4ef7009559e813c5">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Audiovisual Materials series is organized by format and includes sixteen sub-series:
<list>
                     <item>1/8" Audio Cassettes</item>
                     <item>1/8" Audio Tapes</item>
                     <item>1/4" Audio Tapes</item>
                     <item>1/2" Audio Tapes</item>
                     <item>1/2" Video Cassettes (VHS)</item>
                     <item>1/2" Betamax Video Cassettes</item>
                     <item>1/2" Sanyo V-60 Video Cassettes</item>
                     <item>3/4" U-Matic Video Cassettes</item>
                     <item>3/4" U-Matic S Video Cassettes</item>
                     <item>1" Video Tapes</item>
                     <item>2" Video Tapes</item>
                     <item>16 mm film</item>
                     <item>35 mm film</item>
                     <item>10" LP Vinyl Album</item>
                     <item>CDs</item>
                     <item>DVDs</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
These materials document three aspects of Fonda's life: her political activism, including that related to her anti-Vietnam War efforts; the Jane Fonda Workout series; and interviews and television appearances, featuring Jane Fonda and/or her third husband, Ted Turner. The Vietnam-era audiovisual materials are of particular historical value.</p>
               <p>
In general, the sub-series are organized chronologically and alphabetically. Many items in each sub-series have related manuscript materials. These are filed at the beginning of the series.</p>
               <p>
The extensive 16 mm footage has been maintained in the order in which it was donated to the Sophia Smith Collection. The titles of each box are listed. Some boxes contain multiple elements, and these titles are also listed, under each box heading. Much of the 16 mm sub-series focuses on the 1974 Vietnam-related, anti-war documentary, <title render="italic">Introduction to the Enemy,</title> and therefore some box and item titles are in Vietnamese.<title render="italic">Introduction to the Enemy,</title> was produced by Jane Fonda, Tom Hayden, Haskell Wexler, Christine Burrill, and Bill Yahraus, filmed and directed by Haskell Wexler, and released through Fonda's production company, I.P.C. Films.</p>

               <p>Some CDs and DVDs include photographs and PowerPoint presentations.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_3fc4bcc4399ce5aa8375b2edb07d04f4" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle>
               <unitid>7</unitid>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 linear feet</extent>
                  <extent altrender="carrier">(2 boxes)</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate normal="1955/2000" type="inclusive">1955-2000</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_05fcffe70d000a57d4c8e10b10e6e155">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The Memorabilia series contains various items, including a urinal sticker, a presentation poster, a flattened aluminum can that is painted with a likeness of Fonda, a Life magazine with Fonda on the cover, a NARAL Pro-Choice Georgia license plate, artwork featuring Fonda, and a cloth hat with a patch that states "Veteran of the 60's" and has multiple political buttons attached. There are oversize items.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
