<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="mnsss"/>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Anne MacKay papers <num>SSC.MS.00472</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-09 15:29:23 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-04</date>
            <item>Updated legacy finding aid and added some further notes.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Anne MacKay papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_1659" source="local_inmagic-people">MacKay, Anne</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00472</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(17 boxes. Other materials in the collection: posters in flat file #32)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1928/2012"
                   type="inclusive">1928-2013</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_f5717a8d9ecf12374e728ce24ea6eb55">The collection contains personal and business files of Anne Mackay, an amatuer theatre director, playwrite, and author, who was prominent in the lesbian community of New York in the 20th century. This includes materials reflecting both MacKay's decades of teaching theater at two prestigious NYC prep schools (Dalton and Horace Mann Schools) and her amateur theater work, as well as her work as an author of both fiction, nonfiction and poetry. Also well documented is her active participation in reunion activities at her alma mater Vassar College (Class of 1949).</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_0c1278abd098fbf8eedaadcb712464f6">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accruals id="aspace_5b8fcfec26209837d6ccc89ff4f40256">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>This collection is comprised of the following accessions, some of which may not have accession records. Accession numbers: 1998-S-0014, 2002-S-0051, 2010-S-0073, 2012-S-0072. Accessions were received on the following dates: 1998-04-22, 2002-09-03, 2010-09-30, 2012-11-18.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_40e3560b8a35e53720881409f321984e">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was gifted by Anne McKay in 1998, 2002, 2010, and 2012.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_55284679ad39592a8a336e32df4e25f4">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Acc. #02S-51 added to box 16 of Acc. #12S-72.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_e4204a84445e17f3df569ae6f0e060e8">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Anne MacKay was an amatuer theatre director, playwrite, and author, who was prominent in the lesbian community of New York in the 20th century.  She was born in New York, NY on March 31, 1928 to Franklin (?) MacKay and Isabel (Dorman) MacKay. She grew up in New York City and Orient, NY, Pittsfield, MA , Corning, NY, and Berkeley, CA, according to her father's employment. Summers were spent with extended family in Orient, NY, on the North Fork of Long Island. MacKay attended the Dalton School in New York, and graduated from Vassar College in 1949. From 1949 to 1953, she was stage manager for various New York theater companies, and from 1953 to 1973 taught Drama at the Dalton School. She was employed as Director of Theatre Arts at the Horace Mann School in New York from 1973 to 1991, when she retired. She also created and directed three lesbian musical revues, including"Taking Liberties," a fundraiser for the Lesbian Herstory Archives and Astraea that was performed at Symphony Space in New York in 1984. She edited several books about lesbianism and other topics. In 1993 she was given the Uncommon Woman Award for outstanding contributions to the women's community by the Legacy Foundation, and in 1996 the Dalton School awarded her with"Honored Teacher"status. She was a member of a lesbian community on Long Island's North Fork and a founder of that group's women's health initiative, the North Fork Women for Women Fund, for which she also served as archivist.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_981c9f47469892876211d97ac1ca4977">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>Two of the accessions, from 2002 and 2012, have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_877a0c3606906c640b7a8d813383d3dd">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Anne MacKay papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00472, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1b36195805ff3a9c9e3c4dcfaf7c871d">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>North Fork Women for Women Fund Records, Voices of Feminism Oral History Project</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_6ca87627a8711b660fe25fa1784b7742">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection contains the materials reflecting both MacKay's decades of teaching theater at two prestigious NYC prep schools (Dalton and Horace Mann Schools) and her amateur theater work, as well as her work as an author of both fiction, nonfiction and poetry. Also well documented is her active participation in reunion activities at her alma mater Vassar College (Class of 1949).  Materials include books she wrote or edited, literary manuscript, scripts, photographs, business records, and audio-visual materials.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_e0062ddc01e29c71e15997c62e860adb">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Anne MacKay has retained copyright until her death in her works donated to Smith College. After her death, copyright in these works will transfer to Manuela Soares, and upon her death copyright passes to Smith College, with the exception of Wolf Girls at Vassar which passes to Vassar College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by MacKay, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">MacKay, Anne</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Vassar College--Students--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Gay college students--United States--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbian communities--United States--History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lesbians--United States--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Authors, American--20th century--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">MacKay, Anne. Just lucky, I guess!: memoirs of a Wolf girl, or, Growing up in sheep's clothing (1995)</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">MacKay, Anne (ed.). Wolf girls at Vassar : lesbian and gay experiences, 1930-1990 (1992)</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">MacKay, Anne (ed.) She Went A-Whaling: The Journal of Martha Smith Brewer Brown (1993)</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Typescripts</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_2135"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Soares, Manuela</persname>
    
    
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_1659"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">MacKay, Anne</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
