<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss"/>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Adrienne Germain papers <num>SSC.MS.00778</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-09 14:33:34 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-04</date>
            <item>Updated legacy finding aid with DACS and further notes.</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Adrienne Germain papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local_inmagic-collection">Germain, Adrienne</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00778</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(2 record boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1964/2016"
                   type="inclusive">1964-2016</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_7bcb19e10c014553fdb740b3ea40969f">The Adrienne Germain papers contain the working papers of Addrienne Germain,a champion for women's health and human rights in low-income countries, including essays, research materials, and correspondence related to her work with the Ford Foundation and the International Women's Health Coalition.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accruals id="aspace_7d7efab3ca675451e0df60e04d08ce9b">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>Periodic accruals may be added to the collection.</p>  
      </accruals>
      <bioghist id="aspace_5d10dd495a87e289c87f7cc46dde346e">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Throughout her career, Adrienne Germain has been a major force advancing international women's health and human rights in low income countries and has made this work central to the missions of many international organizations. Born in San Francisco in 1947 to William and Carel Germain, Germain graduated from Wellesley College in 1969 with a B.A. and from University of California at Berkeley in 1971 with an M.A., both in sociology. Germaine began her career at the Population Council in 1970, where for two years she undertook family planning program research. She started work with the Ford Foundation in 1972, where she became the youngest and first woman to be appointed as a Resident Representative to Bangladesh.  In this role she worked to shift discussion of population issues to a reproductive health lens. She rose to the role of Vice President of and Program Director for the International Women's Health Coalition (IWHC) in 1985, where she drove policy analysis and conceptual development, supervised numerous programs and local groups in Asia, Africa, and Latin America addressing women's reproductive health rights, produced scholarship, and advised the U.S. State Department, NGOs, European governments, and the U.N. system. By 1994, Germaine's influence had led to the consensus that women's sexual and reproductive health rights were central to women's human rights, sustainable development, and population stabilization.  In 1998, with the retirement of Joan Banks Dunlop, Germain became president of the IWHC. She went on to work for United Nations Population Fund as a consultant for their Reproductive Health Branch from 2011-2014. Germain has received many prestigious awards, among them the United Nations Population Award in 2012 and an Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters at Bard College in 2001.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ffd378fcfd7a41371e911801cce5bd21">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Adrienne Germain Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00778, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_75d27a4454d9721c188116b910f34807">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Carel B. Germain Papers. 
Joan Dunlop Papers. 
Population and Reproductive Health Oral History Project.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_1b1e6aa2fd8b6ca2c17996b988717484">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection contains essays and research materials, as well as correspondence and other materials related to Adrienne Germain's work with the Ford Foundation and the International Women's Health Coalition. The collection also contains awards and honors received at school and later in Germain's career.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_aa487a49c5a9b19073f62343918d1be9">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9be89d882717001bdcd6fd2fd6faacfe">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Adrienne Germain has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Adrienne Germain, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_5758d337a634bc1c0b202eb81d3c51d3">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was gifted to Smith College by Adrienne Germain in 2016.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_097197d004ad94d52ea7ef70cc54ef96">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The collection has a brief accession content list that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <processinfo id="aspace_80befa727d7588853d9277c2a7f0b826">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collection processed in 2017 March.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's rights -- Asia, Southeastern -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women's rights -- Developing countries -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's rights -- South America -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women, Black -- Health and hygiene -- Africa -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women's health services</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Reproductive health -- Developing countries</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Population policy -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Population assistance -- Developing countries</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">International Women's Health Coalition</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Germain, Carel B.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Dunlop, Joan</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Resumes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">reports</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publications</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Essays</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">CD-Roms</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Books</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_5302"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Germain, Adrienne</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
