<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">mnsss518</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Tucker Pamella Farley papers <num>SSC.MS.00676</num>
            </titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2012</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-17 16:14:22 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>07/26/2017</date>
            <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:21-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-08-17</date>
            <item>Finding aid updated per donor's request of 8/10/2018, notes, etc. brought up to current standards</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Tucker Pamella Farley papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="lcnaf">Farley, Tucker Pamella</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00676</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(3 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1969/2010"
                   type="inclusive">1969-2010</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_5f459faf75c652f8cedcf19baa75a937">Author; Labor organizer; Lesbian activist; Professor, English; Professor, Women's Studies. The papers contain materials from her academic career and study groups. Most material is related to Marxist Feminist Group 1 (MF 1) which include an extensive amount of discussion notes, minutes, planning materials, and publications. The group's topics ranged significantly over the years, and have included socialism, homophobia, racism, and postmodernism. Some records also exist of her participation in early women's studies courses, research, and conferences. The collection contains draft and published writings by Farley on the subjects of women in literature, women's self-narratives, and the history of women's studies.</abstract>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bioghist">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Tucker Pamella Farley is an activist and academic who helped create a space for women's studies in the university. She has been active in a variety of social justice causes. Farley earned her bachelor's degree from Oberlin College in 1961, and as a graduate student at Pennsylvania State University in the late 1960s, she became involved in Leftist activist efforts aimed at radicalizing the university. She organized for academic labor unions, and she participated in the Radical Caucus of the Modern Language Association and the New University Conference, among other groups. She was also involved in the women's liberation movement and the emergent field of women's studies. Farley completed her Ph.D. in 1973.</p>
         <p>Hired by Brooklyn College of the City University of New York in 1970 to teach women's studies and American literature, she was instrumental in the development of the school's Women's Studies Program and Women's Center. She was a founder of the New York Women's Labor Project, where she created and taught women's studies course for trade union women. 
 
A founder of the National Women's Studies Association (NWSA), Farley spearheaded the creation of NWSA's Lesbian Caucus. At the same time, she engaged in small-scale activist and intellectual networking through participation in a variety of study groups on radical and feminist issues. This included Marxist-Feminist Group 1 (MF 1), which has been active since 1973. Organized in the northeastern United States, MF 1 combined elements of the consciousness raising group with academic inquiry into issues of radicalism and feminism. Members have included academics, policy makers, and political activist. The group continues to meet two to three times a year. Tucker Farley maintained an active publishing and teaching career through the 2000s. She earned emerita status in 2005. She is featured in the Feminist Press book <title>The Politics of Women's Studies: Testimony from the 30 Founding Mothers</title>.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_scope">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Tucker Pamella Farley papers contain materials from her academic career and study groups. Most material is related to Marxist Feminist Group 1 (MF 1). Farley maintained a personal set of the organization's records, which include an extensive amount of discussion notes and minutes, planning materials, and publications. The group's topics ranged significantly over the years, and have included socialism, homophobia, racism, and postmodernism. Farley's contributions to these discussions included the subjects of lesbian feminism and women in literature, among others. Most documentation of MF 1 consists of discussion notes and presentation papers; the collection also contains audiocassettes of a 2010 session. Farley created item level inventories of most of the MF1 documents in this accession. These lists can be found appended to the box list. The remainder of the papers relate to other aspects of Farley's career. A small amount of printed material and correspondence documents her association with labor organizing, feminist organizing, lesbian issues, and direct action campaigns in the academy in the early 1970s. Some records also exist of her participation in early women's studies courses, research, and conferences. The collection contains draft and published writings by Farley on the subjects of women in literature, women's self-narratives, and the history of women's studies.</p>
         <p> [NOTE: The contents list for this collection is not online. Contact the Sophia Smith Collection if you would like one sent to you.]</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_admin-use">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Tucker Pamella Farley has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. </p>
         <p>For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Tucker Pamella Farley, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_admin-cite">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Please use the following format when citing materials from this collection:</p>
         <p>Tucker Pamella Farley Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_admin-acqinfo">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Tucker Pamella Farley began donating her papers to the SSC in 2011. A second accession was added in 2015.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_admin-process">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Accessioned by Amanda Izzo, April 2010. This collection has not been processed, in the sense that archival arrangement and description beyond creating minimal box lists has not been done. The arrangement and description of materials may change in the future as iterative processing occurs. Researchers are encouraged to document their citations with this in mind.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_073725941570b3e67384bd7b6b55747b">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_ae83e1266ceaafed56e1d1283e5044b1">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>More detailed contents lists created at the time of accessioning can be requested by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminism -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminism and education -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminist theory -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Feminists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Gay rights -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian activists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbian feminism -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians -- Education (Higher) -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Labor movement -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Marxist criticism -- United States</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Communism -- Study and teaching -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Radicalism -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sex discrimination in education -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Socialism -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women -- Education (Higher) -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women -- Societies and clubs -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women college teachers -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women radicals -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women's studies -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women in the labor movement -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Brooklyn College -- Faculty</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Bibliographies</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">clippings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Faculty papers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">lecture notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lists</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Minutes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Notes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Organization files</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Proposals</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Publications</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Research</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">syllabi</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Farley, Tucker Pamella</persname>
    
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
