<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-manoscmr">MRBC00018</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding Aid to Anna Hempstead Branch papers <num>MRBC.MS.00018</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Ellice Amanna</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Mortimer Rare Book Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018-10-18</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/mortimer-rare-book-collection"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/mortimer-rare-book-collection"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-25 14:26:14 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Mortimer Rare Book Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Anna Hempstead Branch papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local">Branch, Anna Hempstead</persname>
         </origination>
    
    
    
    
    
    
         <unitid>MRBC.MS.00018</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(13 record cartons)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   certainty="approximate"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1780/1939"
                   type="inclusive">1780-1939</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_fab9c5f944b17678442e34638551fd90">Anna Hempstead Branch (1875-1937) was an American poet who editor William Thomas Stead called "the Browning of American poetry. She was a member of the 1897 Smith College graduating class. The Anna Hempstead Branch Papers consist of aproximately 13 linear ft. and are primarily related to her professional and public life. The papers are arranged in nine series</abstract>
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_625500b34f99160aa72cb110b4d719a1">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The Anna Hempstead Branch papers were donated to the Mortimer Rare Book Room of Smith College by Branch's cousin, Ethel Lyman, before she died in 1946. Judge Oliver W. Branch, a cousin of Anna Hempstead Branch and of Ethel Lyman, sent additional papers to the Mortimer Rare Book Room in 1947. </p>
         <p>Additional papers to the Branch collection were donated by Caroline M. Fuller (Smith College Class of 1895) in 1945; by Mrs. Richard Mansfield in 1945; by the Smith College Class of 1897 in 1944, and by Caroline R. Wing (possibly Smith College Class of 1896) in 1948. </p>
         <p>Other additions were contributed by Ruth Newcomb, 1952-1959, and Winifred G. Whiton (Smith College Class of 1921), 1958. </p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_22a9fc13313910737aef475c20e2a1eb">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Anna Hempstead Branch (1875-1937) was an American poet who editor William Thomas Stead called "the Browning of American poetry. She was a member of the 1897 Smith College graduating class. The year after her graduation her poem "The Road 'Twixt Heaven and Hell" was selected as the year's best verse by a college graduate by Century Magazine. Sonnets from a Lock Box (1929), a collection of thirty-eight first person sonnets is noted for its directness and mystical symbolism and is regarded as her best work.</p>
         <p>Branch was known for her philanthropy, particularly in support of Chrstodora House, a New York City settlement house. She created the Poet's Guild whose members, including Robert Frost and Sara Teasdale, taught classes there. Branch died of cancer in 1937 at the age of 62.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_7ce5e135bbf938a1891ded81718481b1">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>The Anna Hemstead Branch papers, Morimer Rare Book Collection, MS 18, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Massachusetts</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_d42f64358e518817667ad938f1088ccd">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>This collection is unprocessed, the extents are approximate, finding aid is incomplete</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b151c0ed33087a9f4ffcc011b024ce82">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p> Anna Hempstead Branch Collection, Connecticut College, New London, Connecticut.</p>
         <p>Papers of the Christodora House, New York, New York. Branch had a long association with this New York settlement house. At Columbia University, New York. </p>
         <p>Correspondence from Anna Hempstead Branch to Edwin Markham and Anna Catherine Markham in the Markham Manuscript Collection, Wagner College, Staten Island, New York. </p>
         <p>Anna Hempstead Branch poems, circa 1910-1927. The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley. </p>
         <p>Anna Hempstead Branch, Manuscripts, 1924-1933, and n.d.  Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library, Charlottesville, Virginia. Part of the Clifton Waller Barrett Library. </p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_fe214da08e995597b049f35b0fb97406">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Anna Hempstead Branch Papers consist of aproximately 13 linear ft. and are primarily related to her professional and public life. The papers are arranged in nine series: </p>
         <p>I. CORRESPONDENCE</p>
         <p>
	The correspondence is divided into subseries as noted below.  There are still letters 	among some of the papers yet to be sorted, especially in the large brown box number 8.</p>
         <p>
II. WRITINGS </p>
         <p>
Writings are largely contained in the large brown boxes number 3-7? and there are some 	in box 8. Possibly also place "reviews" of Branch's writings as a separate series or at 	the end of this series.  In the preliminary outline Series II was noted as Branch's personal 	papers. Use what is appropriate once arrangement is completed. </p>
         <p>
III. NOTEBOOKS AND SCRAPBOOKS</p>
         <p>
In the preliminary outline this was listed as a possibility. Some scrapbooks were 	included in the Correspondence as that appeared to be more applicable. Possibly not use 	this designation. </p>
         <p>
IV. ORGANIZATIONAL PAPERS OF ALLIED FAMILIES, CHRISTODORS 	HOUSE AND POETRY GUILD</p>
         <p>
V. FAMILY BUSINESS PAPERS</p>
         <p>
Scattered throughout the papers, possibly just put in Miscellaneous as a file or two. </p>
         <p>
VI. BRANCH AND BOLLES FAMILY DOCUMENTS</p>
         <p>
In the large brown box 8, there is a genealogy (oversize document/notebook) of the 	Hempstead/Branch/Bolles (?) families. Possibly there are more documents. Might 	consider placing this in Miscellaneous as it might only be a file or two. </p>
         <p>
VII. PUBLICATIONS OF ANNA HEMPSTEAD BRANCH</p>
         <p>
Possibly consider placing this series as III or IV following the manuscripts of her writings 	and notebooks and scrapbooks. </p>
         <p>VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS</p>
         <p>
There are photographs scattered in numerous boxes. Some are identified; some not  In 	the large brown box 8, there is a loose-leaf album (highly acidic paper) that likely should 	be disassembled and the individual photographs placed in protective envelopes and filed 	here. </p>
         <p>
IX. MISCELLANEOUS</p>
         <p>
Use for oversize (possibly) items. Also there is a birch box that needs to be housed that 	apparently was made by Anna Hempstead Branch. </p>
         <p>
Among the items to go here are recent publications in related to the Hempstead House. 	There are older postcards, but also booklets, pamphlets and the like that are related to the 	House. Most of this material is in the large brown box 8. </p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_cd4b28c308667992b42120e639eba482">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Anna Hempstead Branch papers are the physical property of the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors of the works or their legal representatives.</p>
         <p>The Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Mortimer Rare Book Room without any additional restrictions. Permission must be obtained to publish reproductions or quotations beyond "fair use." Copyright to materials authored by others may be owned by those individuals or their heirs or assigns. It is the responsibility of the researcher to identify and satisfy the holders of all copyrights. Permission to publish reproductions or quotations beyond "fair use" must also be obtained from the Sophia Smith Collection as owners of the physical property.</p>
         <p>Please cite the Papers as follows: Anna Hempstead Branch Papers, Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College, Northampton, Mass.</p>
         <p>This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="local">Christadora House</geogname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="local">American poetry--20th Century -- History and criticism -- Sources</geogname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="fmo" source="local">Lyman, Ethel</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="fmo" source="local">Branch, Oliver W.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="alum-mem_5964"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-alum-mem">Fuller, Caroline, Class of 1895</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="fmo" source="local">Mansfield, Mrs. Richard</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" role="fmo" source="local">Newcomb, Ruth</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="alum-mem_12557"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-alum-mem">Whiton, Winifred, Class of 1921</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Branch, Anna Hempstead</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Branch, Mary Lydia (1840-1922)</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Branch, John L.  (1837-1908)</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">MacColl, Christina Isobel</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Lyman, Ethel</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Branch, Oliver W.</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="alum-mem_5964"
                   source="local_inmagic-alum-mem">Fuller, Caroline, Class of 1895</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Mansfield, Mrs. Richard</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Newcomb, Ruth</persname>
    
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="alum-mem_12557"
                   source="local_inmagic-alum-mem">Whiton, Winifred, Class of 1921</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_df34083e6f18b598d4e7583d3861382e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_2fb72fd610aadb525fdf6a398dde0e4e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_a2f1f042267591644822120cf70a2d69" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Notebooks and Scrapbooks</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_d3c99bb5fe7eb70e47ee8ddcd4af347e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Organizational Papers of Allied Families, Christodors House and Poetry Guild</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_6b85c79cb0089a875119e4f008e37f4d" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Family Business Papers</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ecf1191b6a894c9f7c6780a1bbe25251" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Branch and Bolles Family Documents</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_b61e9dfb0fc5b66b7a9b0918a4f3cb1f" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Publications of Anna Hempstead Brancgh</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_d5289e75c4e4639454a807e40c5c07cd" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_f3e7e8ca3168bcc30b889253a2df53ce" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
