<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">ssc00752</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Diana Russell papers <num>SSC.MS.00752</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-18 10:40:45 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-18</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Diana Russell papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_5222" source="local_inmagic-people">Russell, Diana</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00752</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16.25 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(13 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1978/2006"
                   type="inclusive">1978-2006</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_42c237e13235daa30259121c6c73647f">The papers consist primarily of the "930 completed interview schedules about women's experiences of rape, incest, extrafamilial child sexual abuse, etc." done in 1978 under the direction of Russell at the Institute for Social Analysis.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_142684d0f52c16d01f9715cc748c21c0">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_7b01be8f4da1e214efe42974aad946c5">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The collection was gifted by Diana Russell in 2015.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_30e1e82e5b10f056f545b3766609fca9">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Diana Elizabeth Hamilton Russell was born in Cape Town, South Africa where she earned her undergraduate degree in 1958. After doing postgraduate work at the London School of Economics, Russell came to the United States and attended Harvard University where she earned an MA (1967) and a PhD (1970) in Social Psychology. She started teaching at Mills College in 1969 and was one of the leaders in establishing the Women's Studies major there. Russell's scholarship and her activism has focused on the fight to end violence against women, beginning with her 1975 publication,"The Politics of Rape."She has published several more books and dozens of articles linking pornography to violence against women, exposing the horrors of child sexual abuse and incest, and, with co-author Jill Radford in 1992,"coined the term"femicide."Russell has also published on the women of South Africa where she actively protested against apartheid from the early 1960s onward and has been arresting several times for her actions.
 
 A professor emerita since 1991, Russell has become a renowned speaker appearing on countless radio and television shows, from National Public Radio to the Oprah Show, and has been called as an expert witness in cases related to rape and violence against women. Leading feminist legal scholar Catherine MacKinnon has said of Russell that she"is the recognized academic expert on the empirical study of sexual violence against women in the United States, and a leading authority on this subject throughout the world."She is also an activist, including the founding of Women Against Violence in Pornography and Media in 1976, the first feminist anti-pornography organization in the US. For more information, see Diana Russell's Web site: http://www.dianarussell.com/index.html</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_0b65b5a25b6f6d9e7cca41d5f2fde7eb">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The collection has a container list that is available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_4642bda604ca197a38ba1db25c4555eb">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Diana Russell papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00752, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_6d2dbddc559b1e3d855f8ad358567166">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The papers consist primarily of the "930 completed interview schedules about women's experiences of rape, incest, extrafamilial child sexual abuse, etc." done in 1978 under the direction of Russell at the Institute for Social Analysis, the results formed the core material for her 1986 publication,"The Secret Trauma: Incest in the Lives of Girls and Women."Interviewee names and identifying information is not included in the schedules. A small amount of biographical material about Diana Russell is also included.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_b0ed5a06d5852947f1e56213c923601e">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Russell has assigned the copyright in her works to Smith College; however, copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For instances which may regard materials in the collection not created by Russell, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Abused women -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Child abuse -- United States -- History -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Sexual abuse victims -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Incest -- United States -- History</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women -- Violence against</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Rape -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Biographical sketches</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Case files</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Interviews</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Russell, Diana E. H.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_5222"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Russell, Diana</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_5222"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Russell, Diana</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
