<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">ssc00525</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Jewel Graham papers <num>SSC.MS.00525</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-15 08:33:02 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-12</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Jewel Graham papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="naf">Graham, Jewel</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00525</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(9 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1940/2008"
                   type="inclusive">1940-2008</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_8a57f8ef997c12e4efcedfe18cbf5d94">The collection contains the personal and professional papers of Jewel Graham, including a typescript of her unpublished memoir, which includes reflections on growing up as an African American girl in Springfield, Ohio, her education, her employment as professor at Antioch College, and her life-long service in the YWCA, from age 13, to becoming President of the National Board and of the World YWCA.  </abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_d67d851d21157c32816de21ca3bdcc4a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections. Collection is stored offsite; researchers must give 48 hours advance notice.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_aa9b75169a5860dd4efb793cc4a53aa7">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Collection was donated by Jewel Graham in 2005 and 2009.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3fab6e3739020891b19a6893359b4e0d">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>Precious Jewel Freeman was born in Springfield, Ohio, to Lulu Belle Malone and Robert Lee Freeman, the sixth of seven children. She graduated form Springfield High School in 1942. She earned her B.A. from Fisk University in 1946, her M.S.S.A. (Master of Science in Social Science Administration) from Case Western University in 1952, and her J.D. from the University of Dayton in 1979. She served as Asssociate director of the Teen Age Program Department of the YWCA in Grand Rapids, Michigan from 1947 to 1950; from 1952 to 1965 she held administrative positions at various social service organizations; and from 1965 to 1972 she was employed by the U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. She began working at Antioch College in 1964, initially in the Program for Interracial Education (1964-1968). She was hired as Professor of Social Welfare and Legal Studies in 1969, and worked her way up from Assistant Professor to full Professor; she retired from that position in 1992. She also served as Interim Associate Dean of the College from 1972 to 1973, and as Peer Counselor for Campus Climate from 1992 to 1994. Jewel Graham served on the National Board of the YWCA of the USA from 1970 to 1988, and was president of that organization from 1979 to 1985. She was also president of the World YWCA from 1979 to 1985, and served on its Executive Committee from 1970 to 1995. Throughout her adult life she has been active in local community organizations and in local, state and national politics, held membership in numerous professional organizations, and has published widely in professional journals. She and her husband, Paul Graham, had two sons, Robert Grahamjones and Nathan Graham. Jewel Graham died November 30, 2015.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_52f76aa2feef981a7cb0e1b72b18570b">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>The accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_105842cd2c615e7a6fec16ba917e1977">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Precious Jewel Graham papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00525, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_8458a62051502fff3f090a152f021cc8">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>YWCA of the USA Records</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_3ebb71c33aed9f16234a2e5355e723a7">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Personal and professional correspondence; biographical information including high school, Fisk University (and Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority), Antioch College employment, and involvement in the National and World YWCA (notably as President of both). Drafts of Graham's writings that address issues of race, in general and relating to the YWCA specifically, are of particular interest. A typescript of Jewel Graham's unpublished memoir,"The Life of My Times: Notes For an Autobiography"(2005) includes reflections on growing up as an African American girl in Springfield, Ohio, her education, her employment as professor at Antioch College, and her life-long service in the YWCA, from age 13, to becoming President of the National Board and of the World YWCA.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_7b0bb668a1e65494f474c72ed9f70b5a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Graham has retained copyright until her death in her works donated to Smith College. After her death, copyright in these works will transfer to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Graham, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">African American women--Biography--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">African Americans--Springfield (Ohio)--History--20th century--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Antioch College--Faculty--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Springfield (Ohio)--History--Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">World Young Women's Christian Association</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A.--History</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Typescripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">diaries</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Lectures</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Speeches</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Graham, Jewel</persname>
    
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Graham, Jewel</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
