<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead
  PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="Legacy Finding Aid (updated)"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="us-mnsss">ssc00630</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Finding aid to the Jan Clausen papers <num>SSC.MS.00630</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Madison White</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Sophia Smith Collection</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2018</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>Young Library</addressline>
               <addressline>4 Tyler Drive</addressline>
               <addressline>Northampton, MA 01063</addressline>
               <addressline>specialcollections@smith.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr href="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"
                          show="new"
                          title="http://next.smith.edu/libraries/special-collections/about/sophia-smith-collection-womens-history"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-10-16 14:25:38 -0400</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change>
            <date>2017-07-26T17:48:24-04:00</date>
            <item>This record was migrated from InMagic DB Textworks to ArchivesSpace. </item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2018-10-15</date>
            <item>Updated to conform to DACS</item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Sophia Smith Collection</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Jan Clausen papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="people_4596" source="local_inmagic-people">Clausen, Jan</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid>SSC.MS.00630</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">26.75 linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(24 boxes.)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                   era="ce"
                   normal="1907/2017"
                   type="inclusive">1907-2017</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_b2239b6b1e693c335579342e6a4e9f5f">The collection contains materials documenting Clausen's career as feminist poet, novelist, and writer of non-fiction; her participation in feminist, social justice, anti-nuclear, prison reform, and gay rights activism; and her family life and her relationship with former partner, Elly Bulkin.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_b0e7785146a19806ac17e4d67edb9a41">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_00d996ef87cd931aad987ca15e0e09b3">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Jan Clausen donated her papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2008, 2009, and 2017.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_422538bd1550d9ca6197c4cf55a36737">
         <head>Biographical Note</head>
         <p>
Jan Clausen was born in North Bend, Oregon to Phyllis Irene Shannon Clausen and Victor Herman Ehler Clausen. From 1967 to 1970, she attended Reed College and dropped out following her junior year. She moved to New York in 1973, where she received her B.A. (1994), as well as her M.A. in Gender Studies and Feminist Theory (1996) from the New School for Social Research. Clausen then moved to Brooklyn and settled into a life of writing, demonstrating and activism on behalf of social justice, especially for women. After more than a decade of"marriage"to a woman with whom she was raising a daughter, she fell in love with a West Indian male lawyer she met on a fact-finding tour to Nicaragua in 1987. Her decision to move in with that man stunned the lesbian literary and political community and they forcefully and dramatically cast her out. Her story is told in the memoir Apples And Oranges: My Journey Through Sexual Identity (1999). Clausen is a poet, novelist, liberal activist, book critic and reviewer. She has written nine additional books: After Touch (1975), Waking at the Bottom of the Dark (1979), Mother, Sister, Daughter, Lover (1980), Movement of Poets: Thoughts on Poetry and Feminism (1982), Duration (1983), Sinking, Stealing (1985), The Prosperine Papers (1988), Books and Life (1989), and Beyond Gay or Straight: Understanding Sexual Orientation (1997). Her short fiction, articles, poetry and book reviews appear regularly in numerous magazines including Kenyon Review, The Village Voice, Ms., The Nation, Poets&amp;Writers, and the Women's Review of Books. She is the recipient of a National Endowment for the Arts fiction fellowship. In 1981 she won a National Endowment for the Arts Fiction Fellowship, and in 2003, she was awarded the New York Foundation for the Arts Poetry Fellowship. Clausen is the director of Eugene Lang College, a division of the New School University (formerly New School for Social Research) in Manhattan, where she teaches fiction and autobiographical writing.
 [Source: http://www.writersontheedge.org/
 Additional biographical information: http://www.ablationsite.org/Clausen_frame.html ]  </p>
      </bioghist>
      <otherfindaid id="aspace_067e87fca7564fd60f0b5ee7fb0112ba">
         <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
         <p>This collection has been received in three separate accessions between 2008 and 2017. Currently, only the most recent of these accessions has an online contents list in the form of this finding aid. The other accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu</p>  
      </otherfindaid>
      <prefercite id="aspace_b457179d9d0bb939400ebf8a7f311e66">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Jan Clausen papers, Sophia Smith Collection, SSC-MS-00630, Smith College Special Collections, Northampton, Mass.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_e29144c4413ecdb717edab3813d0e980">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Materials documenting Clausen's career as feminist poet, novelist, and writer of non-fiction; her participation in feminist, social justice, anti-nuclear, prison reform, and gay rights activism; and her family life and her relationship with former partner, Elly Bulkin. The correspondence in this collection is particularly strong in its frank discussion of the confluence of feminist theory and personal experience, as are Clausen's diaries. In addition to correspondence between Clausen and Elly Bulkin, there is also correspondence between Clausen and friend/filmmaker, Sandy Smith; letters from former significant other, Richard Garmise; and family correspondence from her sister, Debra (Debby) Clausen, her brother, Sidney Clausen, and her parents. Also of interest are audiotaped interviews with the Women's Construction Brigade, who went to Nicaragua in 1987, conducted by Clausen and used for her M.A. thesis,"North American Feminists and the Sandinista Revolution."</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_b9898991f972d0c532c48e99ca571558">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>To the extent that she owns copyright, Jan Clausen has retained copyright until her death in her works donated to Smith College, with the exception of unpublished works in her papers, to which Jan Clausen retains copyright permanently. After her death, copyright in these works will transfer to Smith College. Copyright in other items in this collection may be held by their respective creators. For reproductions of materials that are governed by fair use as defined under U. S. Copyright Law, no permission to cite or publish is required. For those few instances beyond fair use, or which may regard materials in the collection not created by Clausen, researchers are responsible for determining who may hold materials' copyrights and obtaining approval from them. Researchers do not need anything further from Smith College Special Collections to move forward with their use.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Bisexuality -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" authfilenumber="sh2008103671" source="lcsh">Feminists -- United States -- Biography</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Lesbians -- United States -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Nicaragua -- History -- Revolution, 1979 -- Women</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local_inmagic-collection">Women authors -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women poets, American -- 20th century -- Biography -- Sources</subject>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">articles</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">correspondence</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">diaries</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Galley proofs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">memorabilia</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Interviews</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Newspapers</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">photographs</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Theses</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Typescripts</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Writings</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Audiotapes</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local_inmagic-collection">Videotapes</genreform>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local_inmagic-collection">Clausen, Jan, 1950-</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4596"
                   role="fmo"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Clausen, Jan</persname>
  
         <persname encodinganalog="600"
                   authfilenumber="people_4596"
                   source="local_inmagic-people">Clausen, Jan</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_d89eb42a4ca7cd67daed6413e928e959" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence and books by Jan Clausen</unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2017-S-0047</unitid>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="1982/2017"
                         type="inclusive">1982-2017</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ec7f3455fdd0db1bf72dfdadeae84e5e">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Box No. 1 Email correspondence from Z Olivier to Jan Clausen (2017), "Self Determined" by Jan Clausen (2017), "Apples and Oranges: My Journal Through Sexual Identity" by Jan Clausen (1999), "A Movement of Poets: Thoughts on Poetry and Feminism" by Jan Clausen (1982), "Veiled Spill: A Sequence" by Jan Clausen (2014)</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
